[{"ID": 1, "Question": "Once the function ends, the control is returned back to the ... function and execution continues from the statement immediately after the function call\na. executing\nb.called\nc.declared\nd.calling", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 2, "Question": "what number is equivalent to -4e3?\na.-4000\nb.-400\nc..004\nd..0004\ne.-40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 3, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\n if(v==1||v==0)\n return 1;\n if(v%2==0)\n return (fn(v/2)+2);\n else\n return(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\nreturn (0);\n}\na.6\nb.9\nc.8\nd.7\ne.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 4, "Question": "which 2 options are correct about the function scanf?\na.EOF indicates that scanf filled all addresses successfully\nb. scanf returns the number of addresses successfully filled of EOF\nc.return avoid type\nd.EOF indicates that scanf did not fill any address AND encountered an end of data character.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D "}, {"ID": 5, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint s=35;\nprintf(\"%d%d%d\",s==35,s+20,s>40)\na.1 35 1\nb.1 55 1\nc.0 55 0\nd.1 55 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 6, "Question": "according to the standard C specification, what are the respective minimum sizes (in bytes) of the following two data type: int and long?\na.2,8\nb.4,8\nc.2,4\nd.2,2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 7, "Question": "what does the following declaration mean (if there are more than one correct answers, choose the best one)\nint *ptr[10];\na.array of 10 integer pointers\nb.pointed to the array of 10 elements\nc.array of 10 pointers", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 8, "Question": "what would happen if the user types in the number 3 and presses Enter when running this program?\nmain(){\nint x=5;\nchar c;\nprintf(\"Enter x=\");\nscanf(\"%d\",&x);\nprintf(\"Calculate square(Y/N):\");\nc=getchar();\nif(c==Y||c==y)\nprintf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\na.sqr=9\nb.Its depend on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \"calculate square?\"\nc.sqr=25\nd.the program exits without printing the square", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 9, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i,j,k,x=0;\nfor(i=1;i<5;i++)\n for(j=0;j<i;++j){\n switch(i+j){\n case 0:x=x+1;\n break;\n case 1:\n case 2:\n case 3: x=x+2;\n break;\n}}\nprintf(\"%d\",x);\na.12\nb.13\nc.10\nd.8\ne.6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 10, "Question": "the while loop can be written as a for loop\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 11, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar fun[]=\"How are you?\";\nchar **p;\np=fun;\nwhile(***p!='\\0'){\nif(strlen(p)!=7) printf(\"%c\",**p);\np++;}\na. How ar you\nb.Ho are you\nc.How re you\nd.How are you\ne. How ae you", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 12, "Question": "given the below code ?\nchar st[50];\nscanf(\"%5[^\\]\",st);\nprintf(\"%s\",st);\na user enters \"pfc is simple\"\nwhat is printed?\na.other\nb.pfc is\nc.pfc is so simple\nd.blank output\ne.pfc i", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 13, "Question": "how is a variable accessed from another file?\na. the global variable is referenced via the auto specifier\nb. the global variable is referenced via the extern specifier\nc. the global variable is referenced via the pointer specifier\nd. the global variable is referenced via the ext specifier\ne. the global variable is referenced via the global specifier", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 14, "Question": "which one of the following is a variable, which can contain the address of the memory location of another variable?(choose the best answer)\na.string\nb.struct\nc.array\nd.pointer", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 15, "Question": "declare a two dimensional integer array of two rows and four columns having some initial values\na.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nb.int arr1[2][4]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nc.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12};{22,45};{23,40};{44,79}}\nd.int arr1[][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 16, "Question": "what value will x contain in the sample code below?\nint x=011|0x10;\na.27\nb.19\nc.25\nd.13\ne.3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 17, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint g=1;\nprintf(\"%d %d %d\",g,++g,g++);\na.1 3 3 \nb.1 2 3 \nc.1 1 1 \nd.3 3 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 18, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0;\nfor(;i;)\nprintf(\"This is a loop\");\nif(i>0)\nprintf(\"in C program\");\na. nothing\nb. garbage value\nc. in C program\nd.this is a loop in C program\ne. this is a loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 19, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nvoid main(){\nint i,j=25;\nint **pi, ***pj=&j;\n ***pj=j+5;\n i=*pj+5;\n pi=pj;\n **pi=i+j;\n printf(\"%d%d\",***pi,*pj);}\na.30 35\nb.65 65\nc.60 60\nd.25 30\ne.60 65", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 20, "Question": "which one of the following is a valid function definition?\na. double funct(int a,b, double c,d)\nb. double funct(int a,b, double c)\nc. double funct(char a,b, double d)\nd. double funct(int a,int b, double c)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 21, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar mess[]=\"Your are welcome here\";\nchar *p;\np=mess;\nmess[8]='\\0';\nputs(++p);\na.our are wel\nb.our are \nc.Your are \nd.Your are wel", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 22, "Question": "which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another\na.strcpy\nb.strcmp\nc.strcat\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 23, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a=8, b=9;\nif(a%2=b%3)\nprintf(\"\\n%d %d\", ++a, b--)\na. 8 9\nb. 9 9 \nc.9 8\nd. compiler error\ne. 8 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 24, "Question": "what will be printed when the sample code below is executed?\nchar **buffer=\"0123456789\";\nchar **ptr=buffer;\nptr+=5;\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",ptr);\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",buffer);\na. 56789\n0123456789\n\nb.56789\n56789\n\nc.0123456789\n0123456789\n\nd.5123456789\n5123456789\n\ne.0123456789\n56789", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 25, "Question": "in myfile.c does not exist, what will be output of this program?\n#include<stdio.h>\nmain(){\nFILE *fi;\nfi=fopen(\"myfile.c\",\"r\");\nif(fi=NULL)\n{puts(\"file is not opened\");\nexit(1);}\nelse\nputs(\"FILE opened\");}\na. file is not opened\nb.no output\nc.FILE opened\nd.error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 26, "Question": "given the below code\nint a=1;\nint i=7;\nif(a||i++)\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nwhat is the output\na.7\nb.8\nc.9\nd.other", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 27, "Question": "a string is a ... array of characters terminated by a null('\\0')\na.one-dimensional\nb.two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 28, "Question": "referring to the sample code below, what value will the variable counter have when completed\nint x=3, counter = 0;\nwhile(x-1){\n++counter;\nx--;}\na.4 \nb.2\nc.3\nd.0\ne.1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 29, "Question": "the operation between float and int would give the result as\na. float\nb. int \nc. unsigned int\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 30, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint k=0x55;\nprintf(\"\\n%d\",k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na.65\nb.75\nc.55\nd.85", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 31, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint calc(int a, int b){\nint x,y;\nx=a+b;\ny=a*b;\nreturn(x+y);\n}\nint main(){\nint p=3, q=4, r, s;\nr=calc(p,q);\ns=calc(q,p);\nprintf(\"\\n%d%d\",r,s);\nreturn 0;}\na. 3 4\nb. 17 19\nc. 18 18\nd. 17 17\ne.19 19", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 32, "Question": "which of the following statement are true with regards to the || operator?(select al correct answer)\na.this operator is used to combine two conditional expressions which evaluate to true as a whole only if either of the two expressions evaluate to true.\nb.only if both the expressions evaluate to false, the outcome is false\nc.if one of the conditional expressions return false, the outcome is false\nd.this operator is used to combine two logical expressions which evaluate to true if both individual expression are true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 33, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed, assuming int data type is 32 bits in size?\nprintf(\"%d, %d, %d, %d\", sizeof(char), sizeof(int), sizeof(10.0), sizeof(10.0f));\na. 2,4,8,4\nb. 1,10,10,10\nc. 1,4,8,4\nd. 1,4,4,4\ne. 1,2,4,4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 34, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a[5]={0}, x=2111223;\nwhile(x>10){\na[x%10-1]++;\nx/=10;}\nprintf(\"%d\",a[1]);\na.6\nb.3\nc.1\nd.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 35, "Question": "what will the code below print when executed?\ndouble x=-3.5, y=3.5;\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",ceil(x), ceil(y));\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",floor(x), floor(y));\na -3:3\n-4:4\nb.-4:3\n-3:4\nc.-4:4\n-3:3\nd.-3:4\n-4:3\ne.-4:3\n-4:3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 36, "Question": "consider the following code:\nif(a==b)\nprintf(\"\\n the number are equal\");\nelse(a<b)\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",a);\nelse\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",b);\nin the above code, if a=14 and b=9, then the .... clause is executed\na. else\nb.if\nc else if", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 37, "Question": "when does the code block following while(x<100) execute?\na.when x is less than one hundred\nb.when x is equal to one hundred\nc.when x is greater than one hundred\nd.while it wishes", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 38, "Question": "which are the following statements printf % character?\na.printf(\"\\%\")\nb.printf(\"\\\\%\")\nc.printf(\"\\%%\")\nd.printf(\"%%\")", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 39, "Question": "a comment can be split over more than one line, as follows\n/** A program\nto calculate average\nof 5 numbers. **/\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 40, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint p,q,h;\nfor(p=1;p<=3;p++)\nfor(q=1;q<=2;q++)\nh=p+q;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",h);\na.1\nb.5\nc.3\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 41, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint x=3;\nif(x==2)\nx=0;\nif(x==3)\nx++;\nelse x+=2;\na.5\nb.3\nc.1\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 42, "Question": "what is the incorrect statement about floating-point data types(float and double)?\na. computers store floating-point data using separate components, including the mantissa and exponent\nb.float-point means that the decimal point can float(that is, it can ba placed anywhere relative to the significant digits)\nc.both data types(float and double) can represent arbitrarily small as well as arbitrarily large numbers\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 43, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint n=10, i;\nint k=0;\nfor(i=1;i<n;i=i*2)k++;\nprintf(\"i:%d, k:%d\", i, k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na i:16, k:3\nb.i:16, k:4\nc.i:16, k:5\nd.i:8, k:4\ne.i:10, k:4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 44, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nmain()\n{int i=5;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i=++i==6)\na.0\nb.1\nc.5\nd.6\ne.7", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 45, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar *ptr=\"Hello world\";\nptr++;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\nptr+=2;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\na.ello worldllo world\nb.Hello worldHello world\nc.ello worldlo world\nd.ello worldHello world\ne.Hello worldello world", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 46, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=3;\nswitch(i){\ncase 3: i+=5;\nif(i==8){\ni++;\nif(i==9) break;\ni*=2;}\ni-=4;\nbreak;\ncase 8:\ni+=5;\nbreak;\ndefault: \ni+=6;\nbreak;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i);\na.8\nb.11\nc.7\nd.9\ne.10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 47, "Question": "using break statement we can exit from\na. for a loop\nb. an if statement\nc. the main() function\nd. a program", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 48, "Question": "give the code below\nint a=2;\nprintf(\"%d\",++a,a+5)\nwhat is printed?\na. undefined\nb. error\nc. 2\nd. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 49, "Question": "What is 7/9*9 equal to?\nA. 2\nB. 0\nC. 1\nD. 0.08642", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 50, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor( i=1; i<10,j<5;i*=2,j++){\nj+=2;\nprintf(\"%d \",j);\n}\nPrintf(\"%d %d\",i,j);\nA. 2 5 4 7\nB. 2 5 6 4\nC. 2 5 3 6 \nD. 2 5 4 8\nE. 2 5 4 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 51, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i;\nfor(i=1;i<4;i++)\n switch(i){\n case 1: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 2: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 3: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 4: printf(\"%d \",i);\n}\nA. 1 2 3 \nB. 4\nC. 1 2 3 4 \nD. 1 2 \nE. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 52, "Question": "If the program completes executing successfully, what value should the function main returned?\nA. void\nB. 0\nC. nothing\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 53, "Question": "Which value can not be assigned to an unsigned-short type?\nA. 59876\nB. 0\nC. 10000\nD. -3\nE. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 54, "Question": "If a program contains just one function, then it must be___.\nA. clrscr()\nB. getch()\nC. printf()\nD. main()\nE. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 55, "Question": "What number is equivalent to -4e3 ?\nA. -4000\nB.-400\nC. .004\nD. -40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 56, "Question": "What does the following declaration mean ( If there are more than one correct answer, choose the best one)\nInt*ptr[10];\nA. Array of 10 integer pointers\nB. Pointers to the array of 10 elements\nC. Array of 10 pointers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 57, "Question": "___ is the comparison operation and ___ is the logical operation.\nA. Modulo, Less than\nB. Less than, NOT\nC. NOT, Less than\nD. Divide, OR", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 58, "Question": "- What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat a=14.5;\ndouble b=12.45;\nprintf(\"%.6f%.6f\",a,b);\nA. 14.50000 12.45000\nB. 14.5 12.45\nC. 14.500000 12.450000\nD. 14.5 12.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 59, "Question": "The ___ function after accepting a character and wait for the Enter key to be pressed.\nA. putch()\nB. putchar()\nC. getch()\nD. getchar()", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 60, "Question": "Evaluate the following as true or false: !(1&&0||!1)\nA. true\nB. false\nC. Invalid expression", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 61, "Question": "The precedence of operators is ___\nA. Arithmetic, Comparison, Logical\nB. Logical, Comparison, Arithmetic\nC. Comparison, Arithmetic, Logical\nD. Comparison, Logical, Arithmetic", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 62, "Question": "What is the output?\n int main(){\nchar i=127;\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nreturn 0;\n}\nA. 128\nB. -128\nC. Undefined\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 63, "Question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint sum(int n);\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"s=%d\\n\",sum(5));\nreturn 0;\n}\nint sum(int n)\n{\nint s,i;\ns=0;\nfor(i=1;i<=n;i++) s+=i;\nreturn(s);\n}\nA. s=14\nB. s=15", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 64, "Question": "A user enter \"pfabcd\" from the console\nWhat is printed?\nA. pfabcd\nB. Runtime error\nC. pfa\nD. Blank(nothing output)\nE. other\nF. pf", "Choices": [], "Answer": "F "}, {"ID": 65, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat j;\nj=1000*1000;\nprintf(\"%3.0f\",j);\nA. 1000000\nB. error\nC. overflow\nD. 100", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 66, "Question": "By default any real number is treated as \nA. a long double\nB. a double\nC. depends upon the memory model that you are using\nD. a float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 67, "Question": "A string is a ___ array of characters terminated by a null('\\0').\nA. one-dimensional\nB. two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 68, "Question": "If you push 1,3, and 5 -in that odder -onto a stack , which number is popped out first?\nA. 5\nB. 1\nC. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 69, "Question": "Which of the following adds ones string to the end of another?\nA. stradd();\nB. append();\nC. strcat();\nD. stringadd();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 70, "Question": "We want to round off x, a float, to an int value. The correct way to do so would be:\nA. y= (int)(x+0.5)\nB. y= (int)((int)x+0.5)\nC.y=(int) x+0.5\nD. y= int(x+0.5)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 71, "Question": "Which of the following is the Boolean operator for logical-and ?\nA. &&\nB. &\nC. |\nD. |&", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 72, "Question": "Which is not a loop structure in C ?\nA. while\nB. for\nC. do while\nD. repeat until", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 73, "Question": "Which of the following statement is (are) wrong ? (choose 2)\nA. a1 = 1343.44;\nB. 3=d;\nC. 3**c=d;\nD. cat = 'A' *** 'B';\nE. asd = 'A'**24;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 74, "Question": "Which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another ?\nA. strcpy\nB. strcmp\nC. strcat\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 75, "Question": "- What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint i;\ni= 1;\ni = i+ 2*i ++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nA. 4\nB. 5\nC. 3\nD. 1\nE. 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 76, "Question": "What is the correct fomat to define a value in C ?\nA. const PI = 3.14159\nB. #define PI = 3.14159\nC. #define PI 3.14159\nD. #define PI = 3.14159;\nD. #define PI 3.14159;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 77, "Question": "What is required to avoid falling through from one case to the next ?\nA. break;\nB. stop;\nC. ;\nD. end;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 78, "Question": "Which is the correct statement about coupling ?\nA. Coupling is a measure of the focus within a module.\nB. In designing, high coupling is generally acceptable.\nC. Global variables introduce a low degree of coupling.\nD. We call a module highly couple if it shares that performance with some other module including the referring module.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 79, "Question": "Which of the following functions compares two strings ?\nA. compare();\nB. stringcompare();\nC. cmp();\nD. strcmp();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 80, "Question": "What is the correct prototype in C ?\nA. doFunc():char;\nB. char doFunc()\nC. int doFunc(int,int);\nD. void doFunc(int x, int y);\nE. float doFunc(void);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 81, "Question": "Which of the following statements prints %character ?\nA. printf(\"\\%\")\nB. printf(\"\\\\%\");\nC. printf(\"\\%%\")\nD. printf(\"%%\");", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 82, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\n if( v==1||v==0) return 1;\n if(v%2==0) return(fn(v/2)+2);\n else return(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main(){\n printf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\n return (0);\n}\nA. 7\nB. 9\nC. 5\nD. 6\nE. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 83, "Question": "Which of the following data type occupied 1 byte ? (choose two)\nA. unsigned char\nB. short\nC. float\nD. long double\nE. double\nF. char", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A F "}, {"ID": 84, "Question": "- What are the correct statements ? ( choose two)\nA. The operator ** reads as 'the data at address'.\nB. The *** operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand\nC. The operator ** reads the address of the variable.\nD. The & operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 85, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint s=0;\nfor (int i=1;i<=10;++i){\n s=s+i;\n if (s>=6) break;\n s=s+1;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",s);\nA. 10\nB. 7\nC. 9\nD. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 86, "Question": "#include<stdlib.h>\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\n int i,n,a=10,b=20;\n for(i=0;i<10;i++){\n n=a+rand()%(b+1-a);\n printf(\"%d\\n\",n);\n }\n return 0;\n}\nRun the above program, which is correct statement about the output?\nA. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 11 and 19 inclusive.\nB. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 10 and 20 inclusive.\nC. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 9 and 21 inclusive.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 87, "Question": "Which are proper declarations of a string str which stores the value \"Melodies\" (choose two)\nA. char str[]= \"Melodies\";\nB. char str[7] = \"Melodies\";\nC. char str[9] = \" Melodies\";\nD. char str[] = Melodies;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 88, "Question": "What would happen if the user types in number 3 and presses Enter when running this program ?\nmain(){\n int x=5;\n char c;\n printf(\"Enter x=\");\n scanf(\"%d\",&x);\n printf(\"Calculate square?(Y/N):\");\n c=getchar();\n if (c== 'Y'|| c== 'y')\n printf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\nA. sqr = 25\nB. The program exits without printing the square\nC. sqr = 9\nD. It depends on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \" calculate square?\"", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 89, "Question": "What is size of an int ?\nA. 8 bits\nB. 16 bits \nC. Dependent on machine's \"word\" size\nD. 32 bits", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 90, "Question": "How is the integer pointer var declared in C?\nA. int** x;\nB. int pointer*** var;\nC. int pointer var;\nD. pointer** var;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 91, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nvoid foo(int x){\n if (x>0) foo(--x);\n printf(\"%d\",x);\n}\nint main(){\n foo(4);\n printf(\"\\n\");\n return 0;\n}\nA. 00123\nB. 001234 \nC. 430123\nD. 01234 \nE. 40123", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 92, "Question": "How do you include a system header file called sysheader.h in a C source file ?\nA. #includefile<sysheader>\nB.#include<sysheader.h>\nC. #incl<sysheader.h>\nD. #incl \"sysheader.h\"\nE. #includesysheader.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 93, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor(i=1;i<10,j<3;i*=2) {\n printf(\"%d\",j++);\n}\nprintf(\"%d%d\",i,j);\nA. 012384 \nB. 012394 \nC. 0123184\nD. 01283", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 94, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nvoid show(int**b){\n printf (\"%d \",**b);\n}\nint main(){\n int i;\n int a[] = { 23,34,45,56};\n for(i=0;i<3;i++) show(&a[i]+1);\n return (0);\n}\nA. 23 45 56\nB. 23 34 45\nC. 45 56 23 \nD. 34 45 56", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 95, "Question": "Which of the following is used to call a function named as doFun()\nA. Call foFunc();\nB. doFunc();\nC. include doFunc();\nD. None of other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 96, "Question": "What is the output of the following program ?\nvoid main()\n{\n Printf(\"%d\",-5/-4);\n}\nA. -1.25\nB. 1.25\nC. -1\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 97, "Question": "Which one is not the standard library in C?\nA. time.h\nB. stdlib.h\nC. system.h\nD. math.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 98, "Question": "Data is stored in computer memory in .........\nChoose one answer. \n a. decimal format. \n b. hexadecimal format. \n c. octal format. \n d. binary format.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 99, "Question": "Which of these statements about primary memory are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Primary memory holds the information accessed by the CPU. \n b. RAM is a volatile memory. \n c. There is only one operation on primary memory and it is reading. \n d. ROM is a volatile memory. \n e. Primary memory is addressable.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 100, "Question": "(1) One byte consists of 4 nibbles. \n(2) One nibble consists of 2 consecutive bits\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. (1): false \n b. (1) true. \n c. (2): true. \n d. (2): false", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 101, "Question": "Which of these statements about fundamental unit in CPU is true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. The natural unit of the CPU is a int \n b. The natural unit of the CPU is a numeric \n c. The natural unit of the CPU is a bit \n d. The natural unit of the CPU is a word \n e. The natural unit of the CPU is a byte", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 102, "Question": "Which of these definitions are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The CPU performs the operation on the values stored as operands or on the values stored in the operand addresses. \n b. The addresses are specific values of a program. \n c. The addresses are either register names or primary memory addresses. \n d. Each program instruction consists of an operation and operands. \n e. Each program instruction consists of an expression only.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 103, "Question": "Comments of a program ......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. are used for documenting a program. \n b. are omitted by the compiler. \n c. enhance the readability of a program. \n d. are translated into instructions after the program is compiled.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B C "}, {"ID": 104, "Question": "Select correct properties of C language.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. C source code must be translated into executable code by a compiler. \n b. C language is a functional language. \n c. C language is case-insensitive language. \n d. C is case sensitive language. \n e. C language is a low-level language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B D "}, {"ID": 105, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. A compiler will translate each statement of source code into machine code then CPU executes this statement. \n b. An interpreter will iterate to translate each statement of source code into machine code then CPU execute these binary code of this statement. \n c. Compiler of the language A can translate A-source code into language B-source code then the B-language compiler will translate B-source code into machine code. \n d. An interpreter will translate all source codes into machine codes then CPU executes them as a whole.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 106, "Question": "....... helps identifying the device which will communiate with CPU.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Address bus. \n b. All \n c. Control bus. \n d. Data bus.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 107, "Question": "Which type qualifiers are defined in C?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. short \n b. complex \n c. double \n d. array \n e. long", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 108, "Question": "In C, select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The expression x=y; will copy value of the variable x to the variable y. \n b. The expression x=y; will copy value of the variable y to the variable x. \n c. A constant character must be enclosed by a pair of double or single quotes. \n d. A constant string must be enclosed by a pair of double quotes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D "}, {"ID": 109, "Question": "1. Intel use this little-endian ordering\n2. Motorola use middle-endian ordering\n3. Motorola use big-endian ordering\n4. Intel use this big-endian ordering\nChoose one answer. \n a. 2, 3 true \n b. All of them are true \n c. 1, 4 true \n d. 2, 4 true \n e. 1, 3 true \n f. 1, 2 true \n g. All of them are false", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 110, "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. employee salary \n b. False \n c. _123 \n d. +ab \n e. 45n \n f. True", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D E "}, {"ID": 111, "Question": "Which of these statements about constants are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The compiler allocates memory for constants. \n b. The compiler does not allocate memory for constants. \n c. The compiler embeds constants directly into the program instructions. \n d. The compiler compiles constants.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 112, "Question": "In C language, \n(1) The == operator is used for setting a value to a variable. \n(2) The = operator is used for checking whether two numbers are equal or not. \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. (2): true. \n b. (2): false \n c. (1): false \n d. (1) true.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 113, "Question": "Select correct statements. With respect to ASCII, ..........\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Binary ASCII code of the character a is 0100 0001 \n b. Binary ASCII code of the digit 1 is 0000 0001 \n c. Binary ASCII of the character A is 0100 0001 \n d. The code of a uppercase character is less than the code of a lowercase character. \n e. The code of a digit is less than the code of an alphabet.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 114, "Question": "Select correct conversion specifiers for an int variable in C lanaguge.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. %f \n b. %o \n c. %e \n d. %d \n e. %u", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D E "}, {"ID": 115, "Question": "In C language, the selection constructs use ....... \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. while \n b. switch \n c. for \n d. ?: \n e. if else \n f. if else then", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D E "}, {"ID": 116, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes are executed. What is the output?\nlong S=10;\nlong i=1;\nwhile (i<=10)\n{ if (i%2==0) S+=i;\ni++;\n}\nprintf(\"%ld\", S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 32 \n b. 38 \n c. 46 \n d. 40 \n e. 36", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 117, "Question": "Flags is a technique that supports using goto, continue statements\nChoose one answer. \n a. True \n b. False", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 118, "Question": "To improve readability, programmers are recommended .......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. using whitespace to identify the logical structure of the code. \n b. using goto statements as needed. \n c. removing continue statements. \n d. using break statements as needed. \n e. using comments.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 119, "Question": "Marks: 1 \n1. The rule in C is that an else statement always belongs to the innermost if available\n2. The rule in C is that an else statement always belongs to the outermost if available\nChoose one answer. \n a. Only 2nd statement is true \n b. Only 1st statement is true \n c. Both 1 and 2 statements are false \n d. Both 1 and 2 statements are true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 120, "Question": "Program should be written ... \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. with a complicated appearance. \n b. as a well program. \n c. with a consistent style and clear throughout. \n d. with significant effort and private style.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 121, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Walkthrough is a process in which any change in codes is recorded. \n b. Walkthrough process is used for evaluating the performance of a program. \n c. A table that contains all program variables is used in walkthrough process. \n d. Walkthrough is a manual process for recording all changes of program variables when the program executes instruction-by-instruction. \n e. A listing of the output, if any, produced by the program is carried out when we do a walkthrough..", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 122, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute and input data are 9 and 12.\nint m,n; \nprintf(\"Enter two integers:\"); \nscanf(\"%d%d\",&m, &n);\nif (m>10 && n<20) printf(\"%d\", m+n);\nelse printf(\"%d\", m-n);\nWhat is the output.\nChoose one answer. \n a. None of the others. \n b. 21 \n c. -3 \n d. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 123, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute. What is the output?\nlong S=10;\nlong i;\nfor (i=1; i<10; i++) if (i%3==0) S+=i;\nprintf(\"%ld\", S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 19 \n b. 31 \n c. 16 \n d. 22 \n e. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 124, "Question": "In C, which of these statements are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. #include \"filename\" using with filename locate in system directory. \n b. We can collect function prototypes into a file and refer to the file in our program \n c. We use the #include directive to instruct the compiler to insert a copy of the header file into our source code. \n d. #include <filename> using with filename locate in user directory \n e. # is a symbol of postprocessor indicators", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D E "}, {"ID": 125, "Question": "What is the output if the following code executes.\nint n=3, m=7;\nint* p1= &n, *p2=&m;\n*p1 -= m+n- 3*(*p2);\n*p2 += *p1%2 ? 2 : 5; \nprintf (\"%d\", m-n);\nChoose one answer. \n a. -5 \n b. None of the others. \n c. -4 \n d. 6 \n e. 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 126, "Question": "In C, incorrect order(s) of a function implementation:\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Return type, body, function name, parameters \n b. Return type, body, parameters, function name \n c. Return type, function name, parameters, body \n d. Return type, parameters, body, function name", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B D "}, {"ID": 127, "Question": "Which of these statements about the function is true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. All of the others \n b. The body is the code block that contains the module instructions and generates the return value \n c. A function definition consists of a header and a body \n d. A function that does not return a value is called a subroutine or procedure in other languages \n e. A function may receive data and may return a value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 128, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Actual parameter is a parameter in function implementation. \n b. Formal parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called. \n c. Actual parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called. \n d. Formal parameter is a parameter in function implementation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 129, "Question": "Select the statements that belong to low cohesion\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. \"logical\" - related tasks of which only one is performed - the module identifier suggests a choice \n b. \"functional\" - performs a single specific task - the module identifier suggests a precise verb phrase \n c. \"communicational\" - the tasks share the same data - all tasks are carried out each time \n d. \"coincidental\" - unrelated tasks", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 130, "Question": "In C, with reference to property of reusing a function, the function that will check whether an integer is a prime or not, should be declared as ........ \nChoose one answer. \n a. a void function. \n b. a function that returns a real number. \n c. a function that will return an integer. \n d. None of the others \n e. a function that returns a string a characters.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 131, "Question": "Study the following function:\nint t (int x, int y, int z)\n{ return x+y+z>20 ? 10 : 20;\n}\nIf this function is called as following with input data are 5 10 15. What is the output?\nint a,b,c;\nprintf(\"Enter 3 integers:\");\nscanf(\"%d%d%d\", &a, &b, &c);\nprintf(\"%d\", t(b,c,a));\nChoose one answer. \n a. None of the others. \n b. 20 \n c. -10 \n d. 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 132, "Question": "Study the function implementation and a case of using this function.\nint t (int x, int y)\n{ return x-y;\n}\n...\nchar c1= 'A', c2= 'D';\nprintf(\"%d\", t(c2, c1));\nSuppose that the above codes execute. What is the output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. An error is thrown when they are executed. \n b. No output is printed out. \n c. 3 \n d. -3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 133, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute. What is the output.\nint n=3, m=7;\nint* p1= &n, *p2=&m;\n*p1 -= m+n- 3*(*p2);\n*p2 += m-n; \nprintf (\"%d\", m+n);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 14 \n b. 16 \n c. 12 \n d. 20 \n e. 18", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 134, "Question": "Which of these statements about the scanf function are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The return code from scanf reflects success of %* conversions \n b. scanf retrieves data values from every keystroke directly \n c. interpreted and processed the entire format string \n d. scanf treats the whitespace between the input values as a separator \n e. If the buffer is empty, the function scanf will wait until the user adds more data values", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 135, "Question": "Select incorrect statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The specifier %hex is used for printing out an integer in hexadecimal format. \n b. The specifier %e is used for printing out a real number in scientific format. \n c. The specifier %u is used for printing out a unsigned integer. \n d. The specifier %b is used to print out an integer in binary format.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 136, "Question": "The getchar function can do\nChoose one answer. \n a. clearing the buffer automatically after retrieving \n b. None of the others \n c. treats the whitespace between the input values as a separator \n d. retrieves data values from every keystroke directly", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 137, "Question": "What library includes function to generate random numbers?\nChoose one answer. \n a. conio.h \n b. stdio.h \n c. stdlib.h \n d. math.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 138, "Question": "Validation do not include\nChoose one answer. \n a. out-of-range input \n b. invalid characters \n c. trailing characters \n d. None of the others \n e. incorrect number of input fields", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 139, "Question": "Which of these statements about format string are not true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. size identifies the size of data type of the value passed. \n b. % flags width . precision size conversion_character \n c. - describes left justification of the converted value in its field \n d. None of the others \n e. 0 pads the field width with leading zeros", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 140, "Question": "What is the output of the following program?\n/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ double x= 3.5, y= 6.8 , z= 1.5;\nint n= floor( x )+ ceil( y )+ z;\nprintf(\"%d\", n);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nChoose one answer. \n a. 12 \n b. 10 \n c. 11.5 \n d. The program causes an error when it is compiled. \n e. 11", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 141, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n;\nchar c;\nscanf(\"%d\",&n);\nc=getchar();\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", n,c);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the output of the above program if user enters the keys 12 and ENTER?\nChoose one answer. \n a. Non-predictable values. \n b. 12 \n c. No output is printed out. \n d. 12, 10 \n e. 12, 13", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 142, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n, m;\nint result = scanf(\"%d%d\",&n, &m);\nprintf(\"%d\", result);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the ouput of the above program if input is 12asd45 ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. a non-predictable value. \n b. 1 \n c. 3 \n d. 2 \n e. An error is thrown when it executes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 143, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n, m;\nscanf(\"%d,%d\",&n, &m);\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", n, m);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhen the program executes, user enters 9 100 . What is output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. Two non-predictable values. \n b. No output is printed out. \n c. 9 and a non-predictable value. \n d. An error when it executes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 144, "Question": "Program ....\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. is a collection of functions. \n b. is a simulation of solution. \n c. is the result of a programming process. \n d. is a set of instructions that computer hardware will execute. \n e. is written by C language only.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C D "}, {"ID": 145, "Question": "What are the right matching?\nCharacter Sequence\na. Newline \\t\nb. vertical tab \\v\nc. backslash \\\nd. alarm \\r\ne. backspace \\b\nf. question mark \\?\n \n \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. a \n b. f \n c. e \n d. c \n e. b \n f. d", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C E "}, {"ID": 146, "Question": "Which of these statements about the array are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. In C, the index of an element can be begin from 1. \n b. An array is stored in contiguously block of memory and each element is identified by its index. \n c. The index of an element can be an integer variable, an integer expression or an integer constant. \n d. We use the operator () to access an element of array. \n e. An array is a group of related elements and they belong the same data type.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C E "}, {"ID": 147, "Question": "The linear search algorithm can be applied on an array in which its elements .......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. are in no order. \n b. are in descending order. \n c. are in ascending order. \n d. have different data types.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 148, "Question": "Study the binary search algorithm:\nint binarySearch (int x, int a[], int low, int high)\n{ while (low<=hight)\n{ int mid= (low+high)/2;\nif ( x==a[mid]) return mid ;\nelse if (x>a[mid]) low=mid+1;\nelse high=mid-1;\n}\nreturn -1;\n} \nSuppose that this function is used as following:\nint a[6] = { 1, 2, 2, 3, 3,5};\nint pos = binarySearch(3,a,0,5);\nWhat is the value of the variable pos? \n \nChoose one answer. \n a. 3 \n b. -1 \n c. 4 \n d. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 149, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Flagging technique uses an integer for marking elements of an array when we summarize data of the array. \n b. Flagging technique is applied when user input values to an array only. \n c. Flagging technique is used when we summarize data in an array. \n d. Flagging technique helps marking some data in an array.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 150, "Question": "What are the names of search algorithm applied to an array?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Linear search. \n b. Binary search. \n c. Random search. \n d. Bubble search. \n e. Selection search.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 151, "Question": "Study the following function:\nSuppose that all needed libraries are included.\nint search ( int x, int a[], int n)\n{ int i;\nfor ( i=n-1; i>=0 ; i--) if (x==a[i]) return i;\nreturn -1;\n}\nThis function is used as following:\nint a[10] = { 1, 2, 2, 2, 3, 3, 3, 4, 4, 4};\nint pos = search(3, a, 10);\nWhen the above code executes, what is the value of the variable pos?\nChoose one answer. \n a. 6 \n b. 4 \n c. 5 \n d. -1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 152, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 1,2,3,4,5 };\nint*p= a;\nint i;\nfor (i=0;i<5; i++) \nif (i%2==0) \n{ (*p)++;\np++;\n}\nfor (i=0;i<5;i++) printf(\"%d, \", a[i]);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhen the above program executes. What is the output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. 2, 3, 4, 4, 5 \n b. 15 \n c. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 153, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 1,2,3,4,5 };\nint*p= a;\nint i;\nint S=10;\nfor (i=0;i<5; i++) \nif (a[i]%2==0) S+=a[i]; \nprintf(\"%d\", S);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. 25 \n b. 12 \n c. 15 \n d. 6 \n e. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 154, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nvoid f1 ( int*a, int n)\n{ int i,j,t;\nfor (i=0;i<n-1;i++)\nfor (j=n-1; j>i; j--)\nif (a[j]>a[j-1])\n{ t=a[j];\na[j]=a[j-1];\na[j-1]=t;\n}\n}\nvoid f2 (int a[], int n)\n{ int i;\nfor (i=0;i<n;i++) printf (\"%d%s \", a[i], (i<4 ? \",\" : \"\" ));\n}\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 5, 1, 2,4, 3 };\nf1(a,5);\nf2(a,5);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. 5, 4, 3, 2, 1 \n b. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 \n c. 2, 4, 1, 3, 5 \n d. 1, 3, 5, 2, 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 155, "Question": "With respect to the binary search algorithm on an array, .......\nChoose one answer. \n a. this algorithm cannot be applied on array of characters. \n b. The values contained in the array must be in an order (ascending or descending). \n c. this algorithm cannot be applied on array of real numbersaracters. \n d. no criterion on the array is required.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 156, "Question": "Which of these statements about the %s conversion specifier used in scanf function are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. It will read all characters until the first white space character. \n b. User can not enter any digit. \n c. It is usually used when user will enter a word such as the code of a product. \n d. A parameter of this function must be a string. \n e. It requires user entering at least 2 characters.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 157, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nvoid f(char S[ ], char c1, char c2)\n{ int L= strlen(S);\nint i;\nfor (i=0; i<L; i++)\nif (*(S+i) == c1) *(S+i)=c2;\n}\nint main() \n{ char S[10]=\"ABCDEFGEH\";\nf( S, 'E', 0);\nprintf(\"%s\", S);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. ABCD \n b. ABCD0FG0H \n c. None of the others. \n d. ABCDEFGEH", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 158, "Question": "Which of these statements about null byte terminator are not true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. We refer to the null byte using the escape sequence '\\0'. \n b. We can describe the null byte as the constant EOF. \n c. The null byte is the character with the value (code) 0. \n d. We use the null byte to locate the last meaningful element in a string", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 159, "Question": "Which of these statements about the %[^ ] specifier is true when it is used in the scanf function ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. The scanf function will store the characters read in memory locations starting with the address passed to scanf \n b. The scanf function will read all characters until the newline character \n c. The scanf function will leave the delimiting character in the input buffer \n d. All of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 160, "Question": "Which of the the following is the result of the %[abcd] conversion specifier when it is used in the scanf function and the input is dfgh ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. abcd \n b. fgh \n c. dfgh \n d. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 161, "Question": "Which is the result of strcmp(S1, S2) with S1 =\"abcdefgh\" and S2 = \"abcdefdh\"?\nChoose one answer. \n a. A negative integer. \n b. Zero. \n c. A positive integer. \n d. A character.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 162, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ char S[50]= \"ABCDEF\";\nprintf(\"Length:%d, %s\", strlen(S), &S[2]);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program s .......\nChoose one answer. \n a. Length:6, CDEF \n b. 6 and an error is thrown. \n c. The program causes an error when it is compiled. \n d. 6, CDEF", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 163, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ char S1[50]= \"ABCDEF\";\nchar S2[50]= \"GHI\";\nstrcat(S1,S2);\nprintf(\"%s\", S1);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the output of the program?\nChoose one answer. \n a. ABCDEFGHI \n b. 6 \n c. An error is thrown when it is compiled. \n d. ABCDEF \n e. 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 164, "Question": "Study three following code segments:\n(1)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nputs(S);\n(2)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nprintf(\"%s\",S);\n(3)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nprintf(\"%s \\n\",S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. (1) and (2) have the same output. \n b. (2) and (3) have the same output. \n c. All of them have different outputs. \n d. (1) and (3) have the same output.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 165, "Question": "Suppose the string library was included. Study the following C-code:\nchar S1[10]=\"AB\";\nchar S2[10]=\"AB1\";\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", strcmp(S1,S2), strcmp(S2,S1));\nThe output of the above code is:\nChoose one answer. \n a. Non-predictable values. \n b. a negative and a positive integers. \n c. The function strcmp(...) is not in string.h \n d. Two 0s. \n e. a positive and a negative integers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 166, "Question": "The function fopen(...) is used for openning a text file. Which of the following mode parameters can not be used?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. rt \n b. art \n c. RW \n d. w+t \n e. a+t", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 167, "Question": "What in the following file operations should be used when the file closed only?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. renaming a file. \n b. seeking in a file. \n c. rewinding a file. \n d. get file size. \n e. remove a file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 168, "Question": "Which of these statements about file format types are true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. With text format, the data on the file can be modified using a text editor. \n b. With text format, data from a file can be read directly to a numeral variable with no tranformation. \n c. With text format, data in a the file are stored as ASCII code of characters. \n d. With binary format, data in a file can be modified using text editor.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 169, "Question": "In C, which of following functions can be used to write data to a file?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. gets \n b. fputc \n c. fprintf \n d. fgets \n e. fgetc \n f. fputs \n g. puts \n h. fgetchar", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C F "}, {"ID": 170, "Question": "Text format is used. Which of these statements about table, record, and fields are not true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. A record is a sequence of characters that ends with a new line delimiter. \n b. Typically, one table refers to one entity of information \n c. Table is a collection of records \n d. A record consists of fields \n e. A new line delimiter must be used to separate two adjacent fields of a record. \n f. A field may be of any data type", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B E "}, {"ID": 171, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. We can rename a file if the file is closed. \n b. We can rewind a file only if the file is closed. \n c. We can rename a file although the file is openning. \n d. The file can be remove if it is openning. \n e. Rewinding a file will move current position to the beginning of the file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 172, "Question": "Suppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\nint n=7;\nIn C, if this variable is written to a textfile (using ASCII code), it will take ... byte(s) in the file.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 2 \n b. 4 \n c. 3 \n d. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 173, "Question": "Suppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\nint n=7;\nIn C, if this variable is written to a binary file, it will take ... byte(s) in the file.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 1 \n b. 4 \n c. 2 \n d. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 174, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nSuppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\n(1) Writing int values into text file will make the file having small size.\n(2) Writing int values into text file will make the file having large size.\n(3) Writing int values into text file is less efficient because type conversions are needed.\nChoose one answer.\n a. (1) and (3) \n b. None of the others. \n c. (3) \n d. (2) and (3)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 175, "Question": "What guideline should be examined before working with a text file?\n(1) data format in the file must be known or designed.\n(2) number of values in the file must be known .\n(3) Last date modified of the file must be known.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 3 \n b. 1 \n c. 2 \n d. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 176, "Question": "Which of these statements about the black-box testing are not true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. External factors, such as logic-driven, and path-oriented, are determinant \n b. Each possible path through the code is executed at least once. The number of possibilities to be tested may be too great \n c. Synonyms for black-box include: structural, glass-box and clear-box \n d. External factors, such as testing to specifications, input-output driven, and data driven, are determinant \n e. Synonyms for black-box include: behavioral, functional, opaque-box, and closed-box", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B C "}, {"ID": 177, "Question": "Methods are used in testing a software are .........\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. White box testing \n b. Black box testing. \n c. Action testing \n d. Statement testing", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 178, "Question": "Which of these statements about comparing the difference of Waterfall and Open Source Model are true?\nChoose one answer.\n a. The Open Source is seldom reliability than Waterfall Models \n b. The Waterfall Models focus is user-driven rather than concept driven in Open Source Models \n c. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 179, "Question": "Marks: 1\nStatement 1: If a program works then it is good designed.\nStatement 2: If the program models a real world situation, it can be hardly upgraded.\nChoose one answer.\n a. One of two statements is true. \n b. The statement 2 is true. \n c. Both of them are false. \n d. The statement 1 is true.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 180, "Question": "Study the following steps in software development process:\n(1) Analysis\n(2) Design\n(3) Implementing\n(4) Deploying\n(5) Maintenance\nThe correct order of them is ..........\nChoose one answer.\n a. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 \n b. None of the others. \n c. 1, 3, 2, 4, 5 \n d. 2, 3, 1, 4, 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 181, "Question": "The output of a program is incorrect. It may be caused by ......\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. the algorithm is wrong. \n b. a semantic error. \n c. a syntactical error.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 182, "Question": "Analysis and maintenance are ............. phases in the sofware development process.\nChoose one answer.\n a. intermediate \n b. None of the others. \n c. last and first \n d. first and last", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 183, "Question": "........software development model(s) has (have) some phases that are concurrently carried out.\nChoose one answer.\n a. Waterfall and practical \n b. None of the others. \n c. Practical \n d. Waterfall", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 184, "Question": "Restricting our use of the language to the standard subset of a language will create the ......... of a program.\nChoose one answer.\n a. portability \n b. efficiency \n c. correctness \n d. reliability", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 185, "Question": "Program information does not consist of\nSelect one:\na. Data\nb. text files\nc. Instructions", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. text files "}, {"ID": 186, "Question": "Which of these statements about primary memory is not true?\nSelect one:\na. Primary memory is also volatile\nb. RAM is a primary memory\nc. Primary memory transfers information at lower speed than hard disks\nd. Primary memory holds the information accessed by the CPU.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. Primary memory transfers information at lower speed than hard disks "}, {"ID": 187, "Question": "Which of these definitions are true about an instruction of a program?\nSelect one:\na. Each program instruction consists of an operation and operands\nb. The addresses are either address names or ROM addresses only\nc. Operation code of an instruction was depended on the specific CPU.\nd. Each program instruction consists of an arithmetic expression only.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. Each program instruction consists of an operation and operands "}, {"ID": 188, "Question": "C language is\nSelect one or more:\na. Case-sensitive language\nb. a perfect language\nc. Safe language\nd. a powerful language\ne. an English-like language\nf. a simple language", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E,a, d, "}, {"ID": 189, "Question": "(1) One byte consists of 4 nibbles. \n(2) One nibble consists of 2 consecutive bits\nThe statement (1) is ...., (2) is .....\nSelect one:\na. false, false\nb. true, true\nc. true, false\nd. false, true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. false, false "}, {"ID": 190, "Question": "Select correct statement(s)\nSelect one:\na. All of the others.\nb. C-compilers compile all comments\nc. Comments in a program enhance the program readability\nd. C-compilers treat comments as strings of characters", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. Comments in a program enhance the program readability "}, {"ID": 191, "Question": "The unit of memory within CPU is ............\nSelect one:\na. byte\nb. bit\nc. word\nd. 2 bytes\ne. None of the others.\nf. 4 bytes", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. word "}, {"ID": 192, "Question": "CPU can process intructions in .......\nSelect one:\na. Text format only.\nb. Binary format only\nc. Text or binary format.\nd. Octal format\ne. Hexadecimal format.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. Binary format only "}, {"ID": 193, "Question": "1- Analyzing , 2- Implementing, 3- Planning, 4- Testing\nWhat is correct order a programmer should follow?\nSelect one:\na. 1, 2, 3, 4\nb. 1, 3, 2, 4\nc. 3, 2, 1, 4\nd. 3, 1, 2, 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. 1, 3, 2, 4 "}, {"ID": 194, "Question": "A computer program ........\nSelect one:\na. is a set of instructions that computer hardware will execute.\nb. will increase performance of standard workflow.\nc. is a simulation of solution.\nd. All of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d. All of the others. "}, {"ID": 195, "Question": "In a flowchart, we use a ......... to express a decision.\nSelect one:\na. Rectangle\nb. Polygon\nc. Diamond\nd. Oval", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. Diamond "}, {"ID": 196, "Question": "Which of the following statements are true about naming conventions in C language?\n1- A name can start with a digit.\n2- A name can start with a letter.\n3- A name can start with a dollar symbol.\n4- A name can start with an underscore symbol.\n\nSelect one:\na. 2, 4\nb. 1, 3\nc. 1, 2, 3\nd. 2, 3, 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. 2, 4 "}, {"ID": 197, "Question": "What are the right matching?\nCharacter\nSequence\na. Newline \\t\nb. vertical tab \\v\nc. backslash \\bl\nd. alarm \ne. backspace \\bu\nf. question mark \\qm\ng. None of others \n\n\nSelect one:\na. c\nb. b\nc. a\nd. g\ne. d\nf. e\ng. f", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 198, "Question": "There are two ways to express an algorithm. They are ......... and ...........\nSelect one:\na. program, flowchart\nb. pseudo code, flowchart\nc. program, instructions\nd. instructions , flowchart", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. pseudo code, flowchart "}, {"ID": 199, "Question": "Which of these statements about integer literal constants are true?\nSelect one:\na. The compiler does not compile constants\nb. The compiler does not allocate memory for constants\nc. The compiler allocates memory for constants\nd. The compiler embeds constants directly into the program instructions", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. The compiler allocates memory for constants "}, {"ID": 200, "Question": "Which qualifiers is defined in C language?\nSelect one:\na. double\nb. complex\nc. array\nd. short", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d. short "}, {"ID": 201, "Question": "Choose incorrect statement(s)\nSelect one:\na. in C, comment lines are blocked by /* and */\nb. A C program will start at main() function\nc. A C statement is terminated by a colon.\nd. A C function is wrapped by curly braces.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. A C statement is terminated by a colon. "}, {"ID": 202, "Question": "The type character of the int datatype is ........., and the float datatype is .......\nSelect one:\na. %d %lf\nb. %i %s\nc. %d %f\nd. %d %ld\ne. %i %L", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. %d %f "}, {"ID": 203, "Question": "Which of these statements about cultural symbols is true?\nSelect one:\na. Store cultural symbols using an integral data type\nb. Store a symbol by storing the double associated with the symbol\nc. Store cultural symbols using a float data type", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. Store cultural symbols using an integral data type "}, {"ID": 204, "Question": "Which of these statements about the magic value are true?\nSelect one:\na. Magic values and refer to the symbolic names throughout the code\nb. All of the others\nc. Use #define SYMBOLIC_NAME =value;\nd. Use #define_magic to manage idiosyncrasies across platforms", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. Magic values and refer to the symbolic names throughout the code "}, {"ID": 205, "Question": "A good source program is that:\nSelect one:\na. A program is written with mix styles\nb. Other programmers try him/herself to understand it with significant effort\nc. Difficult to read\nd. The coding style is consistent and clear throughout", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d. The coding style is consistent and clear throughout "}, {"ID": 206, "Question": "Which of the following is incorrect selection construct?\nSelect one:\na. ? :\nb. if then else\nc. switch\nd. if else", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. if then else "}, {"ID": 207, "Question": "Choose the correct statement about the else statement in C language.\nSelect one:\na. The rule in C is that an else always belongs to the innermost if available.\nb. The rule in C is that an else always belongs to the outermost if available.\nc. The else statement is an independent statement.\nd. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. The rule in C is that an else always belongs to the innermost if available. "}, {"ID": 208, "Question": "Which of these statements about Magic Values are not true?\nSelect one or more:\na. Syntax for a magic value:\ndefine Name = value;\nb. Use #define to manage idiosyncrasies across platforms\nc. They are declared using the include directive.\nd. They will be replaced by the declared values before compiling\ne. Magic Value improves readability", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,b,c(0,67) "}, {"ID": 209, "Question": "The constructs using in C include:\nSelect one or more:\na. Repeat-Until constructs\nb. Sequence constructs\nc. Conditional constructs\nd. Block constructs\ne. Statement constructs\nf. Selection constructs\ng. Iteration constructs", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b,f,g "}, {"ID": 210, "Question": "Which of the following C-keywords can cause violations to the one-entry principle of structured programming?\nSelect one or more:\na. return\nb. do ... while\nc. continue\nd. goto\ne. register\nf. break\ng. * operator\nh. while", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c,d,f "}, {"ID": 211, "Question": "Which of the following shows the correct syntax for an if statement?\nSelect one:\na. if expression\nb. if { expression }\nc. if (expression)\nd. expression if", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. if (expression) "}, {"ID": 212, "Question": "Choose one correct statement about a walkthrough.\nSelect one:\na. A record of the changes that occur in the values of program variables as a program executes\nb. Output produced by the program\nc. All of the others\nd. Used evaluating the programming performance\ne. A record of the changes that the developer modified code", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. A record of the changes that occur in the values of program variables as a program executes "}, {"ID": 213, "Question": "Flag variables must be used in jumping statements (goto, continue, break statements).\nSelect one:\na. True\nb. False", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. False "}, {"ID": 214, "Question": "Select an incorrect statement:\nSelect one:\na. Function is a self-contained program segment that carries out a specific, well-defined task.\nb. Function is a group of statements is given a name.\nc. C functions can be nested.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 215, "Question": "A module/function is high cohesive if .........\nSelect one:\na. It performs some separate tasks.\nb. It can be divided into some sub-modules/functions.\nc. It performs a single task.\nd. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c. It performs a single task. "}, {"ID": 216, "Question": "Which of these statements are not true?\nSelect one:\na. All of the others.\nb. # is a symbol of postprocessor indicators\nc. #include <filename> using with filename locate in user directory\nd. #include \"filename\" using with filename locate in system directory", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a. All of the others. "}, {"ID": 217, "Question": "Which of these statements are true?\nSelect one:\na. We use the #define directive to instruct the compiler to insert a copy of the header file into our source code\nb. #include \"filename\" is used with filename located in user directory\nc. We can collect function prototypes into file and refer to the file in our program\nd. #include <filename> is used with filename located in any directory\ne. # is a symbol of postprocessor indicators", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. #include \"filename\" is used with filename located in user directory "}, {"ID": 218, "Question": "Correct order of a function implementation:\nSelect one:\na. Return type, body, function name, parameters\nb. Return type, body, parameters, function name\nc. Return type, parameters, body, function name\nd. Return type, function name, parameters, body", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d. Return type, function name, parameters, body "}, {"ID": 219, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nSelect one or more:\na. Actual parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called.\nb. Formal parameter is a parameter in function implementation.\nc. Actual parameter is a parameter in function implementation.\nd. Formal parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,b "}, {"ID": 220, "Question": "Incorrect order(s) of a function implementation:\nSelect one or more:\na. Return type, parameters, body, function name.\nb. Return type, body, parameters, function name.\nc. Return type, body, function name, parameters.\nd. Return type, function name, parameters, body.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,b,c "}, {"ID": 221, "Question": "Study the following statements:\n\n(1) Formal parameters are parameters in function implementation.\n(2) Actual parameters are parameters that are transferred to a function when it is called.\n\nThe statement (1) is ...., the statement (2) is .......\nSelect one:\na. true, true\nb. false, false\nc. true, false\nd. false, true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 222, "Question": "Which of these statements about C-functions is (are) true?\nSelect one:\na. A function definition consists of a header and a body\nb. All of the others\nc. The body is the code block that contains the module instructions may generate the return value\nd. A function that does not return a value is called a subroutine or procedure in other languages\ne. A function may receive data and may return a value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 223, "Question": "Select true statement(s)\nSelect one or more:\na. The format of calling a function is: FuctionName(..)\nb. Parentheses in calling function format is optional.\nc. The function calls another is known as \"calling function\"\nd. The function is called by another is known as \"calling function\"", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,c "}, {"ID": 224, "Question": "What do the scanf(\"%d%*c\", &number) statement do?\nSelect one:\na. clear the buffer\nb. swallow the new line symbol after the input.\nc. swallow the buffer\nd. swallow one character first", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 225, "Question": "What in the following functions are formatted io functions?\nSelect one:\na. putchar(...)\nb. getchar()\nc. println(...)\nd. scanf(...)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 226, "Question": "The getchar function ....\nSelect one:\na. clears the buffer automatically after retrieving\nb. retrieves data values from every keystroke directly\nc. treats the whitespace between the input values as a separator\nd. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 227, "Question": "Which of these statements about the scanf function is not true?\nSelect one:\na. It processes the input based on the entire format string\nb. The whitespaces between the input values are treated as separators\nc. If a character that does not meet the next conversion specification in the format string is found, it leaves the offending character in the buffer\nd. It retrieves data values from every keystroke directly", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 228, "Question": "The function scanf(...) will return ........\nSelect one:\na. A list of data entered\nb. 1 if success, 0 if failed.\nc. Number of fields successfully entered.\nd. Value of the first data entered.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 229, "Question": "Data validations do not include ...\nSelect one:\na. trailing characters\nb. incorrect number of input fields\nc. out-of-range input\nd. invalid characters\ne. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "e "}, {"ID": 230, "Question": "Which of the following header files declared functions related to dynamic memory allocation/ de-allocation?\nSelect one:\na. stdlib.h\nb. math.h\nc. stdio.h\nd. conio.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 231, "Question": "The function double pow(double, double) is declared in the header file .......\nSelect one:\na. conio.h\nb. math.h\nc. stdio.h\nd. stdlib.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 232, "Question": "Flagging is the solution of using a masking array to search the inputted valued from the user only.\nSelect one:\na. False\nb. True", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 233, "Question": "A binary search algorithm will ....\nSelect one or more:\na. keep discarding the half of the remaining subset of elements that does not contain the search value\nb. return the last index when searching founds\nc. return -1 if match found\nd. work with any array\ne. calculate the mid-element following the formula (low+high+1)/2\nf. discard half of the array that does not contain the search value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,e,f "}, {"ID": 234, "Question": "Which of these statements about arrays is true?\nSelect one:\na. To refer to an element, we use the array name followed by parentheses notation around the element index\nb. Index numbering starts at 1 and extends to the size of the array\nc. The index can be an integer variable, an integer expression or an integer constant\nd. A C- array can stored elements in different data types", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 235, "Question": "Name of algorithms for searching an element in an array?\nSelect one:\na. linear search, bubble search, selection search\nb. masking, flagging\nc. Linear search, binary search\nd. bubble search and binary search\ne. binary search, and selection search", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 236, "Question": "Which of these statements about masking technique are true?\nSelect one:\na. None of the others\nb. generate a truly fair result\nc. one array hides or 'masks' the corresponding elements of parallel arrays\nd. using a masking array to find the subtotals of common valued items in a list", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 237, "Question": "Select correct statement(s)\nSelect one or more:\na. We can use the assign operator to assign an array as a whole.\nb. We can not use the assign operators to assign an array as a whole.\nc. If a is an array then a and &a[0] are equivalent.\nd. If an array of primitive data type elements, we have to use assign operator to set values to each element.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b,c,d "}, {"ID": 238, "Question": "An element of an array can be identified by ...\nSelect one:\na. Its position in the array\nb. its name\nc. its value\nd. Its data type", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 239, "Question": "Dimension of an array is ...\nSelect one:\na. the number of elements which are contained in the array\nb. the number of indices will be needed to identify an element.\nc. Name of the array.\nd. the number of elements which can be contained in the array", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 240, "Question": "Array is ........\nSelect one:\na. A group of different variables\nb. A group of elements which can have different data type\nc. A group of constants.\nd. A group of elements which have the same data type.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 241, "Question": "Binary search algorithm ....\nSelect one:\na. All of the others\nb. discards half of the array that does not contain the search value\nc. Compares the search value to the middle element of the array.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 242, "Question": "Select an incorrect data definition in C language.\nSelect one:\na. char* S4 ;\nb. char S2[20] = 'Hello' ;\nc. char S3[40] = \"Hi All!\" ;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b. char S2[20] = 'Hello' ; "}, {"ID": 243, "Question": "Which of these statements about %[^ ] is true when it is used in the scanf function ?\nSelect one:\na. Reading a string of characters until the Enter key is pressed\nb. None of the others.\nc. Reading a string of characters until the blank key is pressed\nd. Reading an integer", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 244, "Question": "Which of the following statements about the %s conversion specifier, used in the scanf function, is true?\nSelect one:\na. reads all characters until the newline (' ')\nb. reads all characters until the first white space character\nc. stores the null byte in the memory byte following the first character accepted", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 245, "Question": "Given S is a string variable and the function call fflush(stdin) will clear the input buffer. What code in the followings will allow user input a string certainly?\nSelect one:\na. puts(S)\nb. fflush(stdin) ; gets(S);\nc. gets(S)\nd. get(S);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 246, "Question": "Which of these statements about null byte terminator are true?\nSelect one or more:\na. The null byte is the character with the value (code) 0.\nb. We refer to the null byte using the escape sequence '\\0'.\nc. We refer to the null byte using the escape sequence NULL or EOF.\nd. The number of elements occupied by a string equals the number of non-null characters\ne. We use the null byte to locate the last meaningful element in a string", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,b,e "}, {"ID": 247, "Question": "Which of the following statements about null byte terminator is not true?\nSelect one:\na. The null byte is the character with the value (code) 0.\nb. We refer to the null byte using the escape sequence '\\0'.\nc. We refer to the null byte using the escape sequence NULL or EOF.\nd. We use the null byte to locate the last meaningful element in a string", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 248, "Question": "The delimiter of a string in C is ...... and its code is .........\nSelect one:\na. ESC, 27\nb. Enter, 10\nc. NULL, 0\nd. Enter, 13", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 249, "Question": "Which result of strcmp(S1, S2) with S1 =\"abcdefgh\" and S2 = \"abcdefdh\"?\nSelect one:\na. 0\nb. A negative integer.\nc. None of the others\nd. A positive integer.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 250, "Question": "Given S is a string variable. Choose a statement that will cause an error?\nSelect one:\na. scanf( \"%s\", S);\nb. S[0]= getchar();\nc. gets(S);\nd. S= getchar();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 251, "Question": "Which result of %[abcd] conversion specifier, used in the scanf function, with the input value is dfgh?\nSelect one:\na. None of the others\nb. fgh\nc. dfgh", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 252, "Question": "A unit data in text file is .....\nSelect one:\na. A word.\nb. A string.\nc. An ASCII code of a character.\nd. A number.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 253, "Question": "Rewinding is used to write data to the file?\nSelect one:\na. True\nb. False", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 254, "Question": "In C language, which of the following functions can not used to write data to a file?\n\nSelect one or more:\na. fputc\nb. fprintf\nc. fputs\nd. gets\ne. puts", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d,e "}, {"ID": 255, "Question": "Which of these statements about table, record, and fields is (are) not true?\nSelect one:\na. None of the others.\nb. In a text file, each record is usually separated with others by a new line delimiter\nc. A table includes some records\nd. A record includes some fields", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 256, "Question": "In C language, which of the following functions are applied to write data to a file?\nSelect one:\na. fputs, puts, fprintf, fscanf\nb. fprintf, fputc, fputs\nc. fgetchar, fputchar, freadchar\nd. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 257, "Question": "int n=12345;\nHow many bytes in a text file will store the value of n ?\nSelect one:\na. 4\nb. 5\nc. 2\nd. 6\ne. 7", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 258, "Question": "Two-byte variable int n= 12 will be stored on a ASCII text file as ......\nSelect one:\na. 00110001 00110010\nb. 00000001 00000010\nc. 00000000 00001100\nd. 00000010 00000001", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 259, "Question": "Which of these statements about file format types is true?\nSelect one:\na. In text format, each byte on the file is a direct image of the corresponding byte in memory\nb. Binary format is portability\nc. In text format, the data on the file is in a form that we can display and modify using a text editor.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 260, "Question": "Select the best choice. File is .........\nSelect one:\na. data, stored in external memory of computer.\nb. data, stored in network storage.\nc. data, stored in main memory of computer.\nd. data, stored in compact disk of computer.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 261, "Question": "Which of these statements about the mode parameter, used when opening a text file, is false?\nSelect one:\na. \"r\" : open the file for reading.\nb. \"r+\" : open the file for reading and writing.\nc. \"a\" : open the file for appending.\nd. \"w\" : opens the file for reading and writing", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 262, "Question": "ASCII stand for", "Choices": [], "Answer": "American standard code for information interchange "}, {"ID": 263, "Question": "Registers:", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Registers are the fastest memory type. "}, {"ID": 264, "Question": "Von Neumann architecture", "Choices": [], "Answer": "stored-program computers "}, {"ID": 265, "Question": "programming language", "Choices": [], "Answer": "The higher the level of programming language, the closer to the human languages and the further from native machine languages. "}, {"ID": 266, "Question": "syntactical error and semantic error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Example for a syntactical error: return statement missing\nExample for a semantic error: infinite iteration "}, {"ID": 267, "Question": "primitive data types", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C has four primitive data types: int, char, float and double. "}, {"ID": 268, "Question": "Derived data types", "Choices": [], "Answer": "store multiple values of same type in one variable but never allows to store multiple values of different types "}, {"ID": 269, "Question": "pointers", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Pointers are used to manipulate data using the address. "}, {"ID": 270, "Question": "array", "Choices": [], "Answer": "An array is group of elements, which are of the same size and data type and have the same name. "}, {"ID": 271, "Question": "Gets the next character (an unsigned char) from the specified stream and advances the position indicator for the stream.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "getc "}, {"ID": 272, "Question": "Writes a character (an unsigned char) specified by the argument char to the specified stream and advances the position indicator for the stream.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "fputc "}, {"ID": 273, "Question": "Once the function ends, the control is returned back to the ... function and execution continues from the statement immediately after the function call\na. executing\nb.called\nc.declared\nd.calling", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 274, "Question": "what number is equivalent to -4e3?\na.-4000\nb.-400\nc..004\nd..0004\ne.-40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 275, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\nif(v==1||v==0)\nreturn 1;\nif(v%2==0)\nreturn (fn(v/2)+2);\nelse\nreturn(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\nreturn (0);\n}\na.6\nb.9\nc.8\nd.7\ne.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 276, "Question": "which 2 options are correct about the function scanf?\na.EOF indicates that scanf filled all addresses successfully\nb. scanf returns the number of addresses successfully filled of EOF\nc.return avoid type\nd.EOF indicates that scanf did not fill any address AND encountered an end of data character.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b,d "}, {"ID": 277, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint s=35;\nprintf(\"%d%d%d\",s==35,s+20,s>40)\na.1 35 1\nb.1 55 1\nc.0 55 0\nd.1 55 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 278, "Question": "according to the standard C specification, what are the respective minimum sizes (in bytes) of the following two data type: int and long?\na.2,8\nb.4,8\nc.2,4\nd.2,2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 279, "Question": "what does the following declaration mean (if there are more than one correct answers, choose the best one)\nint *ptr[10];\na.array of 10 integer pointers\nb.pointed to the array of 10 elements\nc.array of 10 pointers", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 280, "Question": "what would happen if the user types in the number 3 and presses Enter when running this program?\nmain(){\nint x=5;\nchar c;\nprintf(\"Enter x=\");\nscanf(\"%d\",&x);\nprintf(\"Calculate square(Y/N):\");\nc=getchar();\nif(c==Y||c==y)\nprintf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\na.sqr=9\nb.Its depend on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \"calculate square?\"\nc.sqr=25\nd.the program exits without printing the square", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 281, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i,j,k,x=0;\nfor(i=1;i<5;i++)\nfor(j=0;j<i;++j){\nswitch(i+j){\ncase 0:x=x+1;\nbreak;\ncase 1:\ncase 2:\ncase 3: x=x+2;\nbreak;\n}}\nprintf(\"%d\",x);\na.12\nb.13\nc.10\nd.8\ne.6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 282, "Question": "the while loop can be written as a for loop\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 283, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar fun[]=\"How are you?\";\nchar **p;\np=fun;\nwhile(***p!='\\0'){\nif(strlen(p)!=7) printf(\"%c\",**p);\np++;}\na. How ar you\nb.Ho are you\nc.How re you\nd.How are you\ne. How ae you", "Choices": [], "Answer": "e "}, {"ID": 284, "Question": "given the below code ?\nchar st[50];\nscanf(\"%5[^\\]\",st);\nprintf(\"%s\",st);\na user enters \"pfc is simple\"\nwhat is printed?\na.other\nb.pfc is\nc.pfc is so simple\nd.blank output\ne.pfc i", "Choices": [], "Answer": "e "}, {"ID": 285, "Question": "how is a variable accessed from another file?\na. the global variable is referenced via the auto specifier\nb. the global variable is referenced via the extern specifier\nc. the global variable is referenced via the pointer specifier\nd. the global variable is referenced via the ext specifier\ne. the global variable is referenced via the global specifier", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 286, "Question": "which one of the following is a variable, which can contain the address of the memory location of another variable?(choose the best answer)\na.string\nb.struct\nc.array\nd.pointer", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 287, "Question": "declare a two dimensional integer array of two rows and four columns having some initial values\na.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nb.int arr1[2][4]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nc.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12};{22,45};{23,40};{44,79}}\nd.int arr1[][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 288, "Question": "what value will x contain in the sample code below?\nint x=011|0x10;\na.27\nb.19\nc.25\nd.13\ne.3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 289, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint g=1;\nprintf(\"%d %d %d\",g,++g,g++);\na.1 3 3 \nb.1 2 3 \nc.1 1 1 \nd.3 3 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 290, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0;\nfor(;i;)\nprintf(\"This is a loop\");\nif(i>0)\nprintf(\"in C program\");\na. nothing\nb. garbage value\nc. in C program\nd.this is a loop in C program\ne. this is a loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 291, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nvoid main(){\nint i,j=25;\nint *pi, **pj=&j;\n***pj=j+5;\ni=*pj+5;\npi=pj;\n**pi=i+j;\nprintf(\"%d%d\",**pi,pj);}\na.30 35\nb.65 65\nc.60 60\nd.25 30\ne.60 65", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 292, "Question": "which one of the following is a valid function definition?\na. double funct(int a,b, double c,d)\nb. double funct(int a,b, double c)\nc. double funct(char a,b, double d)\nd. double funct(int a,int b, double c)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 293, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar mess[]=\"Your are welcome here\";\nchar *p;\np=mess;\nmess[8]='\\0';\nputs(++p);\na.our are wel\nb.our are \nc.Your are \nd.Your are wel", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 294, "Question": "which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another\na.strcpy\nb.strcmp\nc.strcat\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 295, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a=8, b=9;\nif(a%2=b%3)\nprintf(\"\\n%d %d\", ++a, b--)\na. 8 9\nb. 9 9 \nc.9 8\nd. compiler error\ne. 8 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 296, "Question": "what will be printed when the sample code below is executed?\nchar **buffer=\"0123456789\";\nchar **ptr=buffer;\nptr+=5;\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",ptr);\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",buffer);\na. 56789\n0123456789\n\nb.56789\n56789\n\nc.0123456789\n0123456789\n\nd.5123456789\n5123456789\n\ne.0123456789\n56789", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 297, "Question": "in myfile.c does not exist, what will be output of this program?\n#include<stdio.h>\nmain(){\nFILE *fi;\nfi=fopen(\"myfile.c\",\"r\");\nif(fi=NULL)\n{puts(\"file is not opened\");\nexit(1);}\nelse\nputs(\"FILE opened\");}\na. file is not opened\nb.no output\nc.FILE opened\nd.error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 298, "Question": "given the below code\nint a=1;\nint i=7;\nif(a||i++)\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nwhat is the output\na.7\nb.8\nc.9\nd.other", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 299, "Question": "a string is a ... array of characters terminated by a null('\\0')\na.one-dimensional\nb.two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 300, "Question": "referring to the sample code below, what value will the variable counter have when completed\nint x=3, counter = 0;\nwhile(x-1){\n++counter;\nx--;}\na.4 \nb.2\nc.3\nd.0\ne.1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 301, "Question": "the operation between float and int would give the result as\na. float\nb. int \nc. unsigned int\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 302, "Question": "which of the following statement are true with regards to the || operator?(select al correct answer)\na.this operator is used to combine two conditional expressions which evaluate to true as a whole only if either of the two expressions evaluate to true.\nb.only if both the expressions evaluate to false, the outcome is false\nc.if one of the conditional expressions return false, the outcome is false\nd.this operator is used to combine two logical expressions which evaluate to true if both individual expression are true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,b "}, {"ID": 303, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint k=0x55;\nprintf(\"\\n%d\",k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na.65\nb.75\nc.55\nd.85", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 304, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint calc(int a, int b){\nint x,y;\nx=a+b;\ny=a*b;\nreturn(x+y);\n}\nint main(){\nint p=3, q=4, r, s;\nr=calc(p,q);\ns=calc(q,p);\nprintf(\"\\n%d%d\",r,s);\nreturn 0;}\na. 3 4\nb. 17 19\nc. 18 18\nd. 17 17\ne.19 19", "Choices": [], "Answer": "e "}, {"ID": 305, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed, assuming int data type is 32 bits in size?\nprintf(\"%d, %d, %d, %d\", sizeof(char), sizeof(int), sizeof(10.0), sizeof(10.0f));\na. 2,4,8,4\nb. 1,10,10,10\nc. 1,4,8,4\nd. 1,4,4,4\ne. 1,2,4,4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 306, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a[5]={0}, x=2111223;\nwhile(x>10){\na[x%10-1]++;\nx/=10;}\nprintf(\"%d\",a[1]);\na.6\nb.3\nc.1\nd.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 307, "Question": "what will the code below print when executed?\ndouble x=-3.5, y=3.5;\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",ceil(x), ceil(y));\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",floor(x), floor(y));\na -3:3\n-4:4\nb.-4:3\n-3:4\nc.-4:4\n-3:3\nd.-3:4\n-4:3\ne.-4:3\n-4:3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 308, "Question": "consider the following code:\nif(a==b)\nprintf(\"\\n the number are equal\");\nelse(a<b)\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",a);\nelse\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",b);\nin the above code, if a=14 and b=9, then the .... clause is executed\na. else\nb.if\nc else if", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 309, "Question": "when does the code block following while(x<100) execute?\na.when x is less than one hundred\nb.when x is equal to one hundred\nc.when x is greater than one hundred\nd.while it wishes", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 310, "Question": "which are the following statements printf % character?\na.printf(\"\\%\")\nb.printf(\"\\\\%\")\nc.printf(\"\\%%\")\nd.printf(\"%%\")", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c,d "}, {"ID": 311, "Question": "a comment can be split over more than one line, as follows\n/** A program\nto calculate average\nof 5 numbers. **/\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 312, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint p,q,h;\nfor(p=1;p<=3;p++)\nfor(q=1;q<=2;q++)\nh=p+q;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",h);\na.1\nb.5\nc.3\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 313, "Question": "Dwhat is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint x=3;\nif(x==2)\nx=0;\nif(x==3)\nx++;\nelse x+=2;\na.5\nb.3\nc.1\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 314, "Question": "what is the incorrect statement about floating-point data types(float and double)?\na. computers store floating-point data using separate components, including the mantissa and exponent\nb.float-point means that the decimal point can float(that is, it can ba placed anywhere relative to the significant digits)\nc.both data types(float and double) can represent arbitrarily small as well as arbitrarily large numbers\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 315, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint n=10, i;\nint k=0;\nfor(i=1;i<n;i=i*2)k++;\nprintf(\"i:%d, k:%d\", i, k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na i:16, k:3\nb.i:16, k:4\nc.i:16, k:5\nd.i:8, k:4\ne.i:10, k:4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 316, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nmain()\n{int i=5;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i=++i==6)\na.0\nb.1\nc.5\nd.6\ne.7", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 317, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar *ptr=\"Hello world\";\nptr++;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\nptr+=2;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\na.ello worldllo world\nb.Hello worldHello world\nc.ello worldlo world\nd.ello worldHello world\ne.Hello worldello world", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 318, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=3;\nswitch(i){\ncase 3: i+=5;\nif(i==8){\ni++;\nif(i==9) break;\ni*=2;}\ni-=4;\nbreak;\ncase 8:\ni+=5;\nbreak;\ndefault: \ni+=6;\nbreak;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i);\na.8\nb.11\nc.7\nd.9\ne.10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 319, "Question": "using break statement we can exit from\na. for a loop\nb. an if statement\nc. the main() function\nd. a program", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 320, "Question": "give the code below\nint a=2;\nprintf(\"%d\",++a,a+5)\nwhat is printed?\na. undefined\nb. error\nc. 2\nd. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 321, "Question": "What is 7/9*9 equal to?\nA. 2\nB. 0\nC. 1\nD. 0.08642", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 322, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor( i=1; i<10,j<5;i*=2,j++){\nj+=2;\nprintf(\"%d \",j);\n}\nPrintf(\"%d %d\",i,j);\nA. 2 5 4 7\nB. 2 5 6 4\nC. 2 5 3 6 \nD. 2 5 4 8\nE. 2 5 4 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "e "}, {"ID": 323, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i;\nfor(i=1;i<4;i++)\nswitch(i){\ncase 1: printf(\"%d \",i);\nbreak;\ncase 2: printf(\"%d \",i);\nbreak;\ncase 3: printf(\"%d \",i);\nbreak;\ncase 4: printf(\"%d \",i);\n}\nA. 1 2 3 \nB. 4\nC. 1 2 3 4 \nD. 1 2 \nE. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 324, "Question": "If the program completes executing successfully, what value should the function main returned?\nA. void\nB. 0\nC. nothing\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 325, "Question": "Which one is not the standard library in C?\nA. time.h\nB. stdlib.h\nC. system.h\nD. math.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 326, "Question": "What is the output of the following program ?\nvoid main()\n{\nPrintf(\"%d\",-5/-4);\n}\nA. -1.25\nB. 1.25\nC. -1\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 327, "Question": "Which of the following is used to call a function named as doFun()\nA. Call foFunc();\nB. doFunc();\nC. include doFunc();\nD. None of other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 328, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nvoid show(int**b){\nprintf (\"%d \",**b);\n}\nint main(){\nint i;\nint a[] = { 23,34,45,56};\nfor(i=0;i<3;i++) show(&a[i]+1);\nreturn (0);\n}\nA. 23 45 56\nB. 23 34 45\nC. 45 56 23 \nD. 34 45 56", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 329, "Question": "How do you include a system header file called sysheader.h in a C source file ?\nA. #includefile<sysheader>\nB.#include<sysheader.h>\nC. #incl<sysheader.h>\nD. #incl \"sysheader.h\"\nE. #includesysheader.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 330, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor(i=1;i<10,j<3;i*=2) {\nprintf(\"%d\",j++);\n}\nprintf(\"%d%d\",i,j);\nA. 012384 \nB. 012394 \nC. 0123184\nD. 01283", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 331, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nvoid foo(int x){\nif (x>0) foo(--x);\nprintf(\"%d\",x);\n}\nint main(){\nfoo(4);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\nreturn 0;\n}\nA. 00123\nB. 001234 \nC. 430123\nD. 01234 \nE. 40123", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 332, "Question": "How is the integer pointer var declared in C?\nA. int** x;\nB. int pointer*** var;\nC. int pointer var;\nD. pointer** var;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 333, "Question": "What is size of an int ?\nA. 8 bits\nB. 16 bits \nC. Dependent on machine's \"word\" size\nD. 32 bits", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 334, "Question": "What would happen if the user types in number 3 and presses Enter when running this program ?\nmain(){\nint x=5;\nchar c;\nprintf(\"Enter x=\");\nscanf(\"%d\",&x);\nprintf(\"Calculate square?(Y/N):\");\nc=getchar();\nif (c== 'Y'|| c== 'y')\nprintf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\nA. sqr = 25\nB. The program exits without printing the square\nC. sqr = 9\nD. It depends on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \" calculate square?\"", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 335, "Question": "Which are proper declarations of a string str which stores the value \"Melodies\" (choose two)\nA. char str[]= \"Melodies\";\nB. char str[7] = \"Melodies\";\nC. char str[9] = \" Melodies\";\nD. char str[] = Melodies;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,c "}, {"ID": 336, "Question": "#include<stdlib.h>\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\nint i,n,a=10,b=20;\nfor(i=0;i<10;i++){\nn=a+rand()%(b+1-a);\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",n);\n}\nreturn 0;\n}\nRun the above program, which is correct statement about the output?\nA. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 11 and 19 inclusive.\nB. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 10 and 20 inclusive.\nC. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 9 and 21 inclusive.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 337, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint s=0;\nfor (int i=1;i<=10;++i){\ns=s+i;\nif (s>=6) break;\ns=s+1;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",s);\nA. 10\nB. 7\nC. 9\nD. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 338, "Question": "- What are the correct statements ? ( choose two)\nA. The operator ** reads as 'the data at address'.\nB. The *** operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand\nC. The operator ** reads the address of the variable.\nD. The & operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,b "}, {"ID": 339, "Question": "Which of the following data type occupied 1 byte ? (choose two)\nA. unsigned char\nB. short\nC. float\nD. long double\nE. double\nF. char", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a,f "}, {"ID": 340, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\nif( v==1||v==0) return 1;\nif(v%2==0) return(fn(v/2)+2);\nelse return(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main(){\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\nreturn (0);\n}\nA. 7\nB. 9\nC. 5\nD. 6\nE. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "e "}, {"ID": 341, "Question": "What is the correct prototype in C ?\nA. doFunc():char;\nB. char doFunc()\nC. int doFunc(int,int);\nD. void doFunc(int x, int y);\nE. float doFunc(void);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 342, "Question": "Which of the following statements prints %character ?\nA. printf(\"\\%\")\nB. printf(\"\\\\%\");\nC. printf(\"\\%%\")\nD. printf(\"%%\");", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c,d "}, {"ID": 343, "Question": "Which of the following functions compares two strings ?\nA. compare();\nB. stringcompare();\nC. cmp();\nD. strcmp();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 344, "Question": "Which is the correct statement about coupling ?\nA. Coupling is a measure of the focus within a module.\nB. In designing, high coupling is generally acceptable.\nC. Global variables introduce a low degree of coupling.\nD. We call a module highly couple if it shares that performance with some other module including the referring module.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 345, "Question": "What is required to avoid falling through from one case to the next ?\nA. break;\nB. stop;\nC. ;\nD. end;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 346, "Question": "What is the correct fomat to define a value in C ?\nA. const PI = 3.14159\nB. #define PI = 3.14159\nC. #define PI 3.14159\nD. #define PI = 3.14159;\nD. #define PI 3.14159;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 347, "Question": "- What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint i;\ni= 1;\ni = i+ 2*i ++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nA. 4\nB. 5\nC. 3\nD. 1\nE. 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 348, "Question": "Which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another ?\nA. strcpy\nB. strcmp\nC. strcat\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 349, "Question": "Which of the following statement is (are) wrong ? (choose 2)\nA. a1 = 1343.44;\nB. 3=d;\nC. 3**c=d;\nD. cat = 'A' *** 'B';\nE. asd = 'A'**24;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b,c "}, {"ID": 350, "Question": "Which of the following is the Boolean operator for logical-and ?\nA. &&\nB. &\nC. |\nD. |&", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 351, "Question": "Which is not a loop structure in C ?\nA. while\nB. for\nC. do while\nD. repeat until", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 352, "Question": "We want to round off x, a float, to an int value. The correct way to do so would be:\nA. y= (int)(x+0.5)\nB. y= (int)((int)x+0.5)\nC.y=(int) x+0.5\nD. y= int(x+0.5)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 353, "Question": "Which of the following adds ones string to the end of another?\nA. stradd();\nB. append();\nC. strcat();\nD. stringadd();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 354, "Question": "If you push 1,3, and 5 -in that odder -onto a stack , which number is popped out first?\nA. 5\nB. 1\nC. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 355, "Question": "A string is a ___ array of characters terminated by a null('\\0').\nA. one-dimensional\nB. two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 356, "Question": "By default any real number is treated as \nA. a long double\nB. a double\nC. depends upon the memory model that you are using\nD. a float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 357, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat j;\nj=1000*1000;\nprintf(\"%3.0f\",j);\nA. 1000000\nB. error\nC. overflow\nD. 100", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 358, "Question": "A user enter \"pfabcd\" from the console\nWhat is printed?\nA. pfabcd\nB. Runtime error\nC. pfa\nD. Blank(nothing output)\nE. other\nF. pf", "Choices": [], "Answer": "f "}, {"ID": 359, "Question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint sum(int n);\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"s=%d\\n\",sum(5));\nreturn 0;\n}\nint sum(int n)\n{\nint s,i;\ns=0;\nfor(i=1;i<=n;i++) s+=i;\nreturn(s);\n}\nA. s=14\nB. s=15", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 360, "Question": "What is the output?\nint main(){\nchar i=127;\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nreturn 0;\n}\nA. 128\nB. -128\nC. Undefined\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 361, "Question": "The precedence of operators is ___\nA. Arithmetic, Comparison, Logical\nB. Logical, Comparison, Arithmetic\nC. Comparison, Arithmetic, Logical\nD. Comparison, Logical, Arithmetic", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 362, "Question": "Evaluate the following as true or false: !(1&&0||!1)\nA. true\nB. false\nC. Invalid expression", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 363, "Question": "The ___ function after accepting a character and wait for the Enter key to be pressed.\nA. putch()\nB. putchar()\nC. getch()\nD. getchar()", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 364, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat a=14.5;\ndouble b=12.45;\nprintf(\"%.6f%.6f\",a,b);\nA. 14.50000 12.45000\nB. 14.5 12.45\nC. 14.500000 12.450000\nD. 14.5 12.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 365, "Question": "___ is the comparison operation and ___ is the logical operation.\nA. Modulo, Less than\nB. Less than, NOT\nC. NOT, Less than\nD. Divide, OR", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 366, "Question": "What does the following declaration mean ( If there are more than one correct answer, choose the best one)\nInt*ptr[10];\nA. Array of 10 integer pointers\nB. Pointers to the array of 10 elements\nC. Array of 10 pointers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 367, "Question": "What number is equivalent to -4e3 ?\nA. -4000\nB.-400\nC. .004\nD. -40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 368, "Question": "If a program contains just one function, then it must be___.\nA. clrscr()\nB. getch()\nC. printf()\nD. main()\nE. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 369, "Question": "Which value can not be assigned to an unsigned-short type?\nA. 59876\nB. 0\nC. 10000\nD. -3\nE. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 370, "Question": "If the program completes executing successfully, what value should the function main returned?\nA. void\nB. 0\nC. nothing\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 371, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 1.\np1=&b;\np2=&c;\nprintf(\"\\np1=%u, value=%d\",p1+1,*(p1+1)\nprintf(\"\\np2=%u, value=%d\",p2-1,*(p2-1);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "t\u1ef1 t\u00ednh "}, {"ID": 372, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 2\np1=&b;\np2=&c;\nprintf(\"\\np1=%u, value=%d\",p1,*p1);\nprintf(\"\\np2=%u, value=%d\",p2,*p2)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "t\u1ef1 t\u00ednh "}, {"ID": 373, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 2\np1=&b;\np2=&c;\nprintf(\"\\np1=%u, value=%d\",p1-1,*(p1-1);\nprintf(\"\\np2=%u, value=%d\",p2+2,*(p2+2);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "t\u1ef1 t\u00ednh "}, {"ID": 374, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 2\np1=&b;\np2=&c;\np1--;\np2++;\nprintf(\"\\np1=%u, value=%d\",p1,*p1);\nprintf(\"\\np2=%u, value=%d\",p2,*p2);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "t\u1ef1 t\u00ednh "}, {"ID": 375, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 2\np1=&b;\np2=&c;\n*p1=++d;\n*p2=*p1+a;\np2--;\nprintf(\"a=%d,b=%d,c=%d,d=%d:,a,b,c,d);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "t\u1ef1 t\u00ednh "}, {"ID": 376, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 3:\nvoid getvalue(int#*a,int b,int*c,int d){\n *a+=b;\n a=&d;\n *c=*a+b;\n d=b+c;\nb=*a+d;\n}\nmain()\n{\nint x=1,y=2,z=3,t=4;\ngetvalue(&x,y,&z,t);\nprintf(\"x=%d;y=%d,z=%d,t=%d\\n\",x,y,z,t);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "t\u1ef1 t\u00ednh "}, {"ID": 377, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 3:\nvoid getvalue(int#*a,int *b,int*c,int* d){\n *a+=*b;\n *c=*a+*b;\n *d=*b+*c;\n*b=*a+*d;\n\n}\nmain()\n{\nint x=28,y=7,z=20,t=17;\ngetvalue(&x,&y,&z,&t);\nprintf(\"x=%d;y=%d,z=%d,t=%d\\n\",x,y,z,t);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "x=28\ny=7\nz=20\nt=17 "}, {"ID": 378, "Question": "For 4 variables a,b,c,d, *p1, *p2 type integer have addresses and values as the\nfollowing table :\nVariable name address value\na 2358860 2\nb 2358856 3\nc 2358852 4\nd 2358848 5\np1 2358840\nP2 2358832\n\nWhat is the result of the following program ?\nProgram 2\np1=&a;\np2=&b;\n*p1=*(p2+1)+d;;\n*p2=*p1+a;\nc=*p1+*(p2-2);\nd=*(p1-1)+c;\nprintf(\"a=%d,b=%d,c=%d,d=%d:,a,b,c,d);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "t\u1ef1 t\u00ednh "}, {"ID": 379, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed??\nint i=1;\nwhile (i<=10)\n if( i%2==1)\n printf(\"%d\",i++);\n else\n printf(\"%d\",i--);\nA. 1\nB.1 2 1 2 1 2...(infinite loop)\nC. compiler error\nD.1 2 4 6 8 10\nE. 1 3 5 7 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 380, "Question": "Which is the correct order when listing the following languages from the lowest to the highest level??\nA. C, Assembly,C++,MATLAB\nB. Assembly,C,C++,MATLAB\nC. Assembly,MATLAB,C,C++\nD. C,C++,Assembly,MATLAB", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 381, "Question": "If an array has n elements, the largest subscrip is ________ .\nA. n-2\nB. n-1\nC. n\nD. n+1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 382, "Question": "What is the maximum value of an unsigned char??\nA. 128\nB. 127\nC.255\nD.256", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 383, "Question": "What is the correct definition of an array???\nA. An array is the collection of different data types located next to each other in the memory\nB. An array is a collection of the same data type spread throughout the memory\nC. An array is the collection of the same data types located next to each other in the memory\nD. An array is a collection of the different data type spread throughout the memory", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 384, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is excuted??\nvoid foo(int x, int*y){\n x=x*x;\n*y=*y**y;\n }\nint main(){\n int x=-5,y=-2;\n foo(x,y);\n printf(\"%d %d\",x,y);\n return 0;\n }\nA.-5 4\nB. -5 -4\nC. -5 -2\nD. 25 4\nE. 5 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 385, "Question": "give the declaration:\nint ref[]={1,2,4};\nwhat is the value of*(ref+1)?\nA.1\nB.2\nC.4\nD. None of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B.2 "}, {"ID": 386, "Question": "what is the output of the following code?\nint sum(int n)l\nint main(){\n int s,i;\n s=0;\n for(i=1;i<=n;i++) {s+=i;}\n return (s);\n}\nA.13\nB.14\nC.15\nD.16", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 387, "Question": "Which of the following statements are true with regards to the || operator?\nA.if one of the conditional expressions return false, the outcome is false\nB.this operator is used to combine two logical expression which evaluate to true if both individual expressions are true.\nC. only if both the expressions evaluate to false, the outcome is false\nD.it is a relational operator", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 388, "Question": "Suppose you have these statements in your program:\nFILE *fp1,*fp2;\nchar ch;\nfp1=fopen(\"output\",\"r\");\nfp2=fopen(\"input\",\"w\");\nAssume that both files are opened successfully. Which of the following function calls is INCORRECT\nA.fputc(ch,fp2);\nB.fprintf(fp2,\"%c\".ch);\nC.ch=fgetc(fp1);\nD.fclose();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 389, "Question": "what is the value of a when the following code is executed?\nint a=10;\nint *pa=a;\n(*pa)++;\na=a+10;\nA.10\nB.11\nC.21\nD.20", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C.21 "}, {"ID": 390, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0;\nfor(;i;)\n printf(\"This is a loop\");\nif(i>0)\n printf(\"in C program\");\nA. This is a loop in C program\nB. Nothing( no output)\nC.Garbage value\nD. in C program\nE. This is a loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 391, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint count=10,*temp,sum=0;\ntemp=count;\n*temp=20;\ntemp=sum;\n*temp=count;\nprintf(\"%d%d%d\",count,*temp,sum);\nA.20 20 20\nB.10 10 10\nC.10 20 20\nD.20 20 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 392, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nmain(){\nint i=5;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i=++i==6);\n}\nA.5\nB.0\nC.7\nD.1\nE.6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 393, "Question": "Which library that the following fuctions belong to??\ndouble round(double);\ndouble ceil(double);\ndouble sqrt(double);\ndouble pow(double base, double exponent);\nA.stdio.h\nB.math.h\nC.time.h\nD.stdlib.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 394, "Question": "What is the final value of x when the sample code below is executed?\nint x-0;\nfor(inti=1;i<5;i++)\n for(int j=0;j<5;j++)\n x++;\nA.15\nB.5\nC.10\nD.20", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 395, "Question": "What will be the output of the following program??\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\nint x[4]={2,1,4,8};\nint rs=0;\nfor (int i=0;i<4;i++)\n{\n rs+=x[i];\n}\n printf(\"%d\",rs);\nreturn 0;\n}\nA.14\nB.15\nC.16\nD.17", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 396, "Question": "char name[31];\nscanf(\"%[a-zA-Z0-9]\",name);\nwhich is the correct statement about the above code?\nA.Accepts only case letters(in the range between 'a' and 'z') upper case letters( in the range between 'A' and 'Z') and digits(in the range '0' to '9')\nB.Accepts any characters excepts lower case letters(in the range between 'a' and 'z') upper case letters( in the range between 'A' and 'Z') and digits(in the range '0' to '9')\nC.Accepts only space, lower case letters(in the range between 'a' and 'z') upper case letters( in the range between 'A' and 'Z') and digits(in the range '0' to '9')", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 397, "Question": "what is the output of this program?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(void)\n{\nchar note[]=\"Meet me at 7pm''\nchar *ptr;\nptr=note;\nnote[7]='\\0';\nputs(++ptr);\nreturn 0;\n}\nA. eet me a\nB.Meet me\nC.Meet m\nD. eet me", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 398, "Question": "which is the proper declaration of a string mamed str which str which stores the value\"Melodies''\nA. char str[]=Melodes;\nB.char str[7]=\"Melodes\";\nC.char str[9]='Melodes';\nD.char str[]=\"Melodes\";", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 399, "Question": "what will be the output of the following program?\n#include<stdio.h>\n#include<string>\n#include<ctype.h>\nvoid main()\n{\n char str[]=\"abcd\";\n int len=strlen(str);\n for (int i=0;i<len;i++)\n{\n if (i%2==0)\n str[i]=toupper(str[i]);\n }\n printf(\"%s\",str);\nreturn 0;\n }\nA. aBcD\nB.abcd\nC.ABCD\nD.AbCd", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 400, "Question": "The operation between float and int would give the result as\nA. float\nB.int\nC.unsigned int\nD.double\nE.none of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 401, "Question": "which one of the followings is the parameter passed to getchar()?\nA. It takes no parameters\nB.Characters to be displayed\nC.String variable\nD.None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 402, "Question": "why the following code is wrong?\n1.int main(){\n2. int a; float b,c;\n3. Printf(\"Hello FPT University!\");\n4.a=0;\n5.b=c=0;\n6. return 0;\n7.}\nA. Wrong at line 2: Can not write two code statements in one line.\nB. Wrong at line 5: you can not write two assignments at the same time.\nC. Wrong at line 3: C is case sensitive language. So printf is different from Printf which is not the C keyword.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 403, "Question": "Which of the following statements is INCORRECT?\nA. if a file opened for writing already exists, its content will be overwritten\nB. if a file is opened for reading, it is required that the file must exist\nC.None of the others\nD. if a file is opened for writing,it is required that the file must exist", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 404, "Question": "Which of the following fuctions can be used to enter an integer in C program?\nA. getchar\nB.gets\nC.scanf\nD.None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 405, "Question": "In a C orogram, we cannot write more than one function.\n(T/F)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "F "}, {"ID": 406, "Question": "What will be printed when the sample code below is executed?\nint x=0;\nfor(;;){\nif (x++==4)\nbreak;\ncontinue;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",x);\nA.5\nB.6\nC.4\nD.1\nE.0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 407, "Question": "Which of the following is a complete function?\nA.void funct(x){printf(\"Hello\";}\nB.int funct(int x){return x=x+1;}\nC.void funct(int){printf(\"Hello\");\nD. int funct();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 408, "Question": "What is the value of x after executing the code:\nint x;\nfor (x=0;x<10;x++){}\nA.10\nB.1\nC.9\nD.0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 409, "Question": "what is the equivalence of 0124(base 8) in Hex(base 16)?\nA.75\nB.55\nC.65\nD.45", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 410, "Question": "Decimal number 44 is ... in hexadecimal\nA.0x1C\nB.0x2B\nC.0x1B\nD.0x2C", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 411, "Question": "given the code below:\nint a=2;\nprintf(\"%d\",++a,a+5);\nwhat is printed?\nA.3\nB.error\nC.2\nD.Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 412, "Question": "which is NOT a valid function for reading from a file?\nA.fgetchar()\nB.fscanf()\nC.fgetc()\nD.fgets()", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 413, "Question": "How many time the statement is executed?\nfor(int i=1;i<=5;i++)\n for (int j=1;j<=10;j++)\nstatement;\nA.50\nB.15\nC5\nD.10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 414, "Question": "Function strlen() is for finding the number of characters in a string\n(T/F)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "T "}, {"ID": 415, "Question": "Which function is not used to read from a file?\nA.fgetc\nB.fscanf\nC.fprintf\nD.fgets", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 416, "Question": "what does the gets() function do?\nA.This function fetches a single character from the standard input file.\nB.This function fetches a string from the standard input stdin(keyboard) and places it into a string which the programmer must provide.\nC. This function fetches an argument from the standard input file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 417, "Question": "What will be printed when the sample code below is executed?\nint x=1000;\nwhile (x++<1003)\nprintf(\"%d\",x);\n printf(\"%d\\n\",x);\nA.1000 1001 1002 1003\nB.1000 1001 1002\nC.1001 1002 1003 1004\nD. 1001 1002 1003", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 418, "Question": "C99 standard guarantees uniqueness of ____ characters for internal names.\na) 31\nb) 63\nc) 12\nd) 14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 419, "Question": "C99 standard guarantess uniqueness of _____ characters for external names.\na) 31\nb) 6\nc) 12\nd) 14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 420, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?\na) int __a3;\nb) int __3a;\nc) int __A3;\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 421, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?\na) int _a3;\nb) int a_3;\nc) int 3_a;\nd) int _3a", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 422, "Question": "Variable names beginning with underscore is not encouraged. Why?\na) It is not standardized\nb) To avoid conflicts since assemblers and loaders use such names\nc) To avoid conflicts since library routines use such names\nd) To avoid conflicts with environment variables of an operating system", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 423, "Question": "All keywords in C are in\na) LowerCase letters\nb) UpperCase letters\nc) CamelCase letters\nd) None", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 424, "Question": "Variable name resolving (number of significant characters for uniqueness of variable) depends on\na) Compiler and linker implementations\nb) Assemblers and loaders implementations\nc) C language\nd) None", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 425, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid C variable name?\na) int number;\nb) float rate;\nc) int variable_count;\nd) int $main;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 426, "Question": "Which of the following is true for variable names in C?\na) They can contain alphanumeric characters as well as special characters\nb) It is not an error to declare a variable to be one of the keywords(like goto, static)\nc) Variable names cannot start with a digit\nd) Variable can be of any length", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 427, "Question": "Which is valid C expression?\na) int my_num = 100,000;\nb) int my_num = 100000;\nc) int my num = 1000;\nd) int $my_num = 10000;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 428, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"Hello World! %d \\n\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) Hello World! x;\nb) Hello World! followed by a junk value\nc) Compile time error\nd) Hello World!", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 429, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 10000;\n int y = 34;\n printf(\"Hello World! %d\\n\", y);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Hello World! 34\nc) Hello World! 1000\nd) Hello World! followed by a junk value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 430, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?\na) float PI = 3.14;\nb) double PI = 3.14;\nc) int PI = 3.14;\nd) #define PI 3.14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 431, "Question": "What will happen if the below program is executed?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int main = 3;\n printf(\"%d\", main);\n return 0;\n }\na) It will cause a compile-time error\nb) It will cause a run-time error\nc) It will run without any error and prints 3\nd) It will experience infinite looping", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 432, "Question": "What is the problem in following variable declaration?\nfloat 3Bedroom-Hall-Kitchen?;\na) The variable name begins with an integer\nb) The special character '-'\nc) The special character '?'\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 433, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int ThisIsVariableName = 12;\n int ThisIsVariablename = 14;\n printf(\"%d\", ThisIsVariablename);\n return 0;\n }\na) The program will print 12\nb) The program will print 14\nc) The program will have a runtime error\nd) The program will cause a compile-time error due to redeclaration", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 434, "Question": "Which of the following cannot be a variable name in C?\na) volatile\nb) true\nc) friend\nd) export", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 435, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a[5] = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5};\n int i;\n for (i = 0; i < 5; i++)\n if ((char)a[i] == '5')\n printf(\"%d\\n\", a[i]);\n else\n printf(\"FAIL\\n\");\n }\na) The compiler will flag an error\nb) Program will compile and print the output 5\nc) Program will compile and print the ASCII value of 5\nd) Program will compile and print FAIL for 5 times", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 436, "Question": "The format identifier '%i' is also used for _____ data type?\na) char\nb) int\nc) float\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 437, "Question": "Which data type is most suitable for storing a number 65000 in a 32-bit system?\na) signed short\nb) unsigned short\nc) long\nd) int", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 438, "Question": "Which of the following is a User-defined data type?\na) typedef int Boolean;\nb) typedef enum {Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri} Workdays;\nc) struct {char name[10], int age};\nd) all of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 439, "Question": "What is the size of an int data type?\na) 4 Bytes\nb) 8 Bytes\nc) Depends on the system/compiler\nd) Cannot be determined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 440, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n signed char chr;\n chr = 128;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", chr);\n return 0;\n }\na) 128\nb) -128\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 441, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n char c;\n int i = 0;\n FILE *file;\n file = fopen(\"test.txt\", \"w+\");\n fprintf(file, \"%c\", 'a');\n fprintf(file, \"%c\", -1);\n fprintf(file, \"%c\", 'b');\n fclose(file);\n file = fopen(\"test.txt\", \"r\");\n while ((c = fgetc(file)) != -1)\n printf(\"%c\", c);\n return 0;\n }\na) a\nb) Infinite loop\nc) Depends on what fgetc returns\nd) Depends on the compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 442, "Question": "What is short int in C programming?\na) Basic datatype of C\nb) Qualifier\nc) short is the qualifier and int is the basic datatype\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 443, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n float f1 = 0.1;\n if (f1 == 0.1)\n printf(\"equal\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"not equal\\n\");\n }\na) equal\nb) not equal\nc) Output depends on compiler\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 444, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n float f1 = 0.1;\n if (f1 == 0.1f)\n printf(\"equal\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"not equal\\n\");\n }\na) equal\nb) not equal\nc) Output depends on compiler\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 445, "Question": "What is the output of this C code (on a 32-bit machine)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 10000;\n double y = 56;\n int *p = &x;\n double *q = &y;\n printf(\"p and q are %d and %d\", sizeof(p), sizeof(q));\n return 0;\n }\na) p and q are 4 and 4\nb) p and q are 4 and 8\nc) Compiler error\nd) p and q are 2 and 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 446, "Question": "Which is correct with respect to size of the datatypes?\na) char > int > float\nb) int > char > float\nc) char < int < double\nd) double > char > int", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 447, "Question": "What is the output of the following C code(on a 64 bit machine)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n union Sti\n {\n int nu;\n char m;\n };\n int main()\n {\n union Sti s;\n printf(\"%d\", sizeof(s));\n return 0;\n }\na) 8\nb) 5\nc) 9\nd) 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 448, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n float x = 'a';\n printf(\"%f\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) a\nb) run time error\nc) a.0000000\nd) 97.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 449, "Question": "Which of the datatypes have size that is variable?\na) int\nb) struct\nc) float\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 450, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n enum {ORANGE = 5, MANGO, BANANA = 4, PEACH};\n printf(\"PEACH = %d\\n\", PEACH);\n }\na) PEACH = 3\nb) PEACH = 4\nc) PEACH = 5\nd) PEACH = 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 451, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"C programming %s\", \"Class by\\n%s Sanfoundry\", \"WOW\");\n }\na) C programming Class by\n WOW Sanfoundry\nb) C programming Class by\\n%s Sanfoundry\nc) C programming Class by\n %s Sanfoundry\nd) Compilation error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 452, "Question": "For the following code snippet:\n char *str = \"Sanfoundry.com\\0\" \"training classes\";\n The character pointer str holds reference to string:\na) Sanfoundry.com\nb) Sanfoundry.com\\0training classes\nc) Sanfoundry.comtraining classes\nd) Invalid declaration", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 453, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n #define a 10\n int main()\n {\n const int a = 5;\n printf(\"a = %d\\n\", a);\n }\na) a = 5\nb) a = 10\nc) Compilation error\nd) Runtime error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 454, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int var = 010;\n printf(\"%d\", var);\n }\na) 2\nb) 8\nc) 9\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 455, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n enum birds {SPARROW, PEACOCK, PARROT};\n enum animals {TIGER = 8, LION, RABBIT, ZEBRA};\n int main()\n {\n enum birds m = TIGER;\n int k;\n k = m;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) Compile time error\nc) 1\nd) 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 456, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n #define MAX 2\n enum bird {SPARROW = MAX + 1, PARROT = SPARROW + MAX};\n int main()\n {\n enum bird b = PARROT;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", b);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compilation error\nb) 5\nc) Undefined value\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 457, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n #include <string.h>\n int main()\n {\n char *str = \"x\";\n char c = 'x';\n char ary[1];\n ary[0] = c;\n printf(\"%d %d\", strlen(str), strlen(ary));\n return 0;\n }\na) 1 1\nb) 2 1\nc) 2 2\nd) 1 (undefined value)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 458, "Question": "enum types are processed by\na) Compiler\nb) Preprocessor\nc) Linker\nd) Assembler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 459, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"sanfoundry\\rclass\\n\");\n return 0;\n }\na) sanfoundryclass\nb) sanfoundry\n class\nc) classundry\nd) sanfoundry", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 460, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"sanfoundry\\r\\nclass\\n\");\n return 0;\n }\na) sanfoundryclass\nb) sanfoundry\n class\nc) classundry\nd) sanfoundry", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 461, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n const int p;\n p = 4;\n printf(\"p is %d\", p);\n return 0;\n }\na) p is 4\nb) Compile time error\nc) Run time error\nd) p is followed by a garbage value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 462, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 4;\n int *const p = &k;\n int r = 3;\n p = &r;\n printf(\"%d\", p);\n }\na) Address of k\nb) Address of r\nc) Compile time error\nd) Adress of k + address of r", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 463, "Question": "Which is false?\na) Constant variables need not be defined as they are declared and can be defined later\nb) Global constant variables are initialised to zero\nc) const keyword is used to define constant values\nd) You cannot reassign a value to a constant variable", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 464, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int const k = 5;\n k++;\n printf(\"k is %d\", k);\n }\na) k is 6\nb) Error due to const succeeding int\nc) Error, because a constant variable can be changed only twice\nd) Error, because a constant variable cannot be changed", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 465, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int const print()\n {\n printf(\"Sanfoundry.com\");\n return 0;\n }\n void main()\n {\n print();\n }\na) Error because function name cannot be preceded by const\nb) Sanfoundry.com\nc) Sanfoundry.com is printed infinite times\nd) Blank screen, no output", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 466, "Question": "Which of the following declaration is illegal?\na) char *str = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";\nb) char str[] = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";\nc) char str[20] = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";\nd) char[] str = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 467, "Question": "Which keyword is used to prevent any changes in the variable within a C program?\na) immutable\nb) mutable\nc) const\nd) volatile", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 468, "Question": "Which of the following is not a pointer declaration?\na) char a[10];\nb) char a[] = {'1', '2', '3', '4'};\nc) char *str;\nd) char a;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 469, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 4;\n float k = 4;\n printf(\"%d\", k)\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 4\nc) 4.0000000\nd) 4.4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 470, "Question": "Which is false ?\na) A variable defined once can be defined again with different scope\nb) A single variable cannot be defined with two different types in the same scope\nc) A variable must be declared and defined at the same time\nd) A variable refers to a location in memory", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 471, "Question": "A variable declared in a function can be used in main\na) True\nb) False\nc) True if it is declared static\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 472, "Question": "The name of the variable used in one function cannot be used in another function\na) True\nb) False\nc) May be\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 473, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void foo(const int *);\n int main()\n {\n const int i = 10;\n printf(\"%d \", i);\n foo(&i);\n printf(\"%d\", i);\n \n }\n void foo(const int *i)\n {\n *i = 20;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 10 20\nc) Undefined value\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 474, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n const int i = 10;\n int *ptr = &i;\n *ptr = 20;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Compile time warning and printf displays 20\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 475, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n j = 10;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", j++);\n return 0;\n }\na) 10\nb) 11\nc) Compile time error\nd) 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 476, "Question": "Does this compile without error?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n for (int k = 0; k < 10; k++);\n return 0;\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the C standard implemented by compilers\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 477, "Question": "Does this compile without error?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int k;\n {\n int k;\n for (k = 0; k < 10; k++);\n }\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the C standard implemented by compilers", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 478, "Question": "Which of the following declaration is not supported by C?\na) String str;\nb) char *str;\nc) float str = 3e2;\nd) Both (a) and (c)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 479, "Question": "#include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n char *var = \"Advanced Training in C by Sanfoundry.com\";\n }\nWhich of the following format identifier can never be used for the variable var?\na) %f\nb) %d\nc) %c\nd) %s", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 480, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = -3;\n int k = i % 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) -1\nc) 1\nd) Implementation defined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 481, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 3;\n int l = i / -2;\n int k = i % -2;\n printf(\"%d %d\\n\", l, k);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) -1 1\nc) 1 -1\nd) Implementation defined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 482, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 5;\n i = i / 3;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return 0;\n }\na) Implementation defined\nb) 1\nc) 3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 483, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = -5;\n i = i / 3;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return 0;\n }\na) Implementation defined\nb) -1\nc) -3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 484, "Question": "What is the value of x in this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 5 * 9 / 3 + 9;\n }\na) 3.75\nb) Depends on compiler\nc) 24\nd) 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 485, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 5.3 % 2;\n printf(\"Value of x is %d\", x);\n }\na) Value of x is 2.3\nb) Value of x is 1\nc) Value of x is 0.3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 486, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int y = 3;\n int x = 5 % 2 * 3 / 2;\n printf(\"Value of x is %d\", x);\n }\na) Value of x is 1\nb) Value of x is 2\nc) Value of x is 3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 487, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 3;\n int b = ++a + a++ + --a;\n printf(\"Value of b is %d\", b);\n }\na) Value of x is 12\nb) Value of x is 13\nc) Value of x is 10\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 488, "Question": "The precedence of arithmetic operators is (from highest to lowest)\na) %, *, /, +, -\nb) %, +, /, *, -\nc) +, -, %, *, /\nd) %, +, -, *, /", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 489, "Question": "Which of the following is not an arithmetic operation?\na) a *= 10;\nb) a /= 10;\nc) a != 10;\nd) a %= 10;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 490, "Question": "Which of the following data type will throw an error on modulus operation(%)?\na) char\nb) short\nc) int\nd) float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 491, "Question": "Which among the following are the fundamental arithmetic operators, ie, performing the desired operation can be done using that operator only?\na) +, -\nb) +, -, %\nc) +, -, *, /\nd) +, -, *, /, %", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 492, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10;\n double b = 5.6;\n int c;\n c = a + b;\n printf(\"%d\", c);\n }\na) 15\nb) 16\nc) 15.6\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 493, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 5, c = 5;\n int d;\n d = a == (b + c);\n printf(\"%d\", d);\n }\na) Syntax error\nb) 1\nc) 10\nd) 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 494, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0, z = 5;\n int a = x && y || z++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) 6\nb) 5\nc) 0\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 495, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0, z = 5;\n int a = x && y && z++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) 6\nb) 5\nc) 0\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 496, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0, z = 3;\n x > y ? printf(\"%d\", z) : return z;\n }\na) 3\nb) 1\nc) Compile time error\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 497, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 1, z = 3;\n int y = x << 3;\n printf(\" %d\\n\", y);\n }\na) -2147483648\nb) -1\nc) Run time error\nd) 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 498, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 0, y = 2, z = 3;\n int a = x & y | z;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 3\nb) 0\nc) 2\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 499, "Question": "What is the final value of j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0, j = 0;\n if (i && (j = i + 10))\n //do something\n ;\n }\na) 0\nb) 10\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on language standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 500, "Question": "What is the final value of j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 10, j = 0;\n if (i || (j = i + 10))\n //do something\n ;\n }\na) 0\nb) 20\nc) Compile time error\nd) Depends on language standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 501, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 1;\n if (i++ && (i == 1))\n printf(\"Yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"No\\n\");\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 502, "Question": "Are logical operators sequence points?\na) True\nb) False\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 503, "Question": "Does logical operators in C language are evaluated with short circuit?\na) True\nb) False\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 504, "Question": "Result of a logical or relational expression in C is\na) True or False\nb) 0 or 1\nc) 0 if expression is false and any positive number if expression is true\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 505, "Question": "What will be the value of d in the following program?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 5, c = 5;\n int d;\n d = b + c == a;\n printf(\"%d\", d);\n }\na) Syntax error\nb) 1\nc) 5\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 506, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 5, c = 3;\n b != !a;\n c = !!a;\n printf(\"%d\\t%d\", b, c);\n }\na) 5 1\nb) 0 3\nc) 5 3\nd) 1 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 507, "Question": "Which among the following is NOT a logical or relational operator?\na) !=\nb) ==\nc) ||\nd) =", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 508, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10;\n if (a == a--)\n printf(\"TRUE 1\\t\");\n a = 10;\n if (a == --a)\n printf(\"TRUE 2\\t\");\n }\na) TRUE 1\nb) TRUE 2\nc) TRUE 1 TRUE 2\nd) Compiler Dependent", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 509, "Question": "Relational operators cannot be used on:\na) structure\nb) long\nc) strings\nd) float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 510, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n float x = 0.1;\n if (x == 0.1)\n printf(\"Sanfoundry\");\n else\n printf(\"Advanced C Classes\");\n }\na) Advanced C Classes\nb) Sanfoundry\nc) Run time error\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 511, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n float x = 0.1;\n printf(\"%d, \", x);\n printf(\"%f\", x);\n }\na) 0.100000, junk value\nb) Junk value, 0.100000\nc) 0, 0.100000\nd) 0, 0.999999", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 512, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n(7 and 8 are entered)\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n float x;\n int y;\n printf(\"enter two numbers \\n\", x);\n scanf(\"%f %f\", &x, &y);\n printf(\"%f, %d\", x, y);\n }\na) 7.000000, 7\nb) Run time error\nc) 7.000000, junk\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 513, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double x = 123828749.66;\n int y = x;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n printf(\"%lf\\n\", y);\n }\na) 0, 0.0\nb) 123828749, 123828749.66\nc) 12382874, 12382874.0\nd) 123828749, 0.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 514, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 97;\n char y = x;\n printf(\"%c\\n\", y);\n }\na) a\nb) b\nc) 97\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 515, "Question": "When double is converted to float, the value is?\na) Truncated\nb) Rounded\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 516, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n unsigned int i = 23;\n signed char c = -23;\n if (i > c)\n printf(\"Yes\\n\");\n else if (i < c)\n printf(\"No\\n\");\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the operating system", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 517, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 23;\n char c = -23;\n if (i < c)\n printf(\"Yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"No\\n\");\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 518, "Question": "function tolower(c) defined in library works for\na) Ascii character set\nb) Unicode character set\nc) Ascii and utf-8 but not EBSIDIC character set\nd) Any character set", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 519, "Question": "What is the output of the below code considering size of short int is 2, char is 1 and int is 4 bytes?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n short int i = 20;\n char c = 97;\n printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", sizeof(i), sizeof(c), sizeof(c + i));\n return 0;\n }\na) 2, 1, 2\nb) 2, 1, 1\nc) 2, 1, 4\nd) 2, 2, 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 520, "Question": "Which type conversion is NOT accepted?\na) From char to int\nb) From float to char pointer\nc) From negative int to char\nd) From double to char", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 521, "Question": "What will be the data type of the result of the following operation?\n(float)a * (int)b / (long)c * (double)d\na) int\nb) long\nc) float\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 522, "Question": "Which of the following type-casting have chances for wrap around?\na) From int to float\nb) From int to char\nc) From char to short\nd) From char to int", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 523, "Question": "Which of the following typecasting is accepted by C?\na) Widening conversions\nb) Narrowing conversions\nc) Both\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 524, "Question": "When do you need to use type-conversions?\na) The value to be stored is beyond the max limit\nb) The value to be stored is in a form not supported by that data type\nc) To reduce the memory in use, relevant to the value\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 525, "Question": "What is the difference between the following 2 codes?\n\n #include <stdio.h> //Program 1\n int main()\n {\n int d, a = 1, b = 2;\n d = a++ + ++b;\n printf(\"%d %d %d\", d, a, b);\n }\n #include <stdio.h> //Program 2\n int main()\n {\n int d, a = 1, b = 2;\n d = a++ +++b;\n printf(\"%d %d %d\", d, a, b);\n }\na) No difference as space doesn't make any difference, values of a, b, d are same in both the case\nb) Space does make a difference, values of a, b, d are different\nc) Program 1 has syntax error, program 2 is not\nd) Program 2 has syntax error, program 1 is not", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 526, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 1, c;\n c = a++ + b;\n printf(\"%d, %d\", a, b);\n }\na) a = 1, b = 1\nb) a = 2, b = 1\nc) a = 1, b = 2\nd) a = 2, b = 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 527, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 1, d = 1;\n printf(\"%d, %d, %d\", ++a + ++a+a++, a++ + ++b, ++d + d++ + a++);\n }\na) 15, 4, 5\nb) 9, 6, 9\nc) 9, 3, 5\nd) Undefined (Compiler Dependent)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 528, "Question": "For which of the following, \"PI++;\" code will fail?\na) #define PI 3.14\nb) char *PI = \"A\";\nc) float PI = 3.14;\nd) None of the Mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 529, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 10;\n if (a = 5)\n b--;\n printf(\"%d, %d\", a, b--);\n }\na) a = 10, b = 9\nb) a = 10, b = 8\nc) a = 5, b = 9\nd) a = 5, b = 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 530, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n int j = i++ + i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", j);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 531, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 2;\n int j = ++i + i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", j);\n }\na) 6\nb) 5\nc) 4\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 532, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 2;\n int i = i++ + i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n }\na) = operator is not a sequence point\nb) ++ operator may return value with or without side effects\nc) it can be evaluated as (i++)+i or i+(++i)\nd) Both a and b", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 533, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n int x = i++, y = ++i;\n printf(\"%d % d\\n\", x, y);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0, 2\nb) 0, 1\nc) 1, 2\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 534, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 10;\n int *p = &i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", *p++);\n }\na) 10\nb) 11\nc) Garbage value\nd) Address of i", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 535, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 97;\n int y = sizeof(x++);\n printf(\"X is %d\", x);\n }\na) X is 97\nb) X is 98\nc) X is 99\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 536, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4, y, z;\n y = --x;\n z = x--;\n printf(\"%d%d%d\", x, y, z);\n }\na) 3 2 3\nb) 2 3 3\nc) 3 2 2\nd) 2 3 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 537, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4;\n int *p = &x;\n int *k = p++;\n int r = p - k;\n printf(\"%d\", r);\n }\na) 4\nb) 8\nc) 1\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 538, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5, b = -7, c = 0, d;\n d = ++a && ++b || ++c;\n printf(\"\\n%d%d%d%d\", a, b, c, d);\n }\na) 6 -6 0 0\nb) 6 -5 0 1\nc) -6 -6 0 1\nd) 6 -6 0 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 539, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = -5;\n int k = (a++, ++a);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n }\na) -4\nb) -5\nc) 4\nd) -3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 540, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int c = 2 ^ 3;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", c);\n }\na) 1\nb) 8\nc) 9\nd) 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 541, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n unsigned int a = 10;\n a = ~a;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\n }\na) -9\nb) -10\nc) -11\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 542, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n if (7 & 8)\n printf(\"Honesty\");\n if ((~7 & 0x000f) == 8)\n printf(\"is the best policy\\n\");\n }\na) Honesty is the best policy\nb) Honesty\nc) is the best policy\nd) No output", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 543, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 2;\n if (a >> 1)\n printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) No Output.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 544, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i, n, a = 4;\n scanf(\"%d\", &n);\n for (i = 0; i < n; i++)\n a = a * 2;\n }\na) Logical Shift left\nb) No output\nc) Arithmetic Shift right\nd) bitwise exclusive OR", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 545, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 97;\n int y = sizeof(x++);\n printf(\"x is %d\", x);\n }\na) x is 97\nb) x is 98\nc) x is 99\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 546, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4, y, z;\n y = --x;\n z = x--;\n printf(\"%d%d%d\", x, y, z);\n }\na) 3 2 3\nb) 2 2 3\nc) 3 2 2\nd) 2 3 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 547, "Question": "Answer:d\n8. What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4;\n int *p = &x;\n int *k = p++;\n int r = p - k;\n printf(\"%d\", r);\n }\na) 4\nb) 8\nc) 1\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 548, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5, b = -7, c = 0, d;\n d = ++a && ++b || ++c;\n printf(\"\\n%d%d%d%d\", a, b, c, d);\n }\na) 6 -6 0 0\nb) 6 -5 0 1\nc) -6 -6 0 1\nd) 6 -6 0 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 549, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = -5;\n int k = (a++, ++a);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n }\na) -3\nb) -5\nc) 4\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 550, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2;\n x = x << 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) 4\nb) 1\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the endianness of the machine", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 551, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = -2;\n x = x >> 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) 1\nb) -1\nc) 2 ^ 31 - 1 considering int to be 4 bytes\nd) Either b or c", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 552, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n if (~0 == 1)\n printf(\"yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n }\na) yes\nb) no\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 553, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = -2;\n if (!0 == 1)\n printf(\"yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n }\na) yes\nb) no\nc) Run time error\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 554, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 0;\n if (1 |(y = 1))\n printf(\"y is %d\\n\", y);\n else\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n \n }\na) y is 1\nb) 1\nc) Run time error\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 555, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 1;\n if (y & (y = 2))\n printf(\"true %d\\n\", y);\n else\n printf(\"false %d\\n\", y);\n \n }\na) true 2\nb) false 2\nc) Either option a or option b\nd) true 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 556, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n if (x = 0)\n printf(\"Its zero\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"Its not zero\\n\");\n }\na) Its not zero\nb) Its zero\nc) Run time error\nd) None", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 557, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int x = 0 == 1 && k++;\n printf(\"%d%d\\n\", x, k);\n }\na) 0 9\nb) 0 8\nc) 1 8\nd) 1 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 558, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n char a = 'a';\n int x = (a % 10)++;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) 6\nb) Junk value\nc) Compile time error\nd) 7", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 559, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n 1 < 2 ? return 1: return 2;\n }\na) returns 1\nb) returns 2\nc) Varies\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 560, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n unsigned int x = -5;\n printf(\"%d\", x);\n }\na) Run time error\nb) Aries\nc) -5\nd) 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 561, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 1;\n x *= x + y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) 5\nb) 6\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 562, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 2;\n x /= x / y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) 2\nb) 1\nc) 0.5\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 563, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0;\n x &&= y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 1\nc) 0\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 564, "Question": "What is the type of the below assignment expression if x is of type float, y is of type int?\n y = x + y;\na) int\nb) float\nc) There is no type for an assignment expression\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 565, "Question": "What is the value of the below assignment expression\n (x = foo())!= 1 considering foo() returns 2\na) 2\nb) True\nc) 1\nd) 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 566, "Question": "Operation \"a = a * b + a\" can also be written as:\na) a *= b + 1;\nb) (c = a * b)!=(a = c + a);\nc) a = (b + 1)* a;\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 567, "Question": "for c = 2, value of c after c <<= 1; a) c = 1; b) c = 2; c) c = 3; d) c = 4; [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:d [/expand] 5. What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 2;\n a += b -= a;\n printf(\"%d %d\", a, b);\n }\na) 1 1\nb) 1 2\nc) 2 1\nd) 2 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 568, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 4, n, i, result = 0;\n scanf(\"%d\", n);\n for (i = 0;i < n; i++)\n result += a;\n }\na) Addition of a and n.\nb) Subtraction of a and n.\nc) Multiplication of a and n.\nd) Division of a and n.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 569, "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid assignment operator?\na) a %= 10;\nb) a /= 10;\nc) a |= 10;\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 570, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = (y++) ? y == 1 && x : 0;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 571, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1;\n int y = x == 1 ? getchar(): 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Whatever character getchar function returns\nc) Ascii value of character getchar function returns\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 572, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1;\n short int i = 2;\n float f = 3;\n if (sizeof((x == 2) ? f : i) == sizeof(float))\n printf(\"float\\n\");\n else if (sizeof((x == 2) ? f : i) == sizeof(short int))\n printf(\"short int\\n\");\n }\na) float\nb) short int\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 573, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 2;\n int b = 0;\n int y = (b == 0) ? a :(a > b) ? (b = 1): a;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 574, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 1, x = 0;\n int l = (y++, x++) ? y : x;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", l);\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 575, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n int z = k < m ? k++ : m++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) 7\nb) 8\nc) Run time error\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 576, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n int z = k < m ? k = m : m++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) Run time error\nb) 7\nc) 8\nd) Depends on compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 577, "Question": "The code snippet below produces\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n 1 < 2 ? return 1 : return 2;\n }\na) returns 1\nb) returns 2\nc) Varies\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 578, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n k < m ? k++ : m = k;\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\na) 7\nb) 8\nc) Compile time error\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 579, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n k < m ? k = k + 1 : m = m + 1;\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 9\nc) 8\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 580, "Question": "For initialization a = 2, c = 1 the value of a and c after this code will be\n c = (c) ? a = 0 : 2;\na) a = 0, c = 0;\nb) a = 2, c = 2;\nc) a = 2, c = 2;\nd) a = 1, c = 2;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 581, "Question": "What will be the data type of the expression \n(a < 50) ? var1 : var2;\n provided a = int, var1 = double, var2 = float \na) int \nb) float \nc) double \nd) Cannot be determined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 582, "Question": "Which expression has to be present in the following? \nexp1 ? exp2 : exp3; \na) exp1 \nb) exp2 \nc) exp3 \nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 583, "Question": "6. Value of c after the following expression \n(initializations a = 1, b = 2, c = 1):\n c += (-c) ? a : b; \na) Syntax Error \nb) c = 1 \nc) c = 2 \nd) c = 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 584, "Question": "7. Comment on the following expression? \nc = (n) ? a : b; \ncan be rewritten as \na) if (!n)c = b; else c = a; \nb) if (n <= 0)c = b; else c = a; \nc) if (n > 0)c = a;\n else c = b;\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 585, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n reverse(1);\n }\n void reverse(int i)\n {\n if (i > 5)\n exit(0);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return reverse(i++);\n }\na) 1 2 3 4 5\nb) 1 2 3 4\nc) Compile time error\nd) Stack overflow", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 586, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void reverse(int i);\n int main()\n {\n reverse(1);\n }\n void reverse(int i)\n {\n if (i > 5)\n return ;\n printf(\"%d \", i);\n return reverse((i++, i));\n }\na) 1 2 3 4 5\nb) Segmentation fault\nc) Compilation error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 587, "Question": "In expression i = g() + f(), first function called depends on\na) Compiler\nb) Associativiy of () operator\nc) Precedence of () and + operator\nd) Left to write of the expression", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 588, "Question": "What is the value of i and j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int x = 0;\n int main()\n {\n int i = (f() + g()) || g();\n int j = g() || (f() + g());\n }\n int f()\n {\n if (x == 0)\n return x + 1;\n else\n return x - 1;\n }\n int g()\n {\n return x++;\n }\na)i value is 1 and j value is 1\nb)i value is 0 and j value is 0\nc)i value is 1 and j value is undefined\nd)i and j value are undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 589, "Question": "What is the value of i and j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int x = 0;\n int main()\n {\n int i = (f() + g()) | g(); //bitwise or\n int j = g() | (f() + g()); //bitwise or\n }\n int f()\n {\n if (x == 0)\n return x + 1;\n else\n return x - 1;\n }\n int g()\n {\n return x++;\n }\na) i value is 1 and j value is 1\nb) i value is 0 and j value is 0\nc) i value is 1 and j value is undefined\nd) i and j value are undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 590, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = y && (y |= 10);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 1\nb) 0\nc) Undefined behaviour due to order of evaluation\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 591, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = (y++) ? 2 : y == 1 && x;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd)Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 592, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z;\n z = (y++, y);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compilation error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 593, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0, l;\n int z;\n z = y = 1, l = x && y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", l);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Undefined behaviour due to order of evaluation can be different\nd) Compilation error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 594, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 2;\n int z = y +(y = 10);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 12\nb) 20\nc) 4\nd) Either 12 or 20", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 595, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 2;\n float f = y + x /= x / y;\n printf(\"%d %f\\n\", x, f);\n return 0;\n }\na) 2 4.000000\nb) Compile time error\nc) 2 3.500000\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 596, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 2;\n if (x && y == 1)\n printf(\"true\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"false\\n\");\n }\na) true\nb) false\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 597, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 2;\n int z = x & y == 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 598, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3, y = 2;\n int z = x /= y %= 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 1\nb) Compile time error\nc) Floating point exception\nd) Segmentation fault\nView Answer", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 599, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3, y = 2;\n int z = x << 1 > 5;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 1\nb) 0\nc) 3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 600, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3; //, y = 2;\n const int *p = &x;\n *p++;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", *p);\n }\na) Increment of read-only location compile error\nb) 4\nc) Some garbage value\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 601, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 2;\n int z = x ^ y & 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) 0\nd) 1 or 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 602, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = x && y = 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Compile time error\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 603, "Question": "What is the output of the code given below\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0, y = 2;\n if (!x && y)\n printf(\"true\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"false\\n\");\n }\na) true\nb) false\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 604, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0, y = 2;\n int z = ~x & y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) -1\nb) 2\nc) 0\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 605, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5 * 3 + 2 - 4;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 13\nb) 14\nc) 12\nd) 1 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 606, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 2 + 4 + 3 * 5 / 3 - 5;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 7\nb) 6\nc) 10\nd) 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 607, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5 * 3 % 6 - 8 + 3;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 10\nb) 2\nc) -2\nd) -3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 608, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int b = 6;\n int c = 7;\n int a = ++b + c--;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) Run time error\nb) 15\nc) 13\nd) 14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 609, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main(\n {\n double b = 8;\n b++;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 9.000000\nb) 9\nc) 9.0\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 610, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 3 % 0 * 1 - 4 / 2;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) -2\nb) Floating point Exception\nc) 1\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 611, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 5 % 3 & 4 + 5 * 6;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 2\nb) 30\nc) 2.000000\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 612, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 3 && 5 & 4 % 3;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 3.000000\nb) 4.000000\nc) 5.000000\nd) 1.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 613, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 5 & 3 && 4 || 5 | 6;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 1.000000\nb) 0.000000\nc) 7.000000\nd) 2.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 614, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 0;\n double b = k++ + ++k + k--;\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\na) 6\nb) 1\nc) 5\nd) undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 615, "Question": "Which of the following operators has an associativity from Right to Left?\na) <= \nb) << \nc) == \nd) +=", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 616, "Question": "Which operators of the following have same precedence?\n P. \"!=\", Q. \"+=\", R. \"<<=\" \na) P and Q \nb) Q and R \nc) P and R \nd) P, Q and R", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 617, "Question": "Comment on the following statement?\n n = 1;\n printf(\"%d, %dn\", 3*n, n++);\na) Output will be 3, 2 \nb) Output will be 3, 1 \nc) Output will be 6, 1 \nd) Output is compiler dependent", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 618, "Question": "Which of the following option is the correct representation of the following code?\n e = a * b + c / d * f; \na) e = (a * (b +(c /(d * f)))); \nb) e = ((a * b) + (c / (d * f))); \nc) e = ((a * b) + ((c / d)* f)); \nd) Both (B) and (C);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 619, "Question": "What care must be taken during swapping 2 numbers?\n b = (b / a);\n a = a * b;\n b = a / b; \na) Data type should be either of short, int and long \nb) Data type should be either of float and double \nc) All data types are accepted except for (char *). \nd) This code doesn't swap 2 numbers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 620, "Question": "What should be the output of the following program:\n\n #include<stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 2, c = 3, d = 4, e;\n e = c + d = b * a;\n printf(\"%d, %d\\n\", e, d);\n }\na) 7, 4\nb) 7, 2\nc) 5, 2\nd) Syntax error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 621, "Question": "Which of the following is the correct order of evaluation for the given expression?\n a = w % x / y * z;\na) % / * =\nb) / * % =\nc) = % * /\nd) * % / =", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 622, "Question": "Which function in the following expression will be called first?\n a = func3(6) - func2(4, 5) / func1(1, 2, 3);\na) func1();\nb) func2();\nc) func3();\nd) Cannot be predicted.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 623, "Question": "Which of the following operator has the highest precedence in the following?\na) ()\nb) sizeof\nc) *\nd) +", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 624, "Question": "Which of the following is a ternary operator?\na) &&\nb) >>=\nc) ?:\nd) ->", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 625, "Question": "Which of the following are unary operators?\na) sizeof\nb) -\nc) ++\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 626, "Question": "Where in C the order of precedence of operators do not exist?\na) Within conditional statements, if, else\nb) Within while, do-while\nc) Within macro definition\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 627, "Question": "Associativity of an operator are:\na) Right to Left\nb) Left to Right\nc) Random fashion\nd) Both (a) and (b)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 628, "Question": "Which of the following method are accepted for assignment?\na) 5 = a = b = c = d;\nb) a = b = c = d = 5;\nc) a = b = 5 = c = d;\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 629, "Question": "Which of the following is NOT possible with any 2 operators in C?\na) Different precedence, same associativity\nb) Different precedence, different associativity\nc) Same precedence, different associativity.\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 630, "Question": "Which of the following is possible with any 2 operators in C?\na) Same associativity, different precedence\nb) Same associativity, same precedence\nc) Different associativity, different precedence\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 631, "Question": "Which of the following operators has the lowest precedence?\na) !=\nb) &&\nc) ?:\nd) ,", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 632, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3, i = 0;\n do {\n x = x++;\n i++;\n } while (i != 3);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) Undefined behaviour\nb) Output will be 3\nc) Output will be 6\nd) Output will be 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 633, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = -1, b = 4, c = 1, d;\n d = ++a && ++b || ++c;\n printf(\"%d, %d, %d, %d\\n\", a, b, c, d);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0, 4, 2, 1\nb) 0, 5, 2, 1\nc) -1, 4, 1, 1\nd) 0, 5, 1, 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 634, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int p = 10, q = 20, r;\n if (r = p = 5 || q > 20)\n printf(\"%d\", r);\n else\n printf(\"No Output\\n\");\n }\na) 1\nb) 10\nc) 20\nd) No Output", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 635, "Question": "What is 7/9*9 equal to?\nA. 2\nB. 0\nC. 1\nD. 0.08642", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 636, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor( i=1; i<10,j<5;i*=2,j++){\nj+=2;\nprintf(\"%d \",j);\n}\nPrintf(\"%d %d\",i,j);\nA. 2 5 4 7\nB. 2 5 6 4\nC. 2 5 3 6 \nD. 2 5 4 8\nE. 2 5 4 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 637, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i;\nfor(i=1;i<4;i++)\n switch(i){\n case 1: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 2: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 3: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 4: printf(\"%d \",i);\n}\nA. 1 2 3 \nB. 4\nC. 1 2 3 4 \nD. 1 2 \nE. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 638, "Question": "If the program completes executing successfully, what value should the function main returned?\nA. void\nB. 0\nC. nothing\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 639, "Question": "Which value can not be assigned to an unsigned-short type?\nA. 59876\nB. 0\nC. 10000\nD. -3\nE. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 640, "Question": "If a program contains just one function, then it must be___.\nA. clrscr()\nB. getch()\nC. printf()\nD. main()\nE. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 641, "Question": "What number is equivalent to -4e3 ?\nA. -4000\nB.-400\nC. .004\nD. -40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 642, "Question": "What does the following declaration mean ( If there are more than one correct answer, choose the best one)\nInt*ptr[10];\nA. Array of 10 integer pointers\nB. Pointers to the array of 10 elements\nC. Array of 10 pointers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 643, "Question": "___ is the comparison operation and ___ is the logical operation.\nA. Modulo, Less than\nB. Less than, NOT\nC. NOT, Less than\nD. Divide, OR", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 644, "Question": "- What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat a=14.5;\ndouble b=12.45;\nprintf(\"%.6f%.6f\",a,b);\nA. 14.50000 12.45000\nB. 14.5 12.45\nC. 14.500000 12.450000\nD. 14.5 12.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 645, "Question": "The ___ function after accepting a character and wait for the Enter key to be pressed.\nA. putch()\nB. putchar()\nC. getch()\nD. getchar()", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 646, "Question": "Evaluate the following as true or false: !(1&&0||!1)\nA. true\nB. false\nC. Invalid expression", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 647, "Question": "The precedence of operators is ___\nA. Arithmetic, Comparison, Logical\nB. Logical, Comparison, Arithmetic\nC. Comparison, Arithmetic, Logical\nD. Comparison, Logical, Arithmetic", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 648, "Question": "What is the output?\n int main(){\nchar i=127;\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nreturn 0;\n}\nA. 128\nB. -128\nC. Undefined\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 649, "Question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint sum(int n);\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"s=%d\\n\",sum(5));\nreturn 0;\n}\nint sum(int n)\n{\nint s,i;\ns=0;\nfor(i=1;i<=n;i++) s+=i;\nreturn(s);\n}\nA. s=14\nB. s=15", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 650, "Question": "A user enter \"pfabcd\" from the console\nWhat is printed?\nA. pfabcd\nB. Runtime error\nC. pfa\nD. Blank(nothing output)\nE. other\nF. pf", "Choices": [], "Answer": "F "}, {"ID": 651, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat j;\nj=1000*1000;\nprintf(\"%3.0f\",j);\nA. 1000000\nB. error\nC. overflow\nD. 100", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 652, "Question": "By default any real number is treated as \nA. a long double\nB. a double\nC. depends upon the memory model that you are using\nD. a float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 653, "Question": "A string is a ___ array of characters terminated by a null('\\0').\nA. one-dimensional\nB. two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 654, "Question": "If you push 1,3, and 5 -in that odder -onto a stack , which number is popped out first?\nA. 5\nB. 1\nC. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 655, "Question": "Which of the following adds ones string to the end of another?\nA. stradd();\nB. append();\nC. strcat();\nD. stringadd();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 656, "Question": "We want to round off x, a float, to an int value. The correct way to do so would be:\nA. y= (int)(x+0.5)\nB. y= (int)((int)x+0.5)\nC.y=(int) x+0.5\nD. y= int(x+0.5)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 657, "Question": "Which of the following is the Boolean operator for logical-and ?\nA. &&\nB. &\nC. |\nD. |&", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 658, "Question": "Which is not a loop structure in C ?\nA. while\nB. for\nC. do while\nD. repeat until", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 659, "Question": "Which of the following statement is (are) wrong ? (choose 2)\nA. a1 = 1343.44;\nB. 3=d;\nC. 3**c=d;\nD. cat = 'A' *** 'B';\nE. asd = 'A'**24;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 660, "Question": "Which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another ?\nA. strcpy\nB. strcmp\nC. strcat\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 661, "Question": "- What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint i;\ni= 1;\ni = i+ 2*i ++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nA. 4\nB. 5\nC. 3\nD. 1\nE. 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 662, "Question": "What is the correct fomat to define a value in C ?\nA. const PI = 3.14159\nB. #define PI = 3.14159\nC. #define PI 3.14159\nD. #define PI = 3.14159;\nD. #define PI 3.14159;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 663, "Question": "What is required to avoid falling through from one case to the next ?\nA. break;\nB. stop;\nC. ;\nD. end;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 664, "Question": "Which is the correct statement about coupling ?\nA. Coupling is a measure of the focus within a module.\nB. In designing, high coupling is generally acceptable.\nC. Global variables introduce a low degree of coupling.\nD. We call a module highly couple if it shares that performance with some other module including the referring module.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 665, "Question": "Which of the following functions compares two strings ?\nA. compare();\nB. stringcompare();\nC. cmp();\nD. strcmp();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 666, "Question": "What is the correct prototype in C ?\nA. doFunc():char;\nB. char doFunc()\nC. int doFunc(int,int);\nD. void doFunc(int x, int y);\nE. float doFunc(void);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 667, "Question": "Which of the following statements prints %character ?\nA. printf(\"\\%\")\nB. printf(\"\\\\%\");\nC. printf(\"\\%%\")\nD. printf(\"%%\");", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 668, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\n if( v==1||v==0) return 1;\n if(v%2==0) return(fn(v/2)+2);\n else return(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main(){\n printf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\n return (0);\n}\nA. 7\nB. 9\nC. 5\nD. 6\nE. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 669, "Question": "Which of the following data type occupied 1 byte ? (choose two)\nA. unsigned char\nB. short\nC. float\nD. long double\nE. double\nF. char", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A F "}, {"ID": 670, "Question": "- What are the correct statements ? ( choose two)\nA. The operator ** reads as 'the data at address'.\nB. The *** operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand\nC. The operator ** reads the address of the variable.\nD. The & operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 671, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint s=0;\nfor (int i=1;i<=10;++i){\n s=s+i;\n if (s>=6) break;\n s=s+1;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",s);\nA. 10\nB. 7\nC. 9\nD. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 672, "Question": "#include<stdlib.h>\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\n int i,n,a=10,b=20;\n for(i=0;i<10;i++){\n n=a+rand()%(b+1-a);\n printf(\"%d\\n\",n);\n }\n return 0;\n}\nRun the above program, which is correct statement about the output?\nA. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 11 and 19 inclusive.\nB. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 10 and 20 inclusive.\nC. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 9 and 21 inclusive.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 673, "Question": "Which are proper declarations of a string str which stores the value \"Melodies\" (choose two)\nA. char str[]= \"Melodies\";\nB. char str[7] = \"Melodies\";\nC. char str[9] = \" Melodies\";\nD. char str[] = Melodies;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 674, "Question": "What would happen if the user types in number 3 and presses Enter when running this program ?\nmain(){\n int x=5;\n char c;\n printf(\"Enter x=\");\n scanf(\"%d\",&x);\n printf(\"Calculate square?(Y/N):\");\n c=getchar();\n if (c== 'Y'|| c== 'y')\n printf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\nA. sqr = 25\nB. The program exits without printing the square\nC. sqr = 9\nD. It depends on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \" calculate square?\"", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 675, "Question": "What is size of an int ?\nA. 8 bits\nB. 16 bits \nC. Dependent on machine's \"word\" size\nD. 32 bits", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 676, "Question": "How is the integer pointer var declared in C?\nA. int** x;\nB. int pointer*** var;\nC. int pointer var;\nD. pointer** var;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 677, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nvoid foo(int x){\n if (x>0) foo(--x);\n printf(\"%d\",x);\n}\nint main(){\n foo(4);\n printf(\"\\n\");\n return 0;\n}\nA. 00123\nB. 001234 \nC. 430123\nD. 01234 \nE. 40123", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 678, "Question": "How do you include a system header file called sysheader.h in a C source file ?\nA. #includefile<sysheader>\nB.#include<sysheader.h>\nC. #incl<sysheader.h>\nD. #incl \"sysheader.h\"\nE. #includesysheader.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 679, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor(i=1;i<10,j<3;i*=2) {\n printf(\"%d\",j++);\n}\nprintf(\"%d%d\",i,j);\nA. 012384 \nB. 012394 \nC. 0123184\nD. 01283", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 680, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nvoid show(int**b){\n printf (\"%d \",**b);\n}\nint main(){\n int i;\n int a[] = { 23,34,45,56};\n for(i=0;i<3;i++) show(&a[i]+1);\n return (0);\n}\nA. 23 45 56\nB. 23 34 45\nC. 45 56 23 \nD. 34 45 56", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 681, "Question": "Which of the following is used to call a function named as doFun()\nA. Call foFunc();\nB. doFunc();\nC. include doFunc();\nD. None of other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 682, "Question": "What is the output of the following program ?\nvoid main()\n{\n Printf(\"%d\",-5/-4);\n}\nA. -1.25\nB. 1.25\nC. -1\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 683, "Question": "Which one is not the standard library in C?\nA. time.h\nB. stdlib.h\nC. system.h\nD. math.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 684, "Question": "Once the function ends, the control is returned back to the ... function and execution continues from the statement immediately after the function call\na. executing\nb.called\nc.declared\nd.calling", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 685, "Question": "what number is equivalent to -4e3?\na.-4000\nb.-400\nc..004\nd..0004\ne.-40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 686, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\n if(v==1||v==0)\n return 1;\n if(v%2==0)\n return (fn(v/2)+2);\n else\n return(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\nreturn (0);\n}\na.6\nb.9\nc.8\nd.7\ne.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 687, "Question": "which 2 options are correct about the function scanf?\na.EOF indicates that scanf filled all addresses successfully\nb. scanf returns the number of addresses successfully filled of EOF\nc.return avoid type\nd.EOF indicates that scanf did not fill any address AND encountered an end of data character.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D "}, {"ID": 688, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint s=35;\nprintf(\"%d%d%d\",s==35,s+20,s>40)\na.1 35 1\nb.1 55 1\nc.0 55 0\nd.1 55 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 689, "Question": "according to the standard C specification, what are the respective minimum sizes (in bytes) of the following two data type: int and long?\na.2,8\nb.4,8\nc.2,4\nd.2,2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 690, "Question": "what does the following declaration mean (if there are more than one correct answers, choose the best one)\nint *ptr[10];\na.array of 10 integer pointers\nb.pointed to the array of 10 elements\nc.array of 10 pointers", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 691, "Question": "what would happen if the user types in the number 3 and presses Enter when running this program?\nmain(){\nint x=5;\nchar c;\nprintf(\"Enter x=\");\nscanf(\"%d\",&x);\nprintf(\"Calculate square(Y/N):\");\nc=getchar();\nif(c==Y||c==y)\nprintf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\na.sqr=9\nb.Its depend on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \"calculate square?\"\nc.sqr=25\nd.the program exits without printing the square", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 692, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i,j,k,x=0;\nfor(i=1;i<5;i++)\n for(j=0;j<i;++j){\n switch(i+j){\n case 0:x=x+1;\n break;\n case 1:\n case 2:\n case 3: x=x+2;\n break;\n}}\nprintf(\"%d\",x);\na.12\nb.13\nc.10\nd.8\ne.6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 693, "Question": "the while loop can be written as a for loop\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 694, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar fun[]=\"How are you?\";\nchar **p;\np=fun;\nwhile(***p!='\\0'){\nif(strlen(p)!=7) printf(\"%c\",**p);\np++;}\na. How ar you\nb.Ho are you\nc.How re you\nd.How are you\ne. How ae you", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 695, "Question": "given the below code ?\nchar st[50];\nscanf(\"%5[^\\]\",st);\nprintf(\"%s\",st);\na user enters \"pfc is simple\"\nwhat is printed?\na.other\nb.pfc is\nc.pfc is so simple\nd.blank output\ne.pfc i", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 696, "Question": "how is a variable accessed from another file?\na. the global variable is referenced via the auto specifier\nb. the global variable is referenced via the extern specifier\nc. the global variable is referenced via the pointer specifier\nd. the global variable is referenced via the ext specifier\ne. the global variable is referenced via the global specifier", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 697, "Question": "which one of the following is a variable, which can contain the address of the memory location of another variable?(choose the best answer)\na.string\nb.struct\nc.array\nd.pointer", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 698, "Question": "declare a two dimensional integer array of two rows and four columns having some initial values\na.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nb.int arr1[2][4]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nc.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12};{22,45};{23,40};{44,79}}\nd.int arr1[][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 699, "Question": "what value will x contain in the sample code below?\nint x=011|0x10;\na.27\nb.19\nc.25\nd.13\ne.3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 700, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint g=1;\nprintf(\"%d %d %d\",g,++g,g++);\na.1 3 3 \nb.1 2 3 \nc.1 1 1 \nd.3 3 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 701, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0;\nfor(;i;)\nprintf(\"This is a loop\");\nif(i>0)\nprintf(\"in C program\");\na. nothing\nb. garbage value\nc. in C program\nd.this is a loop in C program\ne. this is a loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 702, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nvoid main(){\nint i,j=25;\nint **pi, ***pj=&j;\n ***pj=j+5;\n i=*pj+5;\n pi=pj;\n **pi=i+j;\n printf(\"%d%d\",***pi,*pj);}\na.30 35\nb.65 65\nc.60 60\nd.25 30\ne.60 65", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 703, "Question": "which one of the following is a valid function definition?\na. double funct(int a,b, double c,d)\nb. double funct(int a,b, double c)\nc. double funct(char a,b, double d)\nd. double funct(int a,int b, double c)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 704, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar mess[]=\"Your are welcome here\";\nchar *p;\np=mess;\nmess[8]='\\0';\nputs(++p);\na.our are wel\nb.our are \nc.Your are \nd.Your are wel", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 705, "Question": "which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another\na.strcpy\nb.strcmp\nc.strcat\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 706, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a=8, b=9;\nif(a%2=b%3)\nprintf(\"\\n%d %d\", ++a, b--)\na. 8 9\nb. 9 9 \nc.9 8\nd. compiler error\ne. 8 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 707, "Question": "what will be printed when the sample code below is executed?\nchar **buffer=\"0123456789\";\nchar **ptr=buffer;\nptr+=5;\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",ptr);\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",buffer);\na. 56789\n0123456789\n\nb.56789\n56789\n\nc.0123456789\n0123456789\n\nd.5123456789\n5123456789\n\ne.0123456789\n56789", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 708, "Question": "in myfile.c does not exist, what will be output of this program?\n#include<stdio.h>\nmain(){\nFILE *fi;\nfi=fopen(\"myfile.c\",\"r\");\nif(fi=NULL)\n{puts(\"file is not opened\");\nexit(1);}\nelse\nputs(\"FILE opened\");}\na. file is not opened\nb.no output\nc.FILE opened\nd.error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 709, "Question": "given the below code\nint a=1;\nint i=7;\nif(a||i++)\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nwhat is the output\na.7\nb.8\nc.9\nd.other", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 710, "Question": "a string is a ... array of characters terminated by a null('\\0')\na.one-dimensional\nb.two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 711, "Question": "referring to the sample code below, what value will the variable counter have when completed\nint x=3, counter = 0;\nwhile(x-1){\n++counter;\nx--;}\na.4 \nb.2\nc.3\nd.0\ne.1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 712, "Question": "the operation between float and int would give the result as\na. float\nb. int \nc. unsigned int\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 713, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint k=0x55;\nprintf(\"\\n%d\",k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na.65\nb.75\nc.55\nd.85", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 714, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint calc(int a, int b){\nint x,y;\nx=a+b;\ny=a*b;\nreturn(x+y);\n}\nint main(){\nint p=3, q=4, r, s;\nr=calc(p,q);\ns=calc(q,p);\nprintf(\"\\n%d%d\",r,s);\nreturn 0;}\na. 3 4\nb. 17 19\nc. 18 18\nd. 17 17\ne.19 19", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 715, "Question": "which of the following statement are true with regards to the || operator?(select al correct answer)\na.this operator is used to combine two conditional expressions which evaluate to true as a whole only if either of the two expressions evaluate to true.\nb.only if both the expressions evaluate to false, the outcome is false\nc.if one of the conditional expressions return false, the outcome is false\nd.this operator is used to combine two logical expressions which evaluate to true if both individual expression are true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 716, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed, assuming int data type is 32 bits in size?\nprintf(\"%d, %d, %d, %d\", sizeof(char), sizeof(int), sizeof(10.0), sizeof(10.0f));\na. 2,4,8,4\nb. 1,10,10,10\nc. 1,4,8,4\nd. 1,4,4,4\ne. 1,2,4,4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 717, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a[5]={0}, x=2111223;\nwhile(x>10){\na[x%10-1]++;\nx/=10;}\nprintf(\"%d\",a[1]);\na.6\nb.3\nc.1\nd.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 718, "Question": "what will the code below print when executed?\ndouble x=-3.5, y=3.5;\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",ceil(x), ceil(y));\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",floor(x), floor(y));\na -3:3\n-4:4\nb.-4:3\n-3:4\nc.-4:4\n-3:3\nd.-3:4\n-4:3\ne.-4:3\n-4:3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 719, "Question": "consider the following code:\nif(a==b)\nprintf(\"\\n the number are equal\");\nelse(a<b)\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",a);\nelse\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",b);\nin the above code, if a=14 and b=9, then the .... clause is executed\na. else\nb.if\nc else if", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 720, "Question": "when does the code block following while(x<100) execute?\na.when x is less than one hundred\nb.when x is equal to one hundred\nc.when x is greater than one hundred\nd.while it wishes", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 721, "Question": "which are the following statements printf % character?\na.printf(\"\\%\")\nb.printf(\"\\\\%\")\nc.printf(\"\\%%\")\nd.printf(\"%%\")", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 722, "Question": "a comment can be split over more than one line, as follows\n/** A program\nto calculate average\nof 5 numbers. **/\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 723, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint p,q,h;\nfor(p=1;p<=3;p++)\nfor(q=1;q<=2;q++)\nh=p+q;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",h);\na.1\nb.5\nc.3\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 724, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint x=3;\nif(x==2)\nx=0;\nif(x==3)\nx++;\nelse x+=2;\na.5\nb.3\nc.1\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 725, "Question": "what is the incorrect statement about floating-point data types(float and double)?\na. computers store floating-point data using separate components, including the mantissa and exponent\nb.float-point means that the decimal point can float(that is, it can ba placed anywhere relative to the significant digits)\nc.both data types(float and double) can represent arbitrarily small as well as arbitrarily large numbers\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 726, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint n=10, i;\nint k=0;\nfor(i=1;i<n;i=i*2)k++;\nprintf(\"i:%d, k:%d\", i, k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na i:16, k:3\nb.i:16, k:4\nc.i:16, k:5\nd.i:8, k:4\ne.i:10, k:4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 727, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nmain()\n{int i=5;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i=++i==6)\na.0\nb.1\nc.5\nd.6\ne.7", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 728, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar *ptr=\"Hello world\";\nptr++;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\nptr+=2;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\na.ello worldllo world\nb.Hello worldHello world\nc.ello worldlo world\nd.ello worldHello world\ne.Hello worldello world", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 729, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=3;\nswitch(i){\ncase 3: i+=5;\nif(i==8){\ni++;\nif(i==9) break;\ni*=2;}\ni-=4;\nbreak;\ncase 8:\ni+=5;\nbreak;\ndefault: \ni+=6;\nbreak;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i);\na.8\nb.11\nc.7\nd.9\ne.10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 730, "Question": "using break statement we can exit from\na. for a loop\nb. an if statement\nc. the main() function\nd. a program", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 731, "Question": "give the code below\nint a=2;\nprintf(\"%d\",++a,a+5)\nwhat is printed?\na. undefined\nb. error\nc. 2\nd. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 732, "Question": "Which of these statements about the array are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. In C, the index of an element can be begin from 1. \n b. An array is stored in contiguously block of memory and each element is identified by its index. \n c. The index of an element can be an integer variable, an integer expression or an integer constant. \n d. We use the operator () to access an element of array. \n e. An array is a group of related elements and they belong the same data type.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C E "}, {"ID": 733, "Question": "The linear search algorithm can be applied on an array in which its elements .......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. are in no order. \n b. are in descending order. \n c. are in ascending order. \n d. have different data types.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 734, "Question": "Study the binary search algorithm:\nint binarySearch (int x, int a[], int low, int high)\n{ while (low<=hight)\n{ int mid= (low+high)/2;\nif ( x==a[mid]) return mid ;\nelse if (x>a[mid]) low=mid+1;\nelse high=mid-1;\n}\nreturn -1;\n} \nSuppose that this function is used as following:\nint a[6] = { 1, 2, 2, 3, 3,5};\nint pos = binarySearch(3,a,0,5);\nWhat is the value of the variable pos? \n \nChoose one answer. \n a. 3 \n b. -1 \n c. 4 \n d. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 735, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Flagging technique uses an integer for marking elements of an array when we summarize data of the array. \n b. Flagging technique is applied when user input values to an array only. \n c. Flagging technique is used when we summarize data in an array. \n d. Flagging technique helps marking some data in an array.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 736, "Question": "What are the names of search algorithm applied to an array?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Linear search. \n b. Binary search. \n c. Random search. \n d. Bubble search. \n e. Selection search.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 737, "Question": "Study the following function:\nSuppose that all needed libraries are included.\nint search ( int x, int a[], int n)\n{ int i;\nfor ( i=n-1; i>=0 ; i--) if (x==a[i]) return i;\nreturn -1;\n}\nThis function is used as following:\nint a[10] = { 1, 2, 2, 2, 3, 3, 3, 4, 4, 4};\nint pos = search(3, a, 10);\nWhen the above code executes, what is the value of the variable pos?\nChoose one answer. \n a. 6 \n b. 4 \n c. 5 \n d. -1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 738, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 1,2,3,4,5 };\nint*p= a;\nint i;\nfor (i=0;i<5; i++) \nif (i%2==0) \n{ (*p)++;\np++;\n}\nfor (i=0;i<5;i++) printf(\"%d, \", a[i]);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhen the above program executes. What is the output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. 2, 3, 4, 4, 5 \n b. 15 \n c. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 739, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 1,2,3,4,5 };\nint*p= a;\nint i;\nint S=10;\nfor (i=0;i<5; i++) \nif (a[i]%2==0) S+=a[i]; \nprintf(\"%d\", S);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. 25 \n b. 12 \n c. 15 \n d. 6 \n e. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 740, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nvoid f1 ( int*a, int n)\n{ int i,j,t;\nfor (i=0;i<n-1;i++)\nfor (j=n-1; j>i; j--)\nif (a[j]>a[j-1])\n{ t=a[j];\na[j]=a[j-1];\na[j-1]=t;\n}\n}\nvoid f2 (int a[], int n)\n{ int i;\nfor (i=0;i<n;i++) printf (\"%d%s \", a[i], (i<4 ? \",\" : \"\" ));\n}\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 5, 1, 2,4, 3 };\nf1(a,5);\nf2(a,5);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. 5, 4, 3, 2, 1 \n b. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 \n c. 2, 4, 1, 3, 5 \n d. 1, 3, 5, 2, 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 741, "Question": "With respect to the binary search algorithm on an array, .......\nChoose one answer. \n a. this algorithm cannot be applied on array of characters. \n b. The values contained in the array must be in an order (ascending or descending). \n c. this algorithm cannot be applied on array of real numbersaracters. \n d. no criterion on the array is required.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 742, "Question": "Which of these statements about the %s conversion specifier used in scanf function are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. It will read all characters until the first white space character. \n b. User can not enter any digit. \n c. It is usually used when user will enter a word such as the code of a product. \n d. A parameter of this function must be a string. \n e. It requires user entering at least 2 characters.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 743, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nvoid f(char S[ ], char c1, char c2)\n{ int L= strlen(S);\nint i;\nfor (i=0; i<L; i++)\nif (*(S+i) == c1) *(S+i)=c2;\n}\nint main() \n{ char S[10]=\"ABCDEFGEH\";\nf( S, 'E', 0);\nprintf(\"%s\", S);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. ABCD \n b. ABCD0FG0H \n c. None of the others. \n d. ABCDEFGEH", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 744, "Question": "Which of these statements about null byte terminator are not true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. We refer to the null byte using the escape sequence '\\0'. \n b. We can describe the null byte as the constant EOF. \n c. The null byte is the character with the value (code) 0. \n d. We use the null byte to locate the last meaningful element in a string", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 745, "Question": "Which of these statements about the %[^ ] specifier is true when it is used in the scanf function ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. The scanf function will store the characters read in memory locations starting with the address passed to scanf \n b. The scanf function will read all characters until the newline character \n c. The scanf function will leave the delimiting character in the input buffer \n d. All of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 746, "Question": "Which of the the following is the result of the %[abcd] conversion specifier when it is used in the scanf function and the input is dfgh ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. abcd \n b. fgh \n c. dfgh \n d. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 747, "Question": "Which is the result of strcmp(S1, S2) with S1 =\"abcdefgh\" and S2 = \"abcdefdh\"?\nChoose one answer. \n a. A negative integer. \n b. Zero. \n c. A positive integer. \n d. A character.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 748, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ char S[50]= \"ABCDEF\";\nprintf(\"Length:%d, %s\", strlen(S), &S[2]);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program s .......\nChoose one answer. \n a. Length:6, CDEF \n b. 6 and an error is thrown. \n c. The program causes an error when it is compiled. \n d. 6, CDEF", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 749, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ char S1[50]= \"ABCDEF\";\nchar S2[50]= \"GHI\";\nstrcat(S1,S2);\nprintf(\"%s\", S1);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the output of the program?\nChoose one answer. \n a. ABCDEFGHI \n b. 6 \n c. An error is thrown when it is compiled. \n d. ABCDEF \n e. 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 750, "Question": "Study three following code segments:\n(1)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nputs(S);\n(2)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nprintf(\"%s\",S);\n(3)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nprintf(\"%s \\n\",S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. (1) and (2) have the same output. \n b. (2) and (3) have the same output. \n c. All of them have different outputs. \n d. (1) and (3) have the same output.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 751, "Question": "Suppose the string library was included. Study the following C-code:\nchar S1[10]=\"AB\";\nchar S2[10]=\"AB1\";\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", strcmp(S1,S2), strcmp(S2,S1));\nThe output of the above code is:\nChoose one answer. \n a. Non-predictable values. \n b. a negative and a positive integers. \n c. The function strcmp(...) is not in string.h \n d. Two 0s. \n e. a positive and a negative integers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 752, "Question": "The function fopen(...) is used for openning a text file. Which of the following mode parameters can not be used?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. rt \n b. art \n c. RW \n d. w+t \n e. a+t", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 753, "Question": "What in the following file operations should be used when the file closed only?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. renaming a file. \n b. seeking in a file. \n c. rewinding a file. \n d. get file size. \n e. remove a file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 754, "Question": "Which of these statements about file format types are true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. With text format, the data on the file can be modified using a text editor. \n b. With text format, data from a file can be read directly to a numeral variable with no tranformation. \n c. With text format, data in a the file are stored as ASCII code of characters. \n d. With binary format, data in a file can be modified using text editor.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 755, "Question": "In C, which of following functions can be used to write data to a file?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. gets \n b. fputc \n c. fprintf \n d. fgets \n e. fgetc \n f. fputs \n g. puts \n h. fgetchar", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C F "}, {"ID": 756, "Question": "Text format is used. Which of these statements about table, record, and fields are not true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. A record is a sequence of characters that ends with a new line delimiter. \n b. Typically, one table refers to one entity of information \n c. Table is a collection of records \n d. A record consists of fields \n e. A new line delimiter must be used to separate two adjacent fields of a record. \n f. A field may be of any data type", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B E "}, {"ID": 757, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. We can rename a file if the file is closed. \n b. We can rewind a file only if the file is closed. \n c. We can rename a file although the file is openning. \n d. The file can be remove if it is openning. \n e. Rewinding a file will move current position to the beginning of the file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 758, "Question": "Suppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\nint n=7;\nIn C, if this variable is written to a textfile (using ASCII code), it will take ... byte(s) in the file.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 2 \n b. 4 \n c. 3 \n d. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 759, "Question": "Suppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\nint n=7;\nIn C, if this variable is written to a binary file, it will take ... byte(s) in the file.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 1 \n b. 4 \n c. 2 \n d. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 760, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nSuppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\n(1) Writing int values into text file will make the file having small size.\n(2) Writing int values into text file will make the file having large size.\n(3) Writing int values into text file is less efficient because type conversions are needed.\nChoose one answer.\n a. (1) and (3) \n b. None of the others. \n c. (3) \n d. (2) and (3)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 761, "Question": "What guideline should be examined before working with a text file?\n(1) data format in the file must be known or designed.\n(2) number of values in the file must be known .\n(3) Last date modified of the file must be known.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 3 \n b. 1 \n c. 2 \n d. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 762, "Question": "Which of these statements about the black-box testing are not true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. External factors, such as logic-driven, and path-oriented, are determinant \n b. Each possible path through the code is executed at least once. The number of possibilities to be tested may be too great \n c. Synonyms for black-box include: structural, glass-box and clear-box \n d. External factors, such as testing to specifications, input-output driven, and data driven, are determinant \n e. Synonyms for black-box include: behavioral, functional, opaque-box, and closed-box", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B C "}, {"ID": 763, "Question": "Methods are used in testing a software are .........\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. White box testing \n b. Black box testing. \n c. Action testing \n d. Statement testing", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 764, "Question": "Which of these statements about comparing the difference of Waterfall and Open Source Model are true?\nChoose one answer.\n a. The Open Source is seldom reliability than Waterfall Models \n b. The Waterfall Models focus is user-driven rather than concept driven in Open Source Models \n c. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 765, "Question": "Marks: 1\nStatement 1: If a program works then it is good designed.\nStatement 2: If the program models a real world situation, it can be hardly upgraded.\nChoose one answer.\n a. One of two statements is true. \n b. The statement 2 is true. \n c. Both of them are false. \n d. The statement 1 is true.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 766, "Question": "Study the following steps in software development process:\n(1) Analysis\n(2) Design\n(3) Implementing\n(4) Deploying\n(5) Maintenance\nThe correct order of them is ..........\nChoose one answer.\n a. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 \n b. None of the others. \n c. 1, 3, 2, 4, 5 \n d. 2, 3, 1, 4, 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 767, "Question": "The output of a program is incorrect. It may be caused by ......\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. the algorithm is wrong. \n b. a semantic error. \n c. a syntactical error.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 768, "Question": "Analysis and maintenance are ............. phases in the sofware development process.\nChoose one answer.\n a. intermediate \n b. None of the others. \n c. last and first \n d. first and last", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 769, "Question": "........software development model(s) has (have) some phases that are concurrently carried out.\nChoose one answer.\n a. Waterfall and practical \n b. None of the others. \n c. Practical \n d. Waterfall", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 770, "Question": "Restricting our use of the language to the standard subset of a language will create the ......... of a program.\nChoose one answer.\n a. portability \n b. efficiency \n c. correctness \n d. reliability", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 771, "Question": "Data is stored in computer memory in .........\nChoose one answer. \n a. decimal format. \n b. hexadecimal format. \n c. octal format. \n d. binary format.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 772, "Question": "Which of these statements about primary memory are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Primary memory holds the information accessed by the CPU. \n b. RAM is a volatile memory. \n c. There is only one operation on primary memory and it is reading. \n d. ROM is a volatile memory. \n e. Primary memory is addressable.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 773, "Question": "(1) One byte consists of 4 nibbles. \n(2) One nibble consists of 2 consecutive bits\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. (1): false \n b. (1) true. \n c. (2): true. \n d. (2): false", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 774, "Question": "Which of these statements about fundamental unit in CPU is true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. The natural unit of the CPU is a int \n b. The natural unit of the CPU is a numeric \n c. The natural unit of the CPU is a bit \n d. The natural unit of the CPU is a word \n e. The natural unit of the CPU is a byte", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 775, "Question": "Which of these definitions are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The CPU performs the operation on the values stored as operands or on the values stored in the operand addresses. \n b. The addresses are specific values of a program. \n c. The addresses are either register names or primary memory addresses. \n d. Each program instruction consists of an operation and operands. \n e. Each program instruction consists of an expression only.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 776, "Question": "Comments of a program ......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. are used for documenting a program. \n b. are omitted by the compiler. \n c. enhance the readability of a program. \n d. are translated into instructions after the program is compiled.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B C "}, {"ID": 777, "Question": "Select correct properties of C language.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. C source code must be translated into executable code by a compiler. \n b. C language is a functional language. \n c. C language is case-insensitive language. \n d. C is case sensitive language. \n e. C language is a low-level language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B D "}, {"ID": 778, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. A compiler will translate each statement of source code into machine code then CPU executes this statement. \n b. An interpreter will iterate to translate each statement of source code into machine code then CPU execute these binary code of this statement. \n c. Compiler of the language A can translate A-source code into language B-source code then the B-language compiler will translate B-source code into machine code. \n d. An interpreter will translate all source codes into machine codes then CPU executes them as a whole.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 779, "Question": "....... helps identifying the device which will communiate with CPU.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Address bus. \n b. All \n c. Control bus. \n d. Data bus.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 780, "Question": "Which type qualifiers are defined in C?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. short \n b. complex \n c. double \n d. array \n e. long", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 781, "Question": "In C, select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The expression x=y; will copy value of the variable x to the variable y. \n b. The expression x=y; will copy value of the variable y to the variable x. \n c. A constant character must be enclosed by a pair of double or single quotes. \n d. A constant string must be enclosed by a pair of double quotes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D "}, {"ID": 782, "Question": "1. Intel use this little-endian ordering\n2. Motorola use middle-endian ordering\n3. Motorola use big-endian ordering\n4. Intel use this big-endian ordering\nChoose one answer. \n a. 2, 3 true \n b. All of them are true \n c. 1, 4 true \n d. 2, 4 true \n e. 1, 3 true \n f. 1, 2 true \n g. All of them are false", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 783, "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. employee salary \n b. False \n c. _123 \n d. +ab \n e. 45n \n f. True", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D E "}, {"ID": 784, "Question": "Which of these statements about constants are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The compiler allocates memory for constants. \n b. The compiler does not allocate memory for constants. \n c. The compiler embeds constants directly into the program instructions. \n d. The compiler compiles constants.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 785, "Question": "In C language, \n(1) The == operator is used for setting a value to a variable. \n(2) The = operator is used for checking whether two numbers are equal or not. \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. (2): true. \n b. (2): false \n c. (1): false \n d. (1) true.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 786, "Question": "Select correct statements. With respect to ASCII, ..........\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Binary ASCII code of the character a is 0100 0001 \n b. Binary ASCII code of the digit 1 is 0000 0001 \n c. Binary ASCII of the character A is 0100 0001 \n d. The code of a uppercase character is less than the code of a lowercase character. \n e. The code of a digit is less than the code of an alphabet.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 787, "Question": "Select correct conversion specifiers for an int variable in C lanaguge.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. %f \n b. %o \n c. %e \n d. %d \n e. %u", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D E "}, {"ID": 788, "Question": "In C language, the selection constructs use ....... \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. while \n b. switch \n c. for \n d. ?: \n e. if else \n f. if else then", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D E "}, {"ID": 789, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes are executed. What is the output?\nlong S=10;\nlong i=1;\nwhile (i<=10)\n{ if (i%2==0) S+=i;\ni++;\n}\nprintf(\"%ld\", S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 32 \n b. 38 \n c. 46 \n d. 40 \n e. 36", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 790, "Question": "Flags is a technique that supports using goto, continue statements\nChoose one answer. \n a. True \n b. False", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 791, "Question": "To improve readability, programmers are recommended .......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. using whitespace to identify the logical structure of the code. \n b. using goto statements as needed. \n c. removing continue statements. \n d. using break statements as needed. \n e. using comments.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 792, "Question": "Marks: 1 \n1. The rule in C is that an else statement always belongs to the innermost if available\n2. The rule in C is that an else statement always belongs to the outermost if available\nChoose one answer. \n a. Only 2nd statement is true \n b. Only 1st statement is true \n c. Both 1 and 2 statements are false \n d. Both 1 and 2 statements are true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 793, "Question": "Program should be written ... \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. with a complicated appearance. \n b. as a well program. \n c. with a consistent style and clear throughout. \n d. with significant effort and private style.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 794, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Walkthrough is a process in which any change in codes is recorded. \n b. Walkthrough process is used for evaluating the performance of a program. \n c. A table that contains all program variables is used in walkthrough process. \n d. Walkthrough is a manual process for recording all changes of program variables when the program executes instruction-by-instruction. \n e. A listing of the output, if any, produced by the program is carried out when we do a walkthrough..", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 795, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute and input data are 9 and 12.\nint m,n; \nprintf(\"Enter two integers:\"); \nscanf(\"%d%d\",&m, &n);\nif (m>10 && n<20) printf(\"%d\", m+n);\nelse printf(\"%d\", m-n);\nWhat is the output.\nChoose one answer. \n a. None of the others. \n b. 21 \n c. -3 \n d. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 796, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute. What is the output?\nlong S=10;\nlong i;\nfor (i=1; i<10; i++) if (i%3==0) S+=i;\nprintf(\"%ld\", S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 19 \n b. 31 \n c. 16 \n d. 22 \n e. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 797, "Question": "In C, which of these statements are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. #include \"filename\" using with filename locate in system directory. \n b. We can collect function prototypes into a file and refer to the file in our program \n c. We use the #include directive to instruct the compiler to insert a copy of the header file into our source code. \n d. #include <filename> using with filename locate in user directory \n e. # is a symbol of postprocessor indicators", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D E "}, {"ID": 798, "Question": "What is the output if the following code executes.\nint n=3, m=7;\nint* p1= &n, *p2=&m;\n*p1 -= m+n- 3*(*p2);\n*p2 += *p1%2 ? 2 : 5; \nprintf (\"%d\", m-n);\nChoose one answer. \n a. -5 \n b. None of the others. \n c. -4 \n d. 6 \n e. 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 799, "Question": "In C, incorrect order(s) of a function implementation:\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Return type, body, function name, parameters \n b. Return type, body, parameters, function name \n c. Return type, function name, parameters, body \n d. Return type, parameters, body, function name", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B D "}, {"ID": 800, "Question": "Which of these statements about the function is true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. All of the others \n b. The body is the code block that contains the module instructions and generates the return value \n c. A function definition consists of a header and a body \n d. A function that does not return a value is called a subroutine or procedure in other languages \n e. A function may receive data and may return a value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 801, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Actual parameter is a parameter in function implementation. \n b. Formal parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called. \n c. Actual parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called. \n d. Formal parameter is a parameter in function implementation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 802, "Question": "Select the statements that belong to low cohesion\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. \"logical\" - related tasks of which only one is performed - the module identifier suggests a choice \n b. \"functional\" - performs a single specific task - the module identifier suggests a precise verb phrase \n c. \"communicational\" - the tasks share the same data - all tasks are carried out each time \n d. \"coincidental\" - unrelated tasks", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 803, "Question": "In C, with reference to property of reusing a function, the function that will check whether an integer is a prime or not, should be declared as ........ \nChoose one answer. \n a. a void function. \n b. a function that returns a real number. \n c. a function that will return an integer. \n d. None of the others \n e. a function that returns a string a characters.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 804, "Question": "Study the following function:\nint t (int x, int y, int z)\n{ return x+y+z>20 ? 10 : 20;\n}\nIf this function is called as following with input data are 5 10 15. What is the output?\nint a,b,c;\nprintf(\"Enter 3 integers:\");\nscanf(\"%d%d%d\", &a, &b, &c);\nprintf(\"%d\", t(b,c,a));\nChoose one answer. \n a. None of the others. \n b. 20 \n c. -10 \n d. 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 805, "Question": "Study the function implementation and a case of using this function.\nint t (int x, int y)\n{ return x-y;\n}\n...\nchar c1= 'A', c2= 'D';\nprintf(\"%d\", t(c2, c1));\nSuppose that the above codes execute. What is the output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. An error is thrown when they are executed. \n b. No output is printed out. \n c. 3 \n d. -3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 806, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute. What is the output.\nint n=3, m=7;\nint* p1= &n, *p2=&m;\n*p1 -= m+n- 3*(*p2);\n*p2 += m-n; \nprintf (\"%d\", m+n);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 14 \n b. 16 \n c. 12 \n d. 20 \n e. 18", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 807, "Question": "Which of these statements about the scanf function are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The return code from scanf reflects success of %* conversions \n b. scanf retrieves data values from every keystroke directly \n c. interpreted and processed the entire format string \n d. scanf treats the whitespace between the input values as a separator \n e. If the buffer is empty, the function scanf will wait until the user adds more data values", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 808, "Question": "Select incorrect statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The specifier %hex is used for printing out an integer in hexadecimal format. \n b. The specifier %e is used for printing out a real number in scientific format. \n c. The specifier %u is used for printing out a unsigned integer. \n d. The specifier %b is used to print out an integer in binary format.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 809, "Question": "The getchar function can do\nChoose one answer. \n a. clearing the buffer automatically after retrieving \n b. None of the others \n c. treats the whitespace between the input values as a separator \n d. retrieves data values from every keystroke directly", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 810, "Question": "What library includes function to generate random numbers?\nChoose one answer. \n a. conio.h \n b. stdio.h \n c. stdlib.h \n d. math.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 811, "Question": "Validation do not include\nChoose one answer. \n a. out-of-range input \n b. invalid characters \n c. trailing characters \n d. None of the others \n e. incorrect number of input fields", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 812, "Question": "Which of these statements about format string are not true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. size identifies the size of data type of the value passed. \n b. % flags width . precision size conversion_character \n c. - describes left justification of the converted value in its field \n d. None of the others \n e. 0 pads the field width with leading zeros", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 813, "Question": "What is the output of the following program?\n/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ double x= 3.5, y= 6.8 , z= 1.5;\nint n= floor( x )+ ceil( y )+ z;\nprintf(\"%d\", n);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nChoose one answer. \n a. 12 \n b. 10 \n c. 11.5 \n d. The program causes an error when it is compiled. \n e. 11", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 814, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n;\nchar c;\nscanf(\"%d\",&n);\nc=getchar();\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", n,c);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the output of the above program if user enters the keys 12 and ENTER?\nChoose one answer. \n a. Non-predictable values. \n b. 12 \n c. No output is printed out. \n d. 12, 10 \n e. 12, 13", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 815, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n, m;\nint result = scanf(\"%d%d\",&n, &m);\nprintf(\"%d\", result);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the ouput of the above program if input is 12asd45 ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. a non-predictable value. \n b. 1 \n c. 3 \n d. 2 \n e. An error is thrown when it executes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 816, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n, m;\nscanf(\"%d,%d\",&n, &m);\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", n, m);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhen the program executes, user enters 9 100 . What is output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. Two non-predictable values. \n b. No output is printed out. \n c. 9 and a non-predictable value. \n d. An error when it executes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 817, "Question": "Program ....\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. is a collection of functions. \n b. is a simulation of solution. \n c. is the result of a programming process. \n d. is a set of instructions that computer hardware will execute. \n e. is written by C language only.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C D "}, {"ID": 818, "Question": "What are the right matching?\nCharacter Sequence\na. Newline \\t\nb. vertical tab \\v\nc. backslash \\\nd. alarm \\r\ne. backspace \\b\nf. question mark \\?\n \n \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. a \n b. f \n c. e \n d. c \n e. b \n f. d", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C E "}, {"ID": 819, "Question": "C99 standard guarantees uniqueness of ____ characters for internal names.\na) 31\nb) 63\nc) 12\nd) 14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 820, "Question": "C99 standard guarantess uniqueness of _____ characters for external names.\na) 31\nb) 6\nc) 12\nd) 14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 821, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?\na) int __a3;\nb) int __3a;\nc) int __A3;\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 822, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?\na) int _a3;\nb) int a_3;\nc) int 3_a;\nd) int _3a", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 823, "Question": "Variable names beginning with underscore is not encouraged. Why?\na) It is not standardized\nb) To avoid conflicts since assemblers and loaders use such names\nc) To avoid conflicts since library routines use such names\nd) To avoid conflicts with environment variables of an operating system", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 824, "Question": "All keywords in C are in\na) LowerCase letters\nb) UpperCase letters\nc) CamelCase letters\nd) None", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 825, "Question": "Variable name resolving (number of significant characters for uniqueness of variable) depends on\na) Compiler and linker implementations\nb) Assemblers and loaders implementations\nc) C language\nd) None", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 826, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid C variable name?\na) int number;\nb) float rate;\nc) int variable_count;\nd) int $main;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 827, "Question": "Which of the following is true for variable names in C?\na) They can contain alphanumeric characters as well as special characters\nb) It is not an error to declare a variable to be one of the keywords(like goto, static)\nc) Variable names cannot start with a digit\nd) Variable can be of any length", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 828, "Question": "Which is valid C expression?\na) int my_num = 100,000;\nb) int my_num = 100000;\nc) int my num = 1000;\nd) int $my_num = 10000;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 829, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"Hello World! %d \\n\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) Hello World! x;\nb) Hello World! followed by a junk value\nc) Compile time error\nd) Hello World!", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 830, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 10000;\n int y = 34;\n printf(\"Hello World! %d\\n\", y);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Hello World! 34\nc) Hello World! 1000\nd) Hello World! followed by a junk value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 831, "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?\na) float PI = 3.14;\nb) double PI = 3.14;\nc) int PI = 3.14;\nd) #define PI 3.14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 832, "Question": "What will happen if the below program is executed?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int main = 3;\n printf(\"%d\", main);\n return 0;\n }\na) It will cause a compile-time error\nb) It will cause a run-time error\nc) It will run without any error and prints 3\nd) It will experience infinite looping", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 833, "Question": "What is the problem in following variable declaration?\nfloat 3Bedroom-Hall-Kitchen?;\na) The variable name begins with an integer\nb) The special character '-'\nc) The special character '?'\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 834, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int ThisIsVariableName = 12;\n int ThisIsVariablename = 14;\n printf(\"%d\", ThisIsVariablename);\n return 0;\n }\na) The program will print 12\nb) The program will print 14\nc) The program will have a runtime error\nd) The program will cause a compile-time error due to redeclaration", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 835, "Question": "Which of the following cannot be a variable name in C?\na) volatile\nb) true\nc) friend\nd) export", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 836, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a[5] = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5};\n int i;\n for (i = 0; i < 5; i++)\n if ((char)a[i] == '5')\n printf(\"%d\\n\", a[i]);\n else\n printf(\"FAIL\\n\");\n }\na) The compiler will flag an error\nb) Program will compile and print the output 5\nc) Program will compile and print the ASCII value of 5\nd) Program will compile and print FAIL for 5 times", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 837, "Question": "The format identifier '%i' is also used for _____ data type?\na) char\nb) int\nc) float\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 838, "Question": "Which data type is most suitable for storing a number 65000 in a 32-bit system?\na) signed short\nb) unsigned short\nc) long\nd) int", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 839, "Question": "Which of the following is a User-defined data type?\na) typedef int Boolean;\nb) typedef enum {Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri} Workdays;\nc) struct {char name[10], int age};\nd) all of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 840, "Question": "What is the size of an int data type?\na) 4 Bytes\nb) 8 Bytes\nc) Depends on the system/compiler\nd) Cannot be determined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 841, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n signed char chr;\n chr = 128;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", chr);\n return 0;\n }\na) 128\nb) -128\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 842, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n char c;\n int i = 0;\n FILE *file;\n file = fopen(\"test.txt\", \"w+\");\n fprintf(file, \"%c\", 'a');\n fprintf(file, \"%c\", -1);\n fprintf(file, \"%c\", 'b');\n fclose(file);\n file = fopen(\"test.txt\", \"r\");\n while ((c = fgetc(file)) != -1)\n printf(\"%c\", c);\n return 0;\n }\na) a\nb) Infinite loop\nc) Depends on what fgetc returns\nd) Depends on the compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 843, "Question": "What is short int in C programming?\na) Basic datatype of C\nb) Qualifier\nc) short is the qualifier and int is the basic datatype\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 844, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n float f1 = 0.1;\n if (f1 == 0.1)\n printf(\"equal\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"not equal\\n\");\n }\na) equal\nb) not equal\nc) Output depends on compiler\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 845, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n float f1 = 0.1;\n if (f1 == 0.1f)\n printf(\"equal\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"not equal\\n\");\n }\na) equal\nb) not equal\nc) Output depends on compiler\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 846, "Question": "What is the output of this C code (on a 32-bit machine)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 10000;\n double y = 56;\n int *p = &x;\n double *q = &y;\n printf(\"p and q are %d and %d\", sizeof(p), sizeof(q));\n return 0;\n }\na) p and q are 4 and 4\nb) p and q are 4 and 8\nc) Compiler error\nd) p and q are 2 and 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 847, "Question": "Which is correct with respect to size of the datatypes?\na) char > int > float\nb) int > char > float\nc) char < int < double\nd) double > char > int", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 848, "Question": "What is the output of the following C code(on a 64 bit machine)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n union Sti\n {\n int nu;\n char m;\n };\n int main()\n {\n union Sti s;\n printf(\"%d\", sizeof(s));\n return 0;\n }\na) 8\nb) 5\nc) 9\nd) 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 849, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n float x = 'a';\n printf(\"%f\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) a\nb) run time error\nc) a.0000000\nd) 97.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 850, "Question": "Which of the datatypes have size that is variable?\na) int\nb) struct\nc) float\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 851, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n enum {ORANGE = 5, MANGO, BANANA = 4, PEACH};\n printf(\"PEACH = %d\\n\", PEACH);\n }\na) PEACH = 3\nb) PEACH = 4\nc) PEACH = 5\nd) PEACH = 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 852, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"C programming %s\", \"Class by\\n%s Sanfoundry\", \"WOW\");\n }\na) C programming Class by\n WOW Sanfoundry\nb) C programming Class by\\n%s Sanfoundry\nc) C programming Class by\n %s Sanfoundry\nd) Compilation error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 853, "Question": "For the following code snippet:\n char *str = \"Sanfoundry.com\\0\" \"training classes\";\n The character pointer str holds reference to string:\na) Sanfoundry.com\nb) Sanfoundry.com\\0training classes\nc) Sanfoundry.comtraining classes\nd) Invalid declaration", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 854, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n #define a 10\n int main()\n {\n const int a = 5;\n printf(\"a = %d\\n\", a);\n }\na) a = 5\nb) a = 10\nc) Compilation error\nd) Runtime error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 855, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int var = 010;\n printf(\"%d\", var);\n }\na) 2\nb) 8\nc) 9\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 856, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n enum birds {SPARROW, PEACOCK, PARROT};\n enum animals {TIGER = 8, LION, RABBIT, ZEBRA};\n int main()\n {\n enum birds m = TIGER;\n int k;\n k = m;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) Compile time error\nc) 1\nd) 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 857, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n #define MAX 2\n enum bird {SPARROW = MAX + 1, PARROT = SPARROW + MAX};\n int main()\n {\n enum bird b = PARROT;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", b);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compilation error\nb) 5\nc) Undefined value\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 858, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n #include <string.h>\n int main()\n {\n char *str = \"x\";\n char c = 'x';\n char ary[1];\n ary[0] = c;\n printf(\"%d %d\", strlen(str), strlen(ary));\n return 0;\n }\na) 1 1\nb) 2 1\nc) 2 2\nd) 1 (undefined value)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 859, "Question": "enum types are processed by\na) Compiler\nb) Preprocessor\nc) Linker\nd) Assembler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 860, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"sanfoundry\\rclass\\n\");\n return 0;\n }\na) sanfoundryclass\nb) sanfoundry\n class\nc) classundry\nd) sanfoundry", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 861, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"sanfoundry\\r\\nclass\\n\");\n return 0;\n }\na) sanfoundryclass\nb) sanfoundry\n class\nc) classundry\nd) sanfoundry", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 862, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n const int p;\n p = 4;\n printf(\"p is %d\", p);\n return 0;\n }\na) p is 4\nb) Compile time error\nc) Run time error\nd) p is followed by a garbage value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 863, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 4;\n int *const p = &k;\n int r = 3;\n p = &r;\n printf(\"%d\", p);\n }\na) Address of k\nb) Address of r\nc) Compile time error\nd) Adress of k + address of r", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 864, "Question": "Which is false?\na) Constant variables need not be defined as they are declared and can be defined later\nb) Global constant variables are initialised to zero\nc) const keyword is used to define constant values\nd) You cannot reassign a value to a constant variable", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 865, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int const k = 5;\n k++;\n printf(\"k is %d\", k);\n }\na) k is 6\nb) Error due to const succeeding int\nc) Error, because a constant variable can be changed only twice\nd) Error, because a constant variable cannot be changed", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 866, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int const print()\n {\n printf(\"Sanfoundry.com\");\n return 0;\n }\n void main()\n {\n print();\n }\na) Error because function name cannot be preceded by const\nb) Sanfoundry.com\nc) Sanfoundry.com is printed infinite times\nd) Blank screen, no output", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 867, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void foo(const int *);\n int main()\n {\n const int i = 10;\n printf(\"%d \", i);\n foo(&i);\n printf(\"%d\", i);\n \n }\n void foo(const int *i)\n {\n *i = 20;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 10 20\nc) Undefined value\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 868, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n const int i = 10;\n int *ptr = &i;\n *ptr = 20;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Compile time warning and printf displays 20\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 869, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n j = 10;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", j++);\n return 0;\n }\na) 10\nb) 11\nc) Compile time error\nd) 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 870, "Question": "Does this compile without error?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n for (int k = 0; k < 10; k++);\n return 0;\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the C standard implemented by compilers\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 871, "Question": "Does this compile without error?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int k;\n {\n int k;\n for (k = 0; k < 10; k++);\n }\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the C standard implemented by compilers", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 872, "Question": "Which of the following declaration is not supported by C?\na) String str;\nb) char *str;\nc) float str = 3e2;\nd) Both (a) and (c)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 873, "Question": "#include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n char *var = \"Advanced Training in C by Sanfoundry.com\";\n }\nWhich of the following format identifier can never be used for the variable var?\na) %f\nb) %d\nc) %c\nd) %s", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 874, "Question": "Which of the following declaration is illegal?\na) char *str = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";\nb) char str[] = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";\nc) char str[20] = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";\nd) char[] str = \"Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry\";", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 875, "Question": "Which keyword is used to prevent any changes in the variable within a C program?\na) immutable\nb) mutable\nc) const\nd) volatile", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 876, "Question": "Which of the following is not a pointer declaration?\na) char a[10];\nb) char a[] = {'1', '2', '3', '4'};\nc) char *str;\nd) char a;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 877, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 4;\n float k = 4;\n printf(\"%d\", k)\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 4\nc) 4.0000000\nd) 4.4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 878, "Question": "Which is false ?\na) A variable defined once can be defined again with different scope\nb) A single variable cannot be defined with two different types in the same scope\nc) A variable must be declared and defined at the same time\nd) A variable refers to a location in memory", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 879, "Question": "A variable declared in a function can be used in main\na) True\nb) False\nc) True if it is declared static\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 880, "Question": "The name of the variable used in one function cannot be used in another function\na) True\nb) False\nc) May be\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 881, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = -3;\n int k = i % 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) -1\nc) 1\nd) Implementation defined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 882, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 3;\n int l = i / -2;\n int k = i % -2;\n printf(\"%d %d\\n\", l, k);\n return 0;\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) -1 1\nc) 1 -1\nd) Implementation defined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 883, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 5;\n i = i / 3;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return 0;\n }\na) Implementation defined\nb) 1\nc) 3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 884, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = -5;\n i = i / 3;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return 0;\n }\na) Implementation defined\nb) -1\nc) -3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 885, "Question": "What is the value of x in this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 5 * 9 / 3 + 9;\n }\na) 3.75\nb) Depends on compiler\nc) 24\nd) 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 886, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 5.3 % 2;\n printf(\"Value of x is %d\", x);\n }\na) Value of x is 2.3\nb) Value of x is 1\nc) Value of x is 0.3\nd) Compile time error\nView Answer", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 887, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int y = 3;\n int x = 5 % 2 * 3 / 2;\n printf(\"Value of x is %d\", x);\n }\na) Value of x is 1\nb) Value of x is 2\nc) Value of x is 3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 888, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 3;\n int b = ++a + a++ + --a;\n printf(\"Value of b is %d\", b);\n }\na) Value of x is 12\nb) Value of x is 13\nc) Value of x is 10\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 889, "Question": "The precedence of arithmetic operators is (from highest to lowest)\na) %, *, /, +, -\nb) %, +, /, *, -\nc) +, -, %, *, /\nd) %, +, -, *, /", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 890, "Question": "Which of the following is not an arithmetic operation?\na) a *= 10;\nb) a /= 10;\nc) a != 10;\nd) a %= 10;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 891, "Question": "Which of the following data type will throw an error on modulus operation(%)?\na) char\nb) short\nc) int\nd) float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 892, "Question": "Which among the following are the fundamental arithmetic operators, ie, performing the desired operation can be done using that operator only?\na) +, -\nb) +, -, %\nc) +, -, *, /\nd) +, -, *, /, %", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 893, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10;\n double b = 5.6;\n int c;\n c = a + b;\n printf(\"%d\", c);\n }\na) 15\nb) 16\nc) 15.6\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 894, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 5, c = 5;\n int d;\n d = a == (b + c);\n printf(\"%d\", d);\n }\na) Syntax error\nb) 1\nc) 10\nd) 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 895, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0, z = 5;\n int a = x && y || z++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) 6\nb) 5\nc) 0\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 896, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0, z = 5;\n int a = x && y && z++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) 6\nb) 5\nc) 0\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 897, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0, z = 3;\n x > y ? printf(\"%d\", z) : return z;\n }\na) 3\nb) 1\nc) Compile time error\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 898, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 1, z = 3;\n int y = x << 3;\n printf(\" %d\\n\", y);\n }\na) -2147483648\nb) -1\nc) Run time error\nd) 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 899, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 0, y = 2, z = 3;\n int a = x & y | z;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 3\nb) 0\nc) 2\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 900, "Question": "What is the final value of j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0, j = 0;\n if (i && (j = i + 10))\n //do something\n ;\n }\na) 0\nb) 10\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on language standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 901, "Question": "What is the final value of j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 10, j = 0;\n if (i || (j = i + 10))\n //do something\n ;\n }\na) 0\nb) 20\nc) Compile time error\nd) Depends on language standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 902, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 1;\n if (i++ && (i == 1))\n printf(\"Yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"No\\n\");\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 903, "Question": "Are logical operators sequence points?\na) True\nb) False\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 904, "Question": "Does logical operators in C language are evaluated with short circuit?\na) True\nb) False\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 905, "Question": "Result of a logical or relational expression in C is\na) True or False\nb) 0 or 1\nc) 0 if expression is false and any positive number if expression is true\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 906, "Question": "What will be the value of d in the following program?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 5, c = 5;\n int d;\n d = b + c == a;\n printf(\"%d\", d);\n }\na) Syntax error\nb) 1\nc) 5\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 907, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 5, c = 3;\n b != !a;\n c = !!a;\n printf(\"%d\\t%d\", b, c);\n }\na) 5 1\nb) 0 3\nc) 5 3\nd) 1 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 908, "Question": "Which among the following is NOT a logical or relational operator?\na) !=\nb) ==\nc) ||\nd) =", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 909, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10;\n if (a == a--)\n printf(\"TRUE 1\\t\");\n a = 10;\n if (a == --a)\n printf(\"TRUE 2\\t\");\n }\na) TRUE 1\nb) TRUE 2\nc) TRUE 1 TRUE 2\nd) Compiler Dependent", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 910, "Question": "Relational operators cannot be used on:\na) structure\nb) long\nc) strings\nd) float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 911, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n float x = 0.1;\n if (x == 0.1)\n printf(\"Sanfoundry\");\n else\n printf(\"Advanced C Classes\");\n }\na) Advanced C Classes\nb) Sanfoundry\nc) Run time error\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 912, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n float x = 0.1;\n printf(\"%d, \", x);\n printf(\"%f\", x);\n }\na) 0.100000, junk value\nb) Junk value, 0.100000\nc) 0, 0.100000\nd) 0, 0.999999", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 913, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n(7 and 8 are entered)\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n float x;\n int y;\n printf(\"enter two numbers \\n\", x);\n scanf(\"%f %f\", &x, &y);\n printf(\"%f, %d\", x, y);\n }\na) 7.000000, 7\nb) Run time error\nc) 7.000000, junk\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 914, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double x = 123828749.66;\n int y = x;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n printf(\"%lf\\n\", y);\n }\na) 0, 0.0\nb) 123828749, 123828749.66\nc) 12382874, 12382874.0\nd) 123828749, 0.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 915, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 97;\n char y = x;\n printf(\"%c\\n\", y);\n }\na) a\nb) b\nc) 97\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 916, "Question": "When double is converted to float, the value is?\na) Truncated\nb) Rounded\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 917, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n unsigned int i = 23;\n signed char c = -23;\n if (i > c)\n printf(\"Yes\\n\");\n else if (i < c)\n printf(\"No\\n\");\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the operating system", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 918, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 23;\n char c = -23;\n if (i < c)\n printf(\"Yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"No\\n\");\n }\na) Yes\nb) No\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 919, "Question": "function tolower(c) defined in library works for\na) Ascii character set\nb) Unicode character set\nc) Ascii and utf-8 but not EBSIDIC character set\nd) Any character set", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 920, "Question": "What is the output of the below code considering size of short int is 2, char is 1 and int is 4 bytes?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n short int i = 20;\n char c = 97;\n printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", sizeof(i), sizeof(c), sizeof(c + i));\n return 0;\n }\na) 2, 1, 2\nb) 2, 1, 1\nc) 2, 1, 4\nd) 2, 2, 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 921, "Question": "Which type conversion is NOT accepted?\na) From char to int\nb) From float to char pointer\nc) From negative int to char\nd) From double to char", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 922, "Question": "What will be the data type of the result of the following operation?\n(float)a * (int)b / (long)c * (double)d\na) int\nb) long\nc) float\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 923, "Question": "Which of the following type-casting have chances for wrap around?\na) From int to float\nb) From int to char\nc) From char to short\nd) From char to int", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 924, "Question": "Which of the following typecasting is accepted by C?\na) Widening conversions\nb) Narrowing conversions\nc) Both\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 925, "Question": "When do you need to use type-conversions?\na) The value to be stored is beyond the max limit\nb) The value to be stored is in a form not supported by that data type\nc) To reduce the memory in use, relevant to the value\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 926, "Question": "What is the difference between the following 2 codes?\n\n #include <stdio.h> //Program 1\n int main()\n {\n int d, a = 1, b = 2;\n d = a++ + ++b;\n printf(\"%d %d %d\", d, a, b);\n }\n #include <stdio.h> //Program 2\n int main()\n {\n int d, a = 1, b = 2;\n d = a++ +++b;\n printf(\"%d %d %d\", d, a, b);\n }\na) No difference as space doesn't make any difference, values of a, b, d are same in both the case\nb) Space does make a difference, values of a, b, d are different\nc) Program 1 has syntax error, program 2 is not\nd) Program 2 has syntax error, program 1 is not", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 927, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 1, c;\n c = a++ + b;\n printf(\"%d, %d\", a, b);\n }\na) a = 1, b = 1\nb) a = 2, b = 1\nc) a = 1, b = 2\nd) a = 2, b = 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 928, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 1, d = 1;\n printf(\"%d, %d, %d\", ++a + ++a+a++, a++ + ++b, ++d + d++ + a++);\n }\na) 15, 4, 5\nb) 9, 6, 9\nc) 9, 3, 5\nd) Undefined (Compiler Dependent)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 929, "Question": "For which of the following, \"PI++;\" code will fail?\na) #define PI 3.14\nb) char *PI = \"A\";\nc) float PI = 3.14;\nd) None of the Mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 930, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 10, b = 10;\n if (a = 5)\n b--;\n printf(\"%d, %d\", a, b--);\n }\na) a = 10, b = 9\nb) a = 10, b = 8\nc) a = 5, b = 9\nd) a = 5, b = 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 931, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n int j = i++ + i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", j);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 932, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 2;\n int j = ++i + i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", j);\n }\na) 6\nb) 5\nc) 4\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 933, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 2;\n int i = i++ + i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n }\na) = operator is not a sequence point\nb) ++ operator may return value with or without side effects\nc) it can be evaluated as (i++)+i or i+(++i)\nd) Both a and b", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 934, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n int x = i++, y = ++i;\n printf(\"%d % d\\n\", x, y);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0, 2\nb) 0, 1\nc) 1, 2\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 935, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 10;\n int *p = &i;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", *p++);\n }\na) 10\nb) 11\nc) Garbage value\nd) Address of i", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 936, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 97;\n int y = sizeof(x++);\n printf(\"X is %d\", x);\n }\na) X is 97\nb) X is 98\nc) X is 99\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 937, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4, y, z;\n y = --x;\n z = x--;\n printf(\"%d%d%d\", x, y, z);\n }\na) 3 2 3\nb) 2 3 3\nc) 3 2 2\nd) 2 3 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 938, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4;\n int *p = &x;\n int *k = p++;\n int r = p - k;\n printf(\"%d\", r);\n }\na) 4\nb) 8\nc) 1\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 939, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5, b = -7, c = 0, d;\n d = ++a && ++b || ++c;\n printf(\"\\n%d%d%d%d\", a, b, c, d);\n }\na) 6 -6 0 0\nb) 6 -5 0 1\nc) -6 -6 0 1\nd) 6 -6 0 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 940, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = -5;\n int k = (a++, ++a);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n }\na) -4\nb) -5\nc) 4\nd) -3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 941, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int c = 2 ^ 3;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", c);\n }\na) 1\nb) 8\nc) 9\nd) 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 942, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n unsigned int a = 10;\n a = ~a;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\n }\na) -9\nb) -10\nc) -11\nd) 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 943, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n if (7 & 8)\n printf(\"Honesty\");\n if ((~7 & 0x000f) == 8)\n printf(\"is the best policy\\n\");\n }\na) Honesty is the best policy\nb) Honesty\nc) is the best policy\nd) No output", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 944, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 2;\n if (a >> 1)\n printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) No Output.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 945, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i, n, a = 4;\n scanf(\"%d\", &n);\n for (i = 0; i < n; i++)\n a = a * 2;\n }\na) Logical Shift left\nb) No output\nc) Arithmetic Shift right\nd) bitwise exclusive OR", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 946, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 97;\n int y = sizeof(x++);\n printf(\"x is %d\", x);\n }\na) x is 97\nb) x is 98\nc) x is 99\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 947, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4, y, z;\n y = --x;\n z = x--;\n printf(\"%d%d%d\", x, y, z);\n }\na) 3 2 3\nb) 2 2 3\nc) 3 2 2\nd) 2 3 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 948, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 4;\n int *p = &x;\n int *k = p++;\n int r = p - k;\n printf(\"%d\", r);\n }\na) 4\nb) 8\nc) 1\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 949, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5, b = -7, c = 0, d;\n d = ++a && ++b || ++c;\n printf(\"\\n%d%d%d%d\", a, b, c, d);\n }\na) 6 -6 0 0\nb) 6 -5 0 1\nc) -6 -6 0 1\nd) 6 -6 0 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 950, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = -5;\n int k = (a++, ++a);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", k);\n }\na) -3\nb) -5\nc) 4\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 951, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2;\n x = x << 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) 4\nb) 1\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the endianness of the machine", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 952, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = -2;\n x = x >> 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) 1\nb) -1\nc) 2 ^ 31 - 1 considering int to be 4 bytes\nd) Either b or c", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 953, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n if (~0 == 1)\n printf(\"yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n }\na) yes\nb) no\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 954, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = -2;\n if (!0 == 1)\n printf(\"yes\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n }\na) yes\nb) no\nc) Run time error\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 955, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 0;\n if (1 |(y = 1))\n printf(\"y is %d\\n\", y);\n else\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n \n }\na) y is 1\nb) 1\nc) Run time error\nd) Undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 956, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 1;\n if (y & (y = 2))\n printf(\"true %d\\n\", y);\n else\n printf(\"false %d\\n\", y);\n \n }\na) true 2\nb) false 2\nc) Either option a or option b\nd) true 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 957, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n if (x = 0)\n printf(\"Its zero\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"Its not zero\\n\");\n }\na) Its not zero\nb) Its zero\nc) Run time error\nd) None", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 958, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int x = 0 == 1 && k++;\n printf(\"%d%d\\n\", x, k);\n }\na) 0 9\nb) 0 8\nc) 1 8\nd) 1 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 959, "Question": ". What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n char a = 'a';\n int x = (a % 10)++;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) 6\nb) Junk value\nc) Compile time error\nd) 7", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 960, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n 1 < 2 ? return 1: return 2;\n }\na) returns 1\nb) returns 2\nc) Varies\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 961, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n unsigned int x = -5;\n printf(\"%d\", x);\n }\na) Run time error\nb) Aries\nc) -5\nd) 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 962, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 1;\n x *= x + y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) 5\nb) 6\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 963, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 2;\n x /= x / y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n return 0;\n }\na) 2\nb) 1\nc) 0.5\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 964, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 0;\n x &&= y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 1\nc) 0\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 965, "Question": "What is the type of the below assignment expression if x is of type float, y is of type int?\n y = x + y;\na) int\nb) float\nc) There is no type for an assignment expression\nd) double", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 966, "Question": "What is the value of the below assignment expression\n (x = foo())!= 1 considering foo() returns 2\na) 2\nb) True\nc) 1\nd) 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 967, "Question": "Operation \"a = a * b + a\" can also be written as:\na) a *= b + 1;\nb) (c = a * b)!=(a = c + a);\nc) a = (b + 1)* a;\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 968, "Question": "for c = 2, value of c after c <<= 1; a) c = 1; b) c = 2; c) c = 3; d) c = 4; [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:d [/expand] 5. What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 2;\n a += b -= a;\n printf(\"%d %d\", a, b);\n }\na) 1 1\nb) 1 2\nc) 2 1\nd) 2 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 969, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 4, n, i, result = 0;\n scanf(\"%d\", n);\n for (i = 0;i < n; i++)\n result += a;\n }\na) Addition of a and n.\nb) Subtraction of a and n.\nc) Multiplication of a and n.\nd) Division of a and n.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 970, "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid assignment operator?\na) a %= 10;\nb) a /= 10;\nc) a |= 10;\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 971, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = (y++) ? y == 1 && x : 0;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 972, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1;\n int y = x == 1 ? getchar(): 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Whatever character getchar function returns\nc) Ascii value of character getchar function returns\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 973, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1;\n short int i = 2;\n float f = 3;\n if (sizeof((x == 2) ? f : i) == sizeof(float))\n printf(\"float\\n\");\n else if (sizeof((x == 2) ? f : i) == sizeof(short int))\n printf(\"short int\\n\");\n }\na) float\nb) short int\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 974, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 2;\n int b = 0;\n int y = (b == 0) ? a :(a > b) ? (b = 1): a;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", y);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 975, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 1, x = 0;\n int l = (y++, x++) ? y : x;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", l);\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 976, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n int z = k < m ? k++ : m++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) 7\nb) 8\nc) Run time error\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 977, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n int z = k < m ? k = m : m++;\n printf(\"%d\", z);\n }\na) Run time error\nb) 7\nc) 8\nd) Depends on compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 978, "Question": "The code snippet below produces\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n 1 < 2 ? return 1 : return 2;\n }\na) returns 1\nb) returns 2\nc) Varies\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 979, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n k < m ? k++ : m = k;\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\na) 7\nb) 8\nc) Compile time error\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 980, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 8;\n int m = 7;\n k < m ? k = k + 1 : m = m + 1;\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 9\nc) 8\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 981, "Question": "For initialization a = 2, c = 1 the value of a and c after this code will be\n c = (c) ? a = 0 : 2;\na) a = 0, c = 0;\nb) a = 2, c = 2;\nc) a = 2, c = 2;\nd) a = 1, c = 2;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 982, "Question": "What will be the data type of the expression (a < 50) ? var1 : var2; provided a = int, var1 = double, var2 = float a) int b) float c) double d) Cannot be determined [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:c [/expand] 5. Which expression has to be present in the following? exp1 ? exp2 : exp3; a) exp1 b) exp2 c) exp3 d) All of the mentioned [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:d [/expand] 6. Value of c after the following expression (initializations a = 1, b = 2, c = 1): c += (-c) ? a : b; a) Syntax Error b) c = 1 c) c = 2 d) c = 3 [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:c [/expand] 7. Comment on the following expression? c = (n) ? a : b; can be rewritten as a) if (!n)c = b; else c = a; b) if (n <= 0)c = b; else c = a; c) if (n > 0)c = a;\n else c = b;\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 983, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n reverse(1);\n }\n void reverse(int i)\n {\n if (i > 5)\n exit(0);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n return reverse(i++);\n }\na) 1 2 3 4 5\nb) 1 2 3 4\nc) Compile time error\nd) Stack overflow", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 984, "Question": ". What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void reverse(int i);\n int main()\n {\n reverse(1);\n }\n void reverse(int i)\n {\n if (i > 5)\n return ;\n printf(\"%d \", i);\n return reverse((i++, i));\n }\na) 1 2 3 4 5\nb) Segmentation fault\nc) Compilation error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 985, "Question": "In expression i = g() + f(), first function called depends on\na) Compiler\nb) Associativiy of () operator\nc) Precedence of () and + operator\nd) Left to write of the expression", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 986, "Question": "What is the value of i and j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int x = 0;\n int main()\n {\n int i = (f() + g()) || g();\n int j = g() || (f() + g());\n }\n int f()\n {\n if (x == 0)\n return x + 1;\n else\n return x - 1;\n }\n int g()\n {\n return x++;\n }\na)i value is 1 and j value is 1\nb)i value is 0 and j value is 0\nc)i value is 1 and j value is undefined\nd)i and j value are undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 987, "Question": "What is the value of i and j in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int x = 0;\n int main()\n {\n int i = (f() + g()) | g(); //bitwise or\n int j = g() | (f() + g()); //bitwise or\n }\n int f()\n {\n if (x == 0)\n return x + 1;\n else\n return x - 1;\n }\n int g()\n {\n return x++;\n }\na) i value is 1 and j value is 1\nb) i value is 0 and j value is 0\nc) i value is 1 and j value is undefined\nd) i and j value are undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 988, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = y && (y |= 10);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 1\nb) 0\nc) Undefined behaviour due to order of evaluation\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 989, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = (y++) ? 2 : y == 1 && x;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd)Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 990, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z;\n z = (y++, y);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compilation error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 991, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0, l;\n int z;\n z = y = 1, l = x && y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", l);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Undefined behaviour due to order of evaluation can be different\nd) Compilation error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 992, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int y = 2;\n int z = y +(y = 10);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 12\nb) 20\nc) 4\nd) Either 12 or 20", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 993, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int b = 5 - 4 + 2 * 5;\n printf(\"%d\", b);\n }\na) 25\nb) -5\nc) 11\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 994, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int b = 5 & 4 & 6;\n printf(\"%d\", b);\n }\na) 5\nb) 6\nc) 3\nd) 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 995, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int b = 5 & 4 | 6;\n printf(\"%d\", b);\n }\na) 6\nb) 4\nc) 1\nd) 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 996, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int b = 5 + 7 * 4 - 9 * (3, 2);\n printf(\"%d\", b);\n }\na) 6\nb) 15\nc) 13\nd) 21", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 997, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int h = 8;\n int b = (h++, h++);\n printf(\"%d%d\\n\", b, h);\n }\na) 10 10\nb) 10 9\nc) 9 10\nd) 8 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 998, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int h = 8;\n int b = h++ + h++ + h++;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", h);\n }\na) 9\nb) 10\nc) 12\nd) 11", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 999, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int h = 8;\n int b = 4 * 6 + 3 * 4 < 3 ? 4 : 3;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", b);\n }\na) 3\nb) 33\nc) 34\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1000, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 2 + 3 - 4 + 8 - 5 % 4;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\n }\na) 0\nb) 8\nc) 11\nd) 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1001, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n char a = '0';\n char b = 'm';\n int c = a && b || '1';\n printf(\"%d\\n\", c);\n }\na) 0\nb) a\nc) 1\nd) m", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1002, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n char a = 'A';\n char b = 'B';\n int c = a + b % 3 - 3 * 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", c);\n }\na) 65\nb) 58\nc) 64\nd) 59", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1003, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 2;\n float f = y + x /= x / y;\n printf(\"%d %f\\n\", x, f);\n return 0;\n }\na) 2 4.000000\nb) Compile time error\nc) 2 3.500000\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1004, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 2;\n if (x && y == 1)\n printf(\"true\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"false\\n\");\n }\na) true\nb) false\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1005, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1, y = 2;\n int z = x & y == 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1006, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3, y = 2;\n int z = x /= y %= 2;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 1\nb) Compile time error\nc) Floating point exception\nd) Segmentation fault", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1007, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3, y = 2;\n int z = x << 1 > 5;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 1\nb) 0\nc) 3\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1008, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3; //, y = 2;\n const int *p = &x;\n *p++;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", *p);\n }\na) Increment of read-only location compile error\nb) 4\nc) Some garbage value\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1009, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 2;\n int z = x ^ y & 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) 0\nd) 1 or 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1010, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 2, y = 0;\n int z = x && y = 1;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) 0\nb) 1\nc) Compile time error\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1011, "Question": "What is the output of the code given below\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0, y = 2;\n if (!x && y)\n printf(\"true\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"false\\n\");\n }\na) true\nb) false\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1012, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0, y = 2;\n int z = ~x & y;\n printf(\"%d\\n\", z);\n }\na) -1\nb) 2\nc) 0\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1013, "Question": "Which of the following operators has an associativity from Right to Left?\na) <= b) << c) == d) += [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:d [/expand] 2. Which operators of the following have same precedence? P. \"!=\", Q. \"+=\", R. \"<<=\" a) P and Q b) Q and R c) P and R d) P, Q and R [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:b [/expand] 3. Comment on the following statement? n = 1; printf(\"%d, %dn\", 3*n, n++); a) Output will be 3, 2 b) Output will be 3, 1 c) Output will be 6, 1 d) Output is compiler dependent [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:d [/expand] 4. Which of the following option is the correct representation of the following code? e = a * b + c / d * f; a) e = (a * (b +(c /(d * f)))); b) e = ((a * b) + (c / (d * f))); c) e = ((a * b) + ((c / d)* f)); d) Both (B) and (C); [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:d Explanation:Verified by e = 1 * 2 + 3 / 4 * 5; and then using respective braces according to the option.[/expand] 5. What care must be taken during swapping 2 numbers? b = (b / a); a = a * b; b = a / b; a) Data type should be either of short, int and long b) Data type should be either of float and double c) All data types are accepted except for (char *). d) This code doesn't swap 2 numbers. [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:b [/expand] 6. What should be the output of the following program:\n\n #include<stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 2, c = 3, d = 4, e;\n e = c + d = b * a;\n printf(\"%d, %d\\n\", e, d);\n }\na) 7, 4\nb) 7, 2\nc) 5, 2\nd) Syntax error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1014, "Question": "Which of the following is the correct order of evaluation for the given expression?\n a = w % x / y * z;\na) % / * =\nb) / * % =\nc) = % * /\nd) * % / =", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1015, "Question": "Which function in the following expression will be called first?\n a = func3(6) - func2(4, 5) / func1(1, 2, 3);\na) func1();\nb) func2();\nc) func3();\nd) Cannot be predicted.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1016, "Question": "Which of the following operator has the highest precedence in the following?\na) ()\nb) sizeof\nc) *\nd) +", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1017, "Question": "Which of the following is a ternary operator?\na) &&\nb) >>=\nc) ?:\nd) ->", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1018, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5 * 3 + 2 - 4;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 13\nb) 14\nc) 12\nd) 1 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1019, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 2 + 4 + 3 * 5 / 3 - 5;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 7\nb) 6\nc) 10\nd) 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1020, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int a = 5 * 3 % 6 - 8 + 3;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) 10\nb) 2\nc) -2\nd) -3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1021, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int b = 6;\n int c = 7;\n int a = ++b + c--;\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) Run time error\nb) 15\nc) 13\nd) 14", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1022, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main(\n {\n double b = 8;\n b++;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 9.000000\nb) 9\nc) 9.0\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1023, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 3 % 0 * 1 - 4 / 2;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) -2\nb) Floating point Exception\nc) 1\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1024, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 5 % 3 & 4 + 5 * 6;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 2\nb) 30\nc) 2.000000\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1025, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 3 && 5 & 4 % 3;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 3.000000\nb) 4.000000\nc) 5.000000\nd) 1.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1026, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double b = 5 & 3 && 4 || 5 | 6;\n printf(\"%lf\", b);\n }\na) 1.000000\nb) 0.000000\nc) 7.000000\nd) 2.000000", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1027, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 0;\n double b = k++ + ++k + k--;\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\na) 6\nb) 1\nc) 5\nd) undefined", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1028, "Question": "Which of the following are unary operators?\na) sizeof\nb) -\nc) ++\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1029, "Question": "Where in C the order of precedence of operators do not exist?\na) Within conditional statements, if, else\nb) Within while, do-while\nc) Within macro definition\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1030, "Question": "Associativity of an operator are:\na) Right to Left\nb) Left to Right\nc) Random fashion\nd) Both (a) and (b)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1031, "Question": "Which of the following method are accepted for assignment?\na) 5 = a = b = c = d;\nb) a = b = c = d = 5;\nc) a = b = 5 = c = d;\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1032, "Question": "Which of the following is NOT possible with any 2 operators in C?\na) Different precedence, same associativity\nb) Different precedence, different associativity\nc) Same precedence, different associativity.\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1033, "Question": "Which of the following is possible with any 2 operators in C?\na) Same associativity, different precedence\nb) Same associativity, same precedence\nc) Different associativity, different precedence\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1034, "Question": "Which of the following operators has the lowest precedence?\na) !=\nb) &&\nc) ?:\nd) ,", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1035, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 3, i = 0;\n do {\n x = x++;\n i++;\n } while (i != 3);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) Undefined behaviour\nb) Output will be 3\nc) Output will be 6\nd) Output will be 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1036, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = -1, b = 4, c = 1, d;\n d = ++a && ++b || ++c;\n printf(\"%d, %d, %d, %d\\n\", a, b, c, d);\n return 0;\n }\na) 0, 4, 2, 1\nb) 0, 5, 2, 1\nc) -1, 4, 1, 1\nd) 0, 5, 1, 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1037, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int p = 10, q = 20, r;\n if (r = p = 5 || q > 20)\n printf(\"%d\", r);\n else\n printf(\"No Output\\n\");\n }\na) 1\nb) 10\nc) 20\nd) No Output", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1038, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 5;\n if (x < 1)\n printf(\"hello\");\n if (x == 5)\n printf(\"hi\");\n else\n printf(\"no\");\n }\na) hi\nb) hello\nc) no\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1039, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int x;\n void main()\n {\n if (x)\n printf(\"hi\");\n else\n printf(\"how are u\");\n }\na) hi\nb) how are you\nc) Compile time error\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1040, "Question": "Comment on the following code below\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 5;\n if (true);\n printf(\"hello\");\n }\na) It will display hello\nb) It will throw an error\nc) Nothing will be displayed\nd) Compiler dependent", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1041, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n if (x == 0)\n printf(\"hi\");\n else\n printf(\"how are u\");\n printf(\"hello\");\n }\na) hi\nb) how are you\nc) hello\nd) hihello", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1042, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int x = 5;\n if (x < 1);\n printf(\"Hello\");\n \n }\na) Nothing\nb) Run time error\nc) Hello\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1043, "Question": "The output of the code below is(when 1 is entered)\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%lf\", &ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\");\n break;\n case 2:\n printf(\"2\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1044, "Question": "The output of the code below is(When 1 is entered)\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n char *ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 3:\");\n scanf(\"%s\", ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case \"1\":\n printf(\"1\");\n break;\n case \"2\":\n printf(\"2\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) Compile time error\nd) No Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1045, "Question": "When 1 is entered, The output of the code below is?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%d\", &ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\\n\");\n default:\n printf(\"2\\n\");\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) 1 2\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1046, "Question": "When 2 is entered, The output of the code below is?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%d\", &ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\\n\");\n break;\n printf(\"Hi\");\n default:\n printf(\"2\\n\");\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) Hi 2\nc) Run time error\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1047, "Question": ". When 1 is entered, The output of the code below is?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%d\", &ch);\n switch (ch, ch + 1)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\\n\");\n break;\n case 2:\n printf(\"2\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) 3\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1048, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1;\n if (x > 0)\n printf(\"inside if\\n\");\n else if (x > 0)\n printf(\"inside elseif\\n\");\n }\na) inside if\nb) inside elseif\nc) inside if\n inside elseif\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1049, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n if (x++)\n printf(\"true\\n\");\n else if (x == 1)\n printf(\"false\\n\");\n }\na) true\nb) false\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1050, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n if (x == 1)\n if (x == 0)\n printf(\"inside if\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"inside else if\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"inside else\\n\");\n }\na) inside if\nb) inside else if\nc) inside else\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1051, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n if (x == 0)\n printf(\"true, \");\n else if (x = 10)\n printf(\"false, \");\n printf(\"%d\\n\", x);\n }\na) false, 0\nb) true, 0\nc) true, 10\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1052, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n if (x == 1)\n if (x >= 0)\n printf(\"true\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"false\\n\");\n }\na) true\nb) false\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) No print statement", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1053, "Question": "if (a == 1||b == 2){} can be written as:\na) if (a == 1)\n if (b == 2){}\nb) if (a == 1){}\n if (b == 2){}\nc) if (a == 1){}\n else if (b == 2){}\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1054, "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid if-else statement?\na) if (if (a == 1)){}\nb) if (func1 (a)){}\nc) if (a){}\nd) if ((char) a){}", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1055, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1;\n if (a--)\n printf(\"True\");\n if (a++)\n printf(\"False\");\n }\na) True\nb) False\nc) True False\nd) No Output", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1056, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1;\n if (a)\n printf(\"All is Well \");\n printf(\"I am Well\\n\");\n else\n printf(\"I am not a River\\n\");\n }\na) Output will be All is Well I am Well\nb) Output will be I am Well I am not a River\nc) Output will be I am Well\nd) Compile time errors during compilation", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1057, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n if (printf(\"%d\", printf(\")))\n printf(\"We are Happy\");\n else if (printf(\"1\"))\n printf(\"We are Sad\");\n }\na) 0We are Happy\nb) 1We are Happy\nc) 1We are Sad\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1058, "Question": "What is the output of this C code(when 1 is entered)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%lf\", &ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\");\n break;\n case 2:\n printf(\"2\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 1\nc) 2\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1059, "Question": "What is the output of this C code(When 1 is entered)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n char *ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 3:\");\n scanf(\"%s\", ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case \"1\":\n printf(\"1\");\n break;\n case \"2\":\n printf(\"2\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) Compile time error\nc) 2\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1060, "Question": "What is the output of this C code(When 1 is entered)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%d\", &ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\\n\");\n default:\n printf(\"2\\n\");\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) 1 2\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1061, "Question": "What is the output of this C code(When 2 is entered)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%d\", &ch);\n switch (ch)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\\n\");\n break;\n printf(\"hi\");\n default:\n printf(\"2\\n\");\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) hi 2\nc) Run time error\nd) 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1062, "Question": "What is the output of this C code(When 1 is entered)?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int ch;\n printf(\"enter a value btw 1 to 2:\");\n scanf(\"%d\", &ch);\n switch (ch, ch + 1)\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"1\\n\");\n break;\n case 2:\n printf(\"2\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) 3\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1063, "Question": ". What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1, b = 1;\n switch (a)\n {\n case a*b:\n printf(\"yes \");\n case a-b:\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) yes\nb) no\nc) Compile time error\nd) yes no", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1064, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int x = 97;\n switch (x)\n {\n case 'a':\n printf(\"yes \");\n break;\n case 97:\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) yes\nb) yes no\nc) Duplicate case value error\nd) Character case value error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1065, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n float f = 1;\n switch (f)\n {\n case 1.0:\n printf(\"yes\\n\");\n break;\n default:\n printf(\"default\\n\");\n }\n }\na) yes\nb) yes default\nc) Undefined behaviour\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1066, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n const int a = 1, b = 2;\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1;\n switch (x)\n {\n case a:\n printf(\"yes \");\n case b:\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) yes no\nb) yes\nc) no\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1067, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n #define max(a) a\n int main()\n {\n int x = 1;\n switch (x)\n {\n case max(2):\n printf(\"yes\\n\");\n case max(1):\n printf(\"no\\n\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) yes no\nb) yes\nc) no\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1068, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n switch (printf(\"Do\"))\n {\n case 1:\n printf(\"First\\n\");\n break;\n case 2:\n printf(\"Second\\n\");\n break;\n default:\n printf(\"Default\\n\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) Do\nb) DoFirst\nc) DoSecond\nd) DoDefault", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1069, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1;\n switch (a)\n case 1:\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n case 2:\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n case 3:\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n default:\n printf(\"%d\", a);\n }\na) No error, output is 1111\nb) No error, output is 1\nc) Compile time error, no break statements\nd) Compile time error, case label outside switch statement", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1070, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 1;\n switch (a)\n {\n case a:\n printf(\"Case A \");\n default:\n printf(\"Default\");\n }\n }\na) Output: Case A\nb) Output: Default\nc) Output: Case A Default\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1071, "Question": "Comment on the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n switch (ch)\n {\n case 'a':\n case 'A':\n printf(\"true\");\n }\na) if (ch == 'a' && ch == 'A') printf(\"true\");\nb) if (ch == 'a')\n if (ch == 'a') printf(\"true\");\nc) if (ch == 'a' || ch == 'A') printf(\"true\");\nd) Both a and b", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1072, "Question": "The following code 'for(;;)' represents an infinite loop. It can be terminated by.\na) break\nb) exit(0)\nc) abort()\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1073, "Question": "The correct syntax for running two variable for loop simultaneously is.\na) for (i = 0; i < n; i++) for (j = 0; j < n; j += 5) b) for (i = 0, j = 0;i < n, j < n; i++, j += 5) c) for (i = 0; i < n;i++){} for (j = 0; j < n;j += 5){} d) None of the mentioned [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:b [/expand] 3. Which for loop has range of similar indexes of 'i' used in for (i = 0;i < n; i++)? a) for (i = n; i>0; i-)\nb) for (i = n; i >= 0; i-)\nc) for (i = n-1; i>0; i-)\nd) for (i = n-1; i>-1; i-)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1074, "Question": "Which of the following cannot be used as LHS of the expression in for (exp1;exp2; exp3) ?\na) Variable\nb) Function\nc) typedef\nd) macros", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1075, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n short i;\n for (i = 1; i >= 0; i++)\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n \n }\na) The control won't fall into the for loop\nb) Numbers will be displayed until the signed limit of short and throw a runtime error\nc) Numbers will be displayed until the signed limit of short and program will successfully terminate\nd) This program will get into an infinite loop and keep printing numbers with no errors", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1076, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 0;\n for (k)\n printf(\"Hello\");\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) hello\nc) Nothing\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1077, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = 0;\n for (k < 3; k++)\n printf(\"Hello\");\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Hello is printed thrice\nc) Nothing\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1078, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double k = 0;\n for (k = 0.0; k < 3.0; k++)\n printf(\"Hello\");\n }\na) Run time error\nb) Hello is printed thrice\nc) Hello is printed twice\nd) Hello is printed infinitely", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1079, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n double k = 0;\n for (k = 0.0; k < 3.0; k++);\n printf(\"%lf\", k);\n }\na) 2.000000\nb) 4.000000\nc) 3.000000\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1080, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k;\n for (k = -3; k < -5; k++)\n printf(\"Hello\");\n }\na) Hello\nb) Infinite hello\nc) Run time error\nd) Nothing", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1081, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n for (; ; ;)\n printf(\"In for loop\\n\");\n printf(\"After loop\\n\");\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Infinite loop\nc) After loop\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1082, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n for (i++; i == 1; i = 2)\n printf(\"In for loop \");\n printf(\"After loop\\n\");\n }\na) In for loop after loop\nb) After loop\nc) Compile time error\nd) Undefined behaviour", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1083, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n for (foo(); i == 1; i = 2)\n printf(\"In for loop\\n\");\n printf(\"After loop\\n\");\n }\n int foo()\n {\n return 1;\n }\na) After loop\nb) In for loop after loop\nc) Compile time error\nd) Infinite loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1084, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int *p = NULL;\n for (foo(); p; p = 0)\n printf(\"In for loop\\n\");\n printf(\"After loop\\n\");\n }\na) In for loop after loop\nb) Compile time error\nc) Infinite loop\nd) Depends on the value of NULL", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1085, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n for (int i = 0;i < 1; i++)\n printf(\"In for loop\\n\");\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) In for loop\nc) Depends on the standard compiler implements\nd) Depends on the compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1086, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n while ()\n printf(\"In while loop \");\n printf(\"After loop\\n\");\n }\na) In while loop after loop\nb) After loop\nc) Compile time error\nd) Infinite loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1087, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n do\n printf(\"In while loop \");\n while (0);\n printf(\"After loop\\n\");\n }\na) In while loop\nb) In while loop\nafter loop\nc) After loop\nd) Infinite loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1088, "Question": "#include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n do {\n i++;\n printf(\"In while loop\\n\");\n } while (i < 3);\n }\na) In while loop\nIn while loop\nIn while loop\nb) In while loop\nIn while loop\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1089, "Question": "How many times i value is checked in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n do {\n i++;\n printf(\"in while loop\\n\");\n } while (i < 3);\n }\na) 2\nb) 3\nc) 4\nd) 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1090, "Question": "How many times i value is checked in the below code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n while (i < 3)\n i++;\n printf(\"In while loop\\n\");\n }\na) 2\nb) 3\nc) 4\nd) 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1091, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 2;\n do\n {\n printf(\"Hi\");\n } while (i < 2)\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) Hi Hi\nc) Hi\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1092, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n while (++i)\n {\n printf(\"H\");\n }\n }\na) H\nb) H is printed infinite times\nc) Compile time error\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1093, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n do\n {\n printf(\"Hello\");\n } while (i != 0);\n }\na) Nothing\nb) H is printed infinite times\nc) Hello\nd) Run time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1094, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n char *str = \"\";\n do\n {\n printf(\"hello\");\n } while (str);\n }\na) Nothing\nb) Run time error\nc) Varies\nd) Hello is printed infinite times", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1095, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n#include <stdio.h>\nvoid main()\n{\n int i = 0;\n while (i < 10)\n {\n i++;\n printf(\"hi\\n\");\n while (i < 8) {\n i++;\n printf(\"hello\\n\");\n }\n }\n}\na) Hi is printed 8 times, hello 7 times and then hi 2 times\nb) Hi is printed 10 times, hello 7 times\nc) Hi is printed once, hello 7 times\nd) Hi is printed once, hello 7 times and then hi 2 times", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1096, "Question": "Example of iteration in C.\na) for\nb) while\nc) do-while\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1097, "Question": "Number of times while loop condition is tested is, i is initialized to 0 in both case.\n while (i < n) i++; ------------- do i++; while (i <= n); a) n, n b) n, n+1 c) n+1, n d) n+1, n+1 [expand title=\"View Answer\"] Answer:d [/expand] 5. What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n while (i = 0)\n printf(\"True\\n\");\n printf(\"False\\n\");\n }\na) True (infinite time)\nb) True (1 time) False\nc) False\nd) Compiler dependent", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1098, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0, j = 0;\n while (i < 5, j < 10)\n {\n i++;\n j++;\n }\n printf(\"%d, %d\\n\", i, j);\n }\na) 5, 5\nb) 5, 10\nc) 10, 10\nd) Syntax error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1099, "Question": "Which loop is most suitable to first perform the operation and then test the condition?\na) for loop\nb) while loop\nc) do-while loop\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1100, "Question": "Which keyword can be used for coming out of recursion?\na) break\nb) return\nc) exit\nd) Both (a) and (b)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1101, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 0, i = 0, b;\n for (i = 0;i < 5; i++)\n {\n a++;\n continue;\n }\n }\na) 2\nb) 3\nc) 4\nd) 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1102, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int a = 0, i = 0, b;\n for (i = 0;i < 5; i++)\n {\n a++;\n if (i == 3)\n break;\n }\n }\na) 1\nb) 2\nc) 3\nd) 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1103, "Question": "The keyword 'break' cannot be simply used within:\na) do-while\nb) if-else\nc) for\nd) while", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1104, "Question": "Which keyword is used to come out of a loop only for that iteration?\na) break\nb) continue\nc) return\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1105, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 0, j = 0;\n for (i = 0;i < 5; i++)\n {\n for (j = 0;j < 4; j++)\n {\n if (i > 1)\n break;\n }\n printf(\"Hi \\n\");\n }\n }\na) Hi is printed 5 times\nb) Hi is printed 9 times\nc) Hi is printed 7 times\nd) Hi is printed 4 times", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1106, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n int j = 0;\n for (i = 0;i < 5; i++)\n {\n for (j = 0;j < 4; j++)\n {\n if (i > 1)\n continue;\n printf(\"Hi \\n\");\n }\n }\n }\na) Hi is printed 9 times\nb) Hi is printed 8 times\nc) Hi is printed 7 times\nd) Hi is printed 6 times", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1107, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n for (i = 0;i < 5; i++)\n if (i < 4)\n {\n printf(\"Hello\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) Hello is printed 5 times\nb) Hello is printed 4 times\nc) Hello\nd) Hello is printed 3 times", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1108, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n if (i == 0)\n {\n printf(\"Hello\");\n continue;\n }\n }\na) Hello is printed infinite times\nb) Hello\nc) Varies\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1109, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n if (i == 0)\n {\n printf(\"Hello\");\n break;\n }\n }\na) Hello is printed infinite times\nb) Hello\nc) Varies\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1110, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n do\n {\n i++;\n if (i == 2)\n continue;\n printf(\"In while loop \");\n } while (i < 2);\n printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n }\na) In while loop 2\nb) In while loop in while loop 3\nc) In while loop 3\nd) Infinite loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1111, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0, j = 0;\n for (i; i < 2; i++){\n for (j = 0; j < 3; j++){\n printf(\"1\\n\");\n break;\n }\n printf(\"2\\n\");\n }\n printf(\"after loop\\n\");\n }\na) 1\n 2\n after loop\nb) 1\n after loop\nc) 1\n 2\n 1\n 2\n after loop\nd) 1\n 1\n 2\n after loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1112, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n while (i < 2)\n {\n if (i == 1)\n break;\n i++;\n if (i == 1)\n continue;\n printf(\"In while loop\\n\");\n }\n printf(\"After loop\\n\");\n }\na) In while loop\n After loop\nb) After loop\nc) In while loop\n In while loop\n After loop\nd) In while loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1113, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n int i = 0;\n char c = 'a';\n while (i < 2){\n i++;\n switch (c) {\n case 'a':\n printf(\"%c \", c);\n break;\n break;\n }\n }\n printf(\"after loop\\n\");\n }\na) a after loop\nb) a a after loop\nc) after loop\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1114, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n printf(\"before continue \");\n continue;\n printf(\"after continue\\n\");\n }\na) Before continue after continue\nb) Before continue\nc) After continue\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1115, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n void foo();\n printf(\"1 \");\n foo();\n }\n void foo()\n {\n printf(\"2 \");\n }\na) 1 2\nb) Compile time error\nc) 1 2 1 2\nd) Depends on the compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1116, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n void foo(), f();\n f();\n }\n void foo()\n {\n printf(\"2 \");\n }\n void f()\n {\n printf(\"1 \");\n foo();\n }\na) Compile time error as foo is local to main\nb) 1 2\nc) 2 1\nd) Compile time error due to declaration of functions inside main", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1117, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int main()\n {\n void foo();\n void f()\n {\n foo();\n }\n f();\n }\n void foo()\n {\n printf(\"2 \");\n }\na) 2 2\nb) 2\nc) Compile time error\nd) Depends on the compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1118, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void foo();\n int main()\n {\n void foo();\n foo();\n return 0;\n }\n void foo()\n {\n printf(\"2 \");\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) 2\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1119, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void foo();\n int main()\n {\n void foo(int);\n foo(1);\n return 0;\n }\n void foo(int i)\n {\n printf(\"2 \");\n }\na) 2\nb) Compile time error\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1120, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void foo();\n int main()\n {\n void foo(int);\n foo();\n return 0;\n }\n void foo()\n {\n printf(\"2 \");\n }\na) 2\nb) Compile time error\nc) Depends on the compiler\nd) Depends on the standard", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1121, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n include <stdio.h>\n void m()\n {\n printf(\"hi\");\n }\n void main()\n {\n m();\n }\na) hi\nb) Run time error\nc) Nothing\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1122, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void m();\n void n()\n {\n m();\n }\n void main()\n {\n void m()\n {\n printf(\"hi\");\n }\n }\na) hi\nb) Compile time error\nc) Nothing\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1123, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n m();\n void m()\n {\n printf(\"hi\");\n }\n }\na) hi\nb) Compile time error\nc) Nothing\nd) Varies", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1124, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n m();\n }\n void m()\n {\n printf(\"hi\");\n m();\n }\na) Compile time error\nb) hi\nc) Infinite hi\nd) Nothing", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1125, "Question": "What is the output of this C code?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n static int x = 3;\n x++;\n if (x <= 5)\n {\n printf(\"hi\");\n main();\n }\n }\na) Run time error\nb) hi\nc) Infinite hi\nd) hi hi", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1126, "Question": "Which of the following is a correct format for declaration of function?\na) return-type function-name(argument type);\nb) return-type function-name(argument type)\n{}\nc) return-type (argument type)function-name;\nd) Both (a) and (b)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1127, "Question": "Which of the following function declaration is illegal?\na) int 1bhk(int);\nb) int 1bhk(int a);\nc) int 2bhk(int*, int []);\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1128, "Question": "Which function definition will run correctly?\na) int sum(int a, int b)\n return (a + b);\nb) int sum(int a, int b)\n {return (a + b);}\nc) int sum(a, b)\n return (a + b);\nd) Both (a) and (b)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1129, "Question": "Can we use a function as a parameter of another function? [ Eg: void wow(int func()) ] a) Yes, and we can use the function value conveniently\nb) Yes, but we call the function again to get the value, not as convenient as in using variable\nc) No, C does not support it.\nd) This case is compiler dependent", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1130, "Question": "The value obtained in the function is given back to main by using ________ keyword?\na) return\nb) static\nc) new\nd) volatile", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1131, "Question": "What is the return-type of the function sqrt()\na) int\nb) float\nc) double\nd) Depends on the data type of the parameter", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1132, "Question": "Which of the following function declaration is illegal?\na) double func();\n int main(){}\n double func(){}\nb) double func(){};\n int main(){}\nc) int main()\n {\n double func();\n }\n double func(){//statements}\nd) None of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1133, "Question": "What is the output of this code having void return-type function?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void foo()\n {\n return 1;\n }\n void main()\n {\n int x = 0;\n x = foo();\n printf(\"%d\", x);\n }\na) 1\nb) 0\nc) Runtime error\nd) Compile time error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1134, "Question": "What will be the data type returned for the following function?\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int func()\n {\n return (double)(char)5.0;\n }\na) char\nb) int\nc) double\nd) multiple type-casting in return is illegal", "Choices": [], "Answer": "b "}, {"ID": 1135, "Question": "What is the problem in the following declarations?\n int func(int);\n double func(int);\n int func(float);\na) A function with same name cannot have different signatures\nb) A function with same name cannot have different return types\nc) A function with same name cannot have different number of parameters\nd) All of the mentioned", "Choices": [], "Answer": "d "}, {"ID": 1136, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n void main()\n {\n int k = m();\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\n void m()\n {\n printf(\"hello\");\n }\na) hello 5\nb) Error\nc) Nothing\nd) Junk value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1137, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int *m()\n {\n int *p = 5;\n return p;\n }\n void main()\n {\n int *k = m();\n printf(\"%d\", k);\n }\na) 5\nb) Junk value\nc) 0\nd) Error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a "}, {"ID": 1138, "Question": "The output of the code below is\n\n #include <stdio.h>\n int *m();\n void main()\n {\n int *k = m();\n printf(\"hello \");\n printf(\"%d\", k[0]);\n }\n int *m()\n {\n int a[2] = {5, 8};\n return a;\n }\na) hello 5 8\nb) hello 5\nc) hello followed by garbage value\nd) Compilation error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "c "}, {"ID": 1139, "Question": "Once the function ends, the control is returned back to the ... function and execution continues from the statement immediately after the function call\na. executing\nb.called\nc.declared\nd.calling", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1140, "Question": "what number is equivalent to -4e3?\na.-4000\nb.-400\nc..004\nd..0004\ne.-40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1141, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\n if(v==1||v==0)\n return 1;\n if(v%2==0)\n return (fn(v/2)+2);\n else\n return(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\nreturn (0);\n}\na.6\nb.9\nc.8\nd.7\ne.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1142, "Question": "which 2 options are correct about the function scanf?\na.EOF indicates that scanf filled all addresses successfully\nb. scanf returns the number of addresses successfully filled of EOF\nc.return avoid type\nd.EOF indicates that scanf did not fill any address AND encountered an end of data character.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D "}, {"ID": 1143, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint s=35;\nprintf(\"%d%d%d\",s==35,s+20,s>40)\na.1 35 1\nb.1 55 1\nc.0 55 0\nd.1 55 0", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1144, "Question": "according to the standard C specification, what are the respective minimum sizes (in bytes) of the following two data type: int and long?\na.2,8\nb.4,8\nc.2,4\nd.2,2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1145, "Question": "what does the following declaration mean (if there are more than one correct answers, choose the best one)\nint *ptr[10];\na.array of 10 integer pointers\nb.pointed to the array of 10 elements\nc.array of 10 pointers", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1146, "Question": "what would happen if the user types in the number 3 and presses Enter when running this program?\nmain(){\nint x=5;\nchar c;\nprintf(\"Enter x=\");\nscanf(\"%d\",&x);\nprintf(\"Calculate square(Y/N):\");\nc=getchar();\nif(c==Y||c==y)\nprintf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\na.sqr=9\nb.Its depend on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \"calculate square?\"\nc.sqr=25\nd.the program exits without printing the square", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1147, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i,j,k,x=0;\nfor(i=1;i<5;i++)\n for(j=0;j<i;++j){\n switch(i+j){\n case 0:x=x+1;\n break;\n case 1:\n case 2:\n case 3: x=x+2;\n break;\n}}\nprintf(\"%d\",x);\na.12\nb.13\nc.10\nd.8\ne.6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1148, "Question": "the while loop can be written as a for loop\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1149, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar fun[]=\"How are you?\";\nchar **p;\np=fun;\nwhile(***p!='\\0'){\nif(strlen(p)!=7) printf(\"%c\",**p);\np++;}\na. How ar you\nb.Ho are you\nc.How re you\nd.How are you\ne. How ae you", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1150, "Question": "given the below code ?\nchar st[50];\nscanf(\"%5[^\\]\",st);\nprintf(\"%s\",st);\na user enters \"pfc is simple\"\nwhat is printed?\na.other\nb.pfc is\nc.pfc is so simple\nd.blank output\ne.pfc i", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1151, "Question": "how is a variable accessed from another file?\na. the global variable is referenced via the auto specifier\nb. the global variable is referenced via the extern specifier\nc. the global variable is referenced via the pointer specifier\nd. the global variable is referenced via the ext specifier\ne. the global variable is referenced via the global specifier", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1152, "Question": "which one of the following is a variable, which can contain the address of the memory location of another variable?(choose the best answer)\na.string\nb.struct\nc.array\nd.pointer", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1153, "Question": "declare a two dimensional integer array of two rows and four columns having some initial values\na.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nb.int arr1[2][4]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}\nc.int arr1[4][2]={{8,12};{22,45};{23,40};{44,79}}\nd.int arr1[][2]={{8,12},{22,45},{23,40},{44,79}}", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1154, "Question": "what value will x contain in the sample code below?\nint x=011|0x10;\na.27\nb.19\nc.25\nd.13\ne.3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1155, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint g=1;\nprintf(\"%d %d %d\",g,++g,g++);\na.1 3 3 \nb.1 2 3 \nc.1 1 1 \nd.3 3 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1156, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0;\nfor(;i;)\nprintf(\"This is a loop\");\nif(i>0)\nprintf(\"in C program\");\na. nothing\nb. garbage value\nc. in C program\nd.this is a loop in C program\ne. this is a loop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1157, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\n#include<stdio.h>\nvoid main(){\nint i,j=25;\nint **pi, ***pj=&j;\n ***pj=j+5;\n i=*pj+5;\n pi=pj;\n **pi=i+j;\n printf(\"%d%d\",***pi,*pj);}\na.30 35\nb.65 65\nc.60 60\nd.25 30\ne.60 65", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1158, "Question": "which one of the following is a valid function definition?\na. double funct(int a,b, double c,d)\nb. double funct(int a,b, double c)\nc. double funct(char a,b, double d)\nd. double funct(int a,int b, double c)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1159, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar mess[]=\"Your are welcome here\";\nchar *p;\np=mess;\nmess[8]='\\0';\nputs(++p);\na.our are wel\nb.our are \nc.Your are \nd.Your are wel", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1160, "Question": "which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another\na.strcpy\nb.strcmp\nc.strcat\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1161, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a=8, b=9;\nif(a%2=b%3)\nprintf(\"\\n%d %d\", ++a, b--)\na. 8 9\nb. 9 9 \nc.9 8\nd. compiler error\ne. 8 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1162, "Question": "what will be printed when the sample code below is executed?\nchar **buffer=\"0123456789\";\nchar **ptr=buffer;\nptr+=5;\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",ptr);\nprintf(\"%s\\n\",buffer);\na. 56789\n0123456789\n\nb.56789\n56789\n\nc.0123456789\n0123456789\n\nd.5123456789\n5123456789\n\ne.0123456789\n56789", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1163, "Question": "in myfile.c does not exist, what will be output of this program?\n#include<stdio.h>\nmain(){\nFILE *fi;\nfi=fopen(\"myfile.c\",\"r\");\nif(fi=NULL)\n{puts(\"file is not opened\");\nexit(1);}\nelse\nputs(\"FILE opened\");}\na. file is not opened\nb.no output\nc.FILE opened\nd.error", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1164, "Question": "given the below code\nint a=1;\nint i=7;\nif(a||i++)\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nwhat is the output\na.7\nb.8\nc.9\nd.other", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1165, "Question": "a string is a ... array of characters terminated by a null('\\0')\na.one-dimensional\nb.two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1166, "Question": "referring to the sample code below, what value will the variable counter have when completed\nint x=3, counter = 0;\nwhile(x-1){\n++counter;\nx--;}\na.4 \nb.2\nc.3\nd.0\ne.1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1167, "Question": "the operation between float and int would give the result as\na. float\nb. int \nc. unsigned int\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1168, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint k=0x55;\nprintf(\"\\n%d\",k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na.65\nb.75\nc.55\nd.85", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1169, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint calc(int a, int b){\nint x,y;\nx=a+b;\ny=a*b;\nreturn(x+y);\n}\nint main(){\nint p=3, q=4, r, s;\nr=calc(p,q);\ns=calc(q,p);\nprintf(\"\\n%d%d\",r,s);\nreturn 0;}\na. 3 4\nb. 17 19\nc. 18 18\nd. 17 17\ne.19 19", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1170, "Question": "which of the following statement are true with regards to the || operator?(select al correct answer)\na.this operator is used to combine two conditional expressions which evaluate to true as a whole only if either of the two expressions evaluate to true.\nb.only if both the expressions evaluate to false, the outcome is false\nc.if one of the conditional expressions return false, the outcome is false\nd.this operator is used to combine two logical expressions which evaluate to true if both individual expression are true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 1171, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed, assuming int data type is 32 bits in size?\nprintf(\"%d, %d, %d, %d\", sizeof(char), sizeof(int), sizeof(10.0), sizeof(10.0f));\na. 2,4,8,4\nb. 1,10,10,10\nc. 1,4,8,4\nd. 1,4,4,4\ne. 1,2,4,4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1172, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint a[5]={0}, x=2111223;\nwhile(x>10){\na[x%10-1]++;\nx/=10;}\nprintf(\"%d\",a[1]);\na.6\nb.3\nc.1\nd.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1173, "Question": "what will the code below print when executed?\ndouble x=-3.5, y=3.5;\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",ceil(x), ceil(y));\nprintf(\"%.0f:%.0f\\n\",floor(x), floor(y));\na -3:3\n-4:4\nb.-4:3\n-3:4\nc.-4:4\n-3:3\nd.-3:4\n-4:3\ne.-4:3\n-4:3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1174, "Question": "consider the following code:\nif(a==b)\nprintf(\"\\n the number are equal\");\nelse(a<b)\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",a);\nelse\nprintf(\"\\n the smaller number is: %d\",b);\nin the above code, if a=14 and b=9, then the .... clause is executed\na. else\nb.if\nc else if", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1175, "Question": "when does the code block following while(x<100) execute?\na.when x is less than one hundred\nb.when x is equal to one hundred\nc.when x is greater than one hundred\nd.while it wishes", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1176, "Question": "which are the following statements printf % character?\na.printf(\"\\%\")\nb.printf(\"\\\\%\")\nc.printf(\"\\%%\")\nd.printf(\"%%\")", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 1177, "Question": "a comment can be split over more than one line, as follows\n/** A program\nto calculate average\nof 5 numbers. **/\na.TRUE\nb.FALSE", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1178, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint p,q,h;\nfor(p=1;p<=3;p++)\nfor(q=1;q<=2;q++)\nh=p+q;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",h);\na.1\nb.5\nc.3\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1179, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint x=3;\nif(x==2)\nx=0;\nif(x==3)\nx++;\nelse x+=2;\na.5\nb.3\nc.1\nd.4\ne.2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1180, "Question": "what is the incorrect statement about floating-point data types(float and double)?\na. computers store floating-point data using separate components, including the mantissa and exponent\nb.float-point means that the decimal point can float(that is, it can ba placed anywhere relative to the significant digits)\nc.both data types(float and double) can represent arbitrarily small as well as arbitrarily large numbers\nd.none of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1181, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint n=10, i;\nint k=0;\nfor(i=1;i<n;i=i*2)k++;\nprintf(\"i:%d, k:%d\", i, k);\nprintf(\"\\n\");\na i:16, k:3\nb.i:16, k:4\nc.i:16, k:5\nd.i:8, k:4\ne.i:10, k:4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1182, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nmain()\n{int i=5;\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i=++i==6)\na.0\nb.1\nc.5\nd.6\ne.7", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1183, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nchar *ptr=\"Hello world\";\nptr++;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\nptr+=2;\nprintf(\"%s\",ptr);\na.ello worldllo world\nb.Hello worldHello world\nc.ello worldlo world\nd.ello worldHello world\ne.Hello worldello world", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1184, "Question": "what is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=3;\nswitch(i){\ncase 3: i+=5;\nif(i==8){\ni++;\nif(i==9) break;\ni*=2;}\ni-=4;\nbreak;\ncase 8:\ni+=5;\nbreak;\ndefault: \ni+=6;\nbreak;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",i);\na.8\nb.11\nc.7\nd.9\ne.10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1185, "Question": "using break statement we can exit from\na. for a loop\nb. an if statement\nc. the main() function\nd. a program", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1186, "Question": "give the code below\nint a=2;\nprintf(\"%d\",++a,a+5)\nwhat is printed?\na. undefined\nb. error\nc. 2\nd. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1187, "Question": "What is 7/9*9 equal to?\nA. 2\nB. 0\nC. 1\nD. 0.08642", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1188, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor( i=1; i<10,j<5;i*=2,j++){\nj+=2;\nprintf(\"%d \",j);\n}\nPrintf(\"%d %d\",i,j);\nA. 2 5 4 7\nB. 2 5 6 4\nC. 2 5 3 6 \nD. 2 5 4 8\nE. 2 5 4 6", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1189, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i;\nfor(i=1;i<4;i++)\n switch(i){\n case 1: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 2: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 3: printf(\"%d \",i);\n break;\n case 4: printf(\"%d \",i);\n}\nA. 1 2 3 \nB. 4\nC. 1 2 3 4 \nD. 1 2 \nE. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1190, "Question": "If the program completes executing successfully, what value should the function main returned?\nA. void\nB. 0\nC. nothing\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1191, "Question": "Which value can not be assigned to an unsigned-short type?\nA. 59876\nB. 0\nC. 10000\nD. -3\nE. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1192, "Question": "If a program contains just one function, then it must be___.\nA. clrscr()\nB. getch()\nC. printf()\nD. main()\nE. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1193, "Question": "What number is equivalent to -4e3 ?\nA. -4000\nB.-400\nC. .004\nD. -40", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1194, "Question": "What does the following declaration mean ( If there are more than one correct answer, choose the best one)\nInt*ptr[10];\nA. Array of 10 integer pointers\nB. Pointers to the array of 10 elements\nC. Array of 10 pointers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1195, "Question": "___ is the comparison operation and ___ is the logical operation.\nA. Modulo, Less than\nB. Less than, NOT\nC. NOT, Less than\nD. Divide, OR", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1196, "Question": "- What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat a=14.5;\ndouble b=12.45;\nprintf(\"%.6f%.6f\",a,b);\nA. 14.50000 12.45000\nB. 14.5 12.45\nC. 14.500000 12.450000\nD. 14.5 12.5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1197, "Question": "The ___ function after accepting a character and wait for the Enter key to be pressed.\nA. putch()\nB. putchar()\nC. getch()\nD. getchar()", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1198, "Question": "Evaluate the following as true or false: !(1&&0||!1)\nA. true\nB. false\nC. Invalid expression", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1199, "Question": "The precedence of operators is ___\nA. Arithmetic, Comparison, Logical\nB. Logical, Comparison, Arithmetic\nC. Comparison, Arithmetic, Logical\nD. Comparison, Logical, Arithmetic", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1200, "Question": "What is the output?\n int main(){\nchar i=127;\ni++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nreturn 0;\n}\nA. 128\nB. -128\nC. Undefined\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1201, "Question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint sum(int n);\nint main()\n{\nprintf(\"s=%d\\n\",sum(5));\nreturn 0;\n}\nint sum(int n)\n{\nint s,i;\ns=0;\nfor(i=1;i<=n;i++) s+=i;\nreturn(s);\n}\nA. s=14\nB. s=15", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1202, "Question": "A user enter \"pfabcd\" from the console\nWhat is printed?\nA. pfabcd\nB. Runtime error\nC. pfa\nD. Blank(nothing output)\nE. other\nF. pf", "Choices": [], "Answer": "F "}, {"ID": 1203, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nfloat j;\nj=1000*1000;\nprintf(\"%3.0f\",j);\nA. 1000000\nB. error\nC. overflow\nD. 100", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1204, "Question": "By default any real number is treated as \nA. a long double\nB. a double\nC. depends upon the memory model that you are using\nD. a float", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1205, "Question": "A string is a ___ array of characters terminated by a null('\\0').\nA. one-dimensional\nB. two-dimensional", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1206, "Question": "If you push 1,3, and 5 -in that odder -onto a stack , which number is popped out first?\nA. 5\nB. 1\nC. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1207, "Question": "Which of the following adds ones string to the end of another?\nA. stradd();\nB. append();\nC. strcat();\nD. stringadd();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1208, "Question": "We want to round off x, a float, to an int value. The correct way to do so would be:\nA. y= (int)(x+0.5)\nB. y= (int)((int)x+0.5)\nC.y=(int) x+0.5\nD. y= int(x+0.5)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1209, "Question": "Which of the following is the Boolean operator for logical-and ?\nA. &&\nB. &\nC. |\nD. |&", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1210, "Question": "Which is not a loop structure in C ?\nA. while\nB. for\nC. do while\nD. repeat until", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1211, "Question": "Which of the following statement is (are) wrong ? (choose 2)\nA. a1 = 1343.44;\nB. 3=d;\nC. 3**c=d;\nD. cat = 'A' *** 'B';\nE. asd = 'A'**24;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 1212, "Question": "Which of the following can be used to append one string at the end of another ?\nA. strcpy\nB. strcmp\nC. strcat\nD. None of the other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1213, "Question": "- What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint i;\ni= 1;\ni = i+ 2*i ++;\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\nA. 4\nB. 5\nC. 3\nD. 1\nE. 2", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1214, "Question": "What is the correct fomat to define a value in C ?\nA. const PI = 3.14159\nB. #define PI = 3.14159\nC. #define PI 3.14159\nD. #define PI = 3.14159;\nD. #define PI 3.14159;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1215, "Question": "What is required to avoid falling through from one case to the next ?\nA. break;\nB. stop;\nC. ;\nD. end;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1216, "Question": "Which is the correct statement about coupling ?\nA. Coupling is a measure of the focus within a module.\nB. In designing, high coupling is generally acceptable.\nC. Global variables introduce a low degree of coupling.\nD. We call a module highly couple if it shares that performance with some other module including the referring module.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1217, "Question": "Which of the following functions compares two strings ?\nA. compare();\nB. stringcompare();\nC. cmp();\nD. strcmp();", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1218, "Question": "What is the correct prototype in C ?\nA. doFunc():char;\nB. char doFunc()\nC. int doFunc(int,int);\nD. void doFunc(int x, int y);\nE. float doFunc(void);", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1219, "Question": "Which of the following statements prints %character ?\nA. printf(\"\\%\")\nB. printf(\"\\\\%\");\nC. printf(\"\\%%\")\nD. printf(\"%%\");", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 1220, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\n#include<stdio.h>\nint fn(int v){\n if( v==1||v==0) return 1;\n if(v%2==0) return(fn(v/2)+2);\n else return(fn(v-1)+3);\n}\nint main(){\n printf(\"%d\\n\",fn(5));\n return (0);\n}\nA. 7\nB. 9\nC. 5\nD. 6\nE. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1221, "Question": "Which of the following data type occupied 1 byte ? (choose two)\nA. unsigned char\nB. short\nC. float\nD. long double\nE. double\nF. char", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A F "}, {"ID": 1222, "Question": "- What are the correct statements ? ( choose two)\nA. The operator ** reads as 'the data at address'.\nB. The *** operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand\nC. The operator ** reads the address of the variable.\nD. The & operator is a unary operator and it returns the memory address of the operand", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 1223, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nint s=0;\nfor (int i=1;i<=10;++i){\n s=s+i;\n if (s>=6) break;\n s=s+1;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\\n\",s);\nA. 10\nB. 7\nC. 9\nD. 8", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1224, "Question": "#include<stdlib.h>\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\n int i,n,a=10,b=20;\n for(i=0;i<10;i++){\n n=a+rand()%(b+1-a);\n printf(\"%d\\n\",n);\n }\n return 0;\n}\nRun the above program, which is correct statement about the output?\nA. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 11 and 19 inclusive.\nB. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 10 and 20 inclusive.\nC. The following program prints 10 pseudo-random integers between 9 and 21 inclusive.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1225, "Question": "Which are proper declarations of a string str which stores the value \"Melodies\" (choose two)\nA. char str[]= \"Melodies\";\nB. char str[7] = \"Melodies\";\nC. char str[9] = \" Melodies\";\nD. char str[] = Melodies;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 1226, "Question": "What would happen if the user types in number 3 and presses Enter when running this program ?\nmain(){\n int x=5;\n char c;\n printf(\"Enter x=\");\n scanf(\"%d\",&x);\n printf(\"Calculate square?(Y/N):\");\n c=getchar();\n if (c== 'Y'|| c== 'y')\n printf(\"sqr=%d\",x*x);\n}\nA. sqr = 25\nB. The program exits without printing the square\nC. sqr = 9\nD. It depends on whether the user enters 'Y' or not, being asked \" calculate square?\"", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1227, "Question": "What is size of an int ?\nA. 8 bits\nB. 16 bits \nC. Dependent on machine's \"word\" size\nD. 32 bits", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1228, "Question": "How is the integer pointer var declared in C?\nA. int** x;\nB. int pointer*** var;\nC. int pointer var;\nD. pointer** var;", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1229, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed ?\nvoid foo(int x){\n if (x>0) foo(--x);\n printf(\"%d\",x);\n}\nint main(){\n foo(4);\n printf(\"\\n\");\n return 0;\n}\nA. 00123\nB. 001234 \nC. 430123\nD. 01234 \nE. 40123", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1230, "Question": "How do you include a system header file called sysheader.h in a C source file ?\nA. #includefile<sysheader>\nB.#include<sysheader.h>\nC. #incl<sysheader.h>\nD. #incl \"sysheader.h\"\nE. #includesysheader.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1231, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nint i=0, j=0;\nfor(i=1;i<10,j<3;i*=2) {\n printf(\"%d\",j++);\n}\nprintf(\"%d%d\",i,j);\nA. 012384 \nB. 012394 \nC. 0123184\nD. 01283", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1232, "Question": "What is the output when the sample code below is executed?\nvoid show(int**b){\n printf (\"%d \",**b);\n}\nint main(){\n int i;\n int a[] = { 23,34,45,56};\n for(i=0;i<3;i++) show(&a[i]+1);\n return (0);\n}\nA. 23 45 56\nB. 23 34 45\nC. 45 56 23 \nD. 34 45 56", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1233, "Question": "Which of the following is used to call a function named as doFun()\nA. Call foFunc();\nB. doFunc();\nC. include doFunc();\nD. None of other choices", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1234, "Question": "What is the output of the following program ?\nvoid main()\n{\n Printf(\"%d\",-5/-4);\n}\nA. -1.25\nB. 1.25\nC. -1\nD. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1235, "Question": "Which one is not the standard library in C?\nA. time.h\nB. stdlib.h\nC. system.h\nD. math.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1236, "Question": "Data is stored in computer memory in .........\nChoose one answer. \n a. decimal format. \n b. hexadecimal format. \n c. octal format. \n d. binary format.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1237, "Question": "Which of these statements about primary memory are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Primary memory holds the information accessed by the CPU. \n b. RAM is a volatile memory. \n c. There is only one operation on primary memory and it is reading. \n d. ROM is a volatile memory. \n e. Primary memory is addressable.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 1238, "Question": "(1) One byte consists of 4 nibbles. \n(2) One nibble consists of 2 consecutive bits\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. (1): false \n b. (1) true. \n c. (2): true. \n d. (2): false", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 1239, "Question": "Which of these statements about fundamental unit in CPU is true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. The natural unit of the CPU is a int \n b. The natural unit of the CPU is a numeric \n c. The natural unit of the CPU is a bit \n d. The natural unit of the CPU is a word \n e. The natural unit of the CPU is a byte", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1240, "Question": "Which of these definitions are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The CPU performs the operation on the values stored as operands or on the values stored in the operand addresses. \n b. The addresses are specific values of a program. \n c. The addresses are either register names or primary memory addresses. \n d. Each program instruction consists of an operation and operands. \n e. Each program instruction consists of an expression only.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 1241, "Question": "Comments of a program ......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. are used for documenting a program. \n b. are omitted by the compiler. \n c. enhance the readability of a program. \n d. are translated into instructions after the program is compiled.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B C "}, {"ID": 1242, "Question": "Select correct properties of C language.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. C source code must be translated into executable code by a compiler. \n b. C language is a functional language. \n c. C language is case-insensitive language. \n d. C is case sensitive language. \n e. C language is a low-level language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B D "}, {"ID": 1243, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. A compiler will translate each statement of source code into machine code then CPU executes this statement. \n b. An interpreter will iterate to translate each statement of source code into machine code then CPU execute these binary code of this statement. \n c. Compiler of the language A can translate A-source code into language B-source code then the B-language compiler will translate B-source code into machine code. \n d. An interpreter will translate all source codes into machine codes then CPU executes them as a whole.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 1244, "Question": "....... helps identifying the device which will communiate with CPU.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Address bus. \n b. All \n c. Control bus. \n d. Data bus.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1245, "Question": "Which type qualifiers are defined in C?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. short \n b. complex \n c. double \n d. array \n e. long", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 1246, "Question": "In C, select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The expression x=y; will copy value of the variable x to the variable y. \n b. The expression x=y; will copy value of the variable y to the variable x. \n c. A constant character must be enclosed by a pair of double or single quotes. \n d. A constant string must be enclosed by a pair of double quotes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D "}, {"ID": 1247, "Question": "1. Intel use this little-endian ordering\n2. Motorola use middle-endian ordering\n3. Motorola use big-endian ordering\n4. Intel use this big-endian ordering\nChoose one answer. \n a. 2, 3 true \n b. All of them are true \n c. 1, 4 true \n d. 2, 4 true \n e. 1, 3 true \n f. 1, 2 true \n g. All of them are false", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1248, "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. employee salary \n b. False \n c. _123 \n d. +ab \n e. 45n \n f. True", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D E "}, {"ID": 1249, "Question": "Which of these statements about constants are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The compiler allocates memory for constants. \n b. The compiler does not allocate memory for constants. \n c. The compiler embeds constants directly into the program instructions. \n d. The compiler compiles constants.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 1250, "Question": "In C language, \n(1) The == operator is used for setting a value to a variable. \n(2) The = operator is used for checking whether two numbers are equal or not. \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. (2): true. \n b. (2): false \n c. (1): false \n d. (1) true.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 1251, "Question": "Select correct statements. With respect to ASCII, ..........\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Binary ASCII code of the character a is 0100 0001 \n b. Binary ASCII code of the digit 1 is 0000 0001 \n c. Binary ASCII of the character A is 0100 0001 \n d. The code of a uppercase character is less than the code of a lowercase character. \n e. The code of a digit is less than the code of an alphabet.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 1252, "Question": "Select correct conversion specifiers for an int variable in C lanaguge.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. %f \n b. %o \n c. %e \n d. %d \n e. %u", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D E "}, {"ID": 1253, "Question": "In C language, the selection constructs use ....... \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. while \n b. switch \n c. for \n d. ?: \n e. if else \n f. if else then", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B D E "}, {"ID": 1254, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes are executed. What is the output?\nlong S=10;\nlong i=1;\nwhile (i<=10)\n{ if (i%2==0) S+=i;\ni++;\n}\nprintf(\"%ld\", S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 32 \n b. 38 \n c. 46 \n d. 40 \n e. 36", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1255, "Question": "Flags is a technique that supports using goto, continue statements\nChoose one answer. \n a. True \n b. False", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1256, "Question": "To improve readability, programmers are recommended .......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. using whitespace to identify the logical structure of the code. \n b. using goto statements as needed. \n c. removing continue statements. \n d. using break statements as needed. \n e. using comments.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 1257, "Question": "Marks: 1 \n1. The rule in C is that an else statement always belongs to the innermost if available\n2. The rule in C is that an else statement always belongs to the outermost if available\nChoose one answer. \n a. Only 2nd statement is true \n b. Only 1st statement is true \n c. Both 1 and 2 statements are false \n d. Both 1 and 2 statements are true", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1258, "Question": "Program should be written ... \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. with a complicated appearance. \n b. as a well program. \n c. with a consistent style and clear throughout. \n d. with significant effort and private style.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 1259, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Walkthrough is a process in which any change in codes is recorded. \n b. Walkthrough process is used for evaluating the performance of a program. \n c. A table that contains all program variables is used in walkthrough process. \n d. Walkthrough is a manual process for recording all changes of program variables when the program executes instruction-by-instruction. \n e. A listing of the output, if any, produced by the program is carried out when we do a walkthrough..", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 1260, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute and input data are 9 and 12.\nint m,n; \nprintf(\"Enter two integers:\"); \nscanf(\"%d%d\",&m, &n);\nif (m>10 && n<20) printf(\"%d\", m+n);\nelse printf(\"%d\", m-n);\nWhat is the output.\nChoose one answer. \n a. None of the others. \n b. 21 \n c. -3 \n d. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1261, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute. What is the output?\nlong S=10;\nlong i;\nfor (i=1; i<10; i++) if (i%3==0) S+=i;\nprintf(\"%ld\", S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 19 \n b. 31 \n c. 16 \n d. 22 \n e. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1262, "Question": "In C, which of these statements are not true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. #include \"filename\" using with filename locate in system directory. \n b. We can collect function prototypes into a file and refer to the file in our program \n c. We use the #include directive to instruct the compiler to insert a copy of the header file into our source code. \n d. #include <filename> using with filename locate in user directory \n e. # is a symbol of postprocessor indicators", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D E "}, {"ID": 1263, "Question": "What is the output if the following code executes.\nint n=3, m=7;\nint* p1= &n, *p2=&m;\n*p1 -= m+n- 3*(*p2);\n*p2 += *p1%2 ? 2 : 5; \nprintf (\"%d\", m-n);\nChoose one answer. \n a. -5 \n b. None of the others. \n c. -4 \n d. 6 \n e. 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1264, "Question": "In C, incorrect order(s) of a function implementation:\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Return type, body, function name, parameters \n b. Return type, body, parameters, function name \n c. Return type, function name, parameters, body \n d. Return type, parameters, body, function name", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B D "}, {"ID": 1265, "Question": "Which of these statements about the function is true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. All of the others \n b. The body is the code block that contains the module instructions and generates the return value \n c. A function definition consists of a header and a body \n d. A function that does not return a value is called a subroutine or procedure in other languages \n e. A function may receive data and may return a value", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1266, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Actual parameter is a parameter in function implementation. \n b. Formal parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called. \n c. Actual parameter is a parameter that is transfered to a function when it is called. \n d. Formal parameter is a parameter in function implementation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D "}, {"ID": 1267, "Question": "Select the statements that belong to low cohesion\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. \"logical\" - related tasks of which only one is performed - the module identifier suggests a choice \n b. \"functional\" - performs a single specific task - the module identifier suggests a precise verb phrase \n c. \"communicational\" - the tasks share the same data - all tasks are carried out each time \n d. \"coincidental\" - unrelated tasks", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A D "}, {"ID": 1268, "Question": "In C, with reference to property of reusing a function, the function that will check whether an integer is a prime or not, should be declared as ........ \nChoose one answer. \n a. a void function. \n b. a function that returns a real number. \n c. a function that will return an integer. \n d. None of the others \n e. a function that returns a string a characters.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1269, "Question": "Study the following function:\nint t (int x, int y, int z)\n{ return x+y+z>20 ? 10 : 20;\n}\nIf this function is called as following with input data are 5 10 15. What is the output?\nint a,b,c;\nprintf(\"Enter 3 integers:\");\nscanf(\"%d%d%d\", &a, &b, &c);\nprintf(\"%d\", t(b,c,a));\nChoose one answer. \n a. None of the others. \n b. 20 \n c. -10 \n d. 10", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1270, "Question": "Study the function implementation and a case of using this function.\nint t (int x, int y)\n{ return x-y;\n}\n...\nchar c1= 'A', c2= 'D';\nprintf(\"%d\", t(c2, c1));\nSuppose that the above codes execute. What is the output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. An error is thrown when they are executed. \n b. No output is printed out. \n c. 3 \n d. -3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1271, "Question": "Suppose that the following codes execute. What is the output.\nint n=3, m=7;\nint* p1= &n, *p2=&m;\n*p1 -= m+n- 3*(*p2);\n*p2 += m-n; \nprintf (\"%d\", m+n);\nChoose one answer. \n a. 14 \n b. 16 \n c. 12 \n d. 20 \n e. 18", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1272, "Question": "Which of these statements about the scanf function are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The return code from scanf reflects success of %* conversions \n b. scanf retrieves data values from every keystroke directly \n c. interpreted and processed the entire format string \n d. scanf treats the whitespace between the input values as a separator \n e. If the buffer is empty, the function scanf will wait until the user adds more data values", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C D E "}, {"ID": 1273, "Question": "Select incorrect statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. The specifier %hex is used for printing out an integer in hexadecimal format. \n b. The specifier %e is used for printing out a real number in scientific format. \n c. The specifier %u is used for printing out a unsigned integer. \n d. The specifier %b is used to print out an integer in binary format.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C D "}, {"ID": 1274, "Question": "The getchar function can do\nChoose one answer. \n a. clearing the buffer automatically after retrieving \n b. None of the others \n c. treats the whitespace between the input values as a separator \n d. retrieves data values from every keystroke directly", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1275, "Question": "What library includes function to generate random numbers?\nChoose one answer. \n a. conio.h \n b. stdio.h \n c. stdlib.h \n d. math.h", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1276, "Question": "Validation do not include\nChoose one answer. \n a. out-of-range input \n b. invalid characters \n c. trailing characters \n d. None of the others \n e. incorrect number of input fields", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1277, "Question": "Which of these statements about format string are not true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. size identifies the size of data type of the value passed. \n b. % flags width . precision size conversion_character \n c. - describes left justification of the converted value in its field \n d. None of the others \n e. 0 pads the field width with leading zeros", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1278, "Question": "What is the output of the following program?\n/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ double x= 3.5, y= 6.8 , z= 1.5;\nint n= floor( x )+ ceil( y )+ z;\nprintf(\"%d\", n);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nChoose one answer. \n a. 12 \n b. 10 \n c. 11.5 \n d. The program causes an error when it is compiled. \n e. 11", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1279, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n;\nchar c;\nscanf(\"%d\",&n);\nc=getchar();\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", n,c);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the output of the above program if user enters the keys 12 and ENTER?\nChoose one answer. \n a. Non-predictable values. \n b. 12 \n c. No output is printed out. \n d. 12, 10 \n e. 12, 13", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1280, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n, m;\nint result = scanf(\"%d%d\",&n, &m);\nprintf(\"%d\", result);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the ouput of the above program if input is 12asd45 ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. a non-predictable value. \n b. 1 \n c. 3 \n d. 2 \n e. An error is thrown when it executes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1281, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int n, m;\nscanf(\"%d,%d\",&n, &m);\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", n, m);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhen the program executes, user enters 9 100 . What is output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. Two non-predictable values. \n b. No output is printed out. \n c. 9 and a non-predictable value. \n d. An error when it executes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1282, "Question": "Program ....\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. is a collection of functions. \n b. is a simulation of solution. \n c. is the result of a programming process. \n d. is a set of instructions that computer hardware will execute. \n e. is written by C language only.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C D "}, {"ID": 1283, "Question": "What are the right matching?\nCharacter Sequence\na. Newline \\t\nb. vertical tab \\v\nc. backslash \\\nd. alarm \\r\ne. backspace \\b\nf. question mark \\?\n \n \nChoose at least one answer. \n a. a \n b. f \n c. e \n d. c \n e. b \n f. d", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C E "}, {"ID": 1284, "Question": "Which of these statements about the array are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. In C, the index of an element can be begin from 1. \n b. An array is stored in contiguously block of memory and each element is identified by its index. \n c. The index of an element can be an integer variable, an integer expression or an integer constant. \n d. We use the operator () to access an element of array. \n e. An array is a group of related elements and they belong the same data type.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C E "}, {"ID": 1285, "Question": "The linear search algorithm can be applied on an array in which its elements .......\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. are in no order. \n b. are in descending order. \n c. are in ascending order. \n d. have different data types.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 1286, "Question": "Study the binary search algorithm:\nint binarySearch (int x, int a[], int low, int high)\n{ while (low<=hight)\n{ int mid= (low+high)/2;\nif ( x==a[mid]) return mid ;\nelse if (x>a[mid]) low=mid+1;\nelse high=mid-1;\n}\nreturn -1;\n} \nSuppose that this function is used as following:\nint a[6] = { 1, 2, 2, 3, 3,5};\nint pos = binarySearch(3,a,0,5);\nWhat is the value of the variable pos? \n \nChoose one answer. \n a. 3 \n b. -1 \n c. 4 \n d. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1287, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Flagging technique uses an integer for marking elements of an array when we summarize data of the array. \n b. Flagging technique is applied when user input values to an array only. \n c. Flagging technique is used when we summarize data in an array. \n d. Flagging technique helps marking some data in an array.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 1288, "Question": "What are the names of search algorithm applied to an array?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. Linear search. \n b. Binary search. \n c. Random search. \n d. Bubble search. \n e. Selection search.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 1289, "Question": "Study the following function:\nSuppose that all needed libraries are included.\nint search ( int x, int a[], int n)\n{ int i;\nfor ( i=n-1; i>=0 ; i--) if (x==a[i]) return i;\nreturn -1;\n}\nThis function is used as following:\nint a[10] = { 1, 2, 2, 2, 3, 3, 3, 4, 4, 4};\nint pos = search(3, a, 10);\nWhen the above code executes, what is the value of the variable pos?\nChoose one answer. \n a. 6 \n b. 4 \n c. 5 \n d. -1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1290, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 1,2,3,4,5 };\nint*p= a;\nint i;\nfor (i=0;i<5; i++) \nif (i%2==0) \n{ (*p)++;\np++;\n}\nfor (i=0;i<5;i++) printf(\"%d, \", a[i]);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhen the above program executes. What is the output?\nChoose one answer. \n a. 2, 3, 4, 4, 5 \n b. 15 \n c. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1291, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 1,2,3,4,5 };\nint*p= a;\nint i;\nint S=10;\nfor (i=0;i<5; i++) \nif (a[i]%2==0) S+=a[i]; \nprintf(\"%d\", S);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. 25 \n b. 12 \n c. 15 \n d. 6 \n e. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "E "}, {"ID": 1292, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nvoid f1 ( int*a, int n)\n{ int i,j,t;\nfor (i=0;i<n-1;i++)\nfor (j=n-1; j>i; j--)\nif (a[j]>a[j-1])\n{ t=a[j];\na[j]=a[j-1];\na[j-1]=t;\n}\n}\nvoid f2 (int a[], int n)\n{ int i;\nfor (i=0;i<n;i++) printf (\"%d%s \", a[i], (i<4 ? \",\" : \"\" ));\n}\nint main() \n{ int a[5]= { 5, 1, 2,4, 3 };\nf1(a,5);\nf2(a,5);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. 5, 4, 3, 2, 1 \n b. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 \n c. 2, 4, 1, 3, 5 \n d. 1, 3, 5, 2, 4", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1293, "Question": "With respect to the binary search algorithm on an array, .......\nChoose one answer. \n a. this algorithm cannot be applied on array of characters. \n b. The values contained in the array must be in an order (ascending or descending). \n c. this algorithm cannot be applied on array of real numbersaracters. \n d. no criterion on the array is required.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1294, "Question": "Which of these statements about the %s conversion specifier used in scanf function are true?\nChoose at least one answer. \n a. It will read all characters until the first white space character. \n b. User can not enter any digit. \n c. It is usually used when user will enter a word such as the code of a product. \n d. A parameter of this function must be a string. \n e. It requires user entering at least 2 characters.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 1295, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nvoid f(char S[ ], char c1, char c2)\n{ int L= strlen(S);\nint i;\nfor (i=0; i<L; i++)\nif (*(S+i) == c1) *(S+i)=c2;\n}\nint main() \n{ char S[10]=\"ABCDEFGEH\";\nf( S, 'E', 0);\nprintf(\"%s\", S);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program is ......\nChoose one answer. \n a. ABCD \n b. ABCD0FG0H \n c. None of the others. \n d. ABCDEFGEH", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1296, "Question": "Which of these statements about null byte terminator are not true?\nChoose one answer. \n a. We refer to the null byte using the escape sequence '\\0'. \n b. We can describe the null byte as the constant EOF. \n c. The null byte is the character with the value (code) 0. \n d. We use the null byte to locate the last meaningful element in a string", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1297, "Question": "Which of these statements about the %[^ ] specifier is true when it is used in the scanf function ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. The scanf function will store the characters read in memory locations starting with the address passed to scanf \n b. The scanf function will read all characters until the newline character \n c. The scanf function will leave the delimiting character in the input buffer \n d. All of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1298, "Question": "Which of the the following is the result of the %[abcd] conversion specifier when it is used in the scanf function and the input is dfgh ?\nChoose one answer. \n a. abcd \n b. fgh \n c. dfgh \n d. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1299, "Question": "Which is the result of strcmp(S1, S2) with S1 =\"abcdefgh\" and S2 = \"abcdefdh\"?\nChoose one answer. \n a. A negative integer. \n b. Zero. \n c. A positive integer. \n d. A character.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1300, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ char S[50]= \"ABCDEF\";\nprintf(\"Length:%d, %s\", strlen(S), &S[2]);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nThe output of the program s .......\nChoose one answer. \n a. Length:6, CDEF \n b. 6 and an error is thrown. \n c. The program causes an error when it is compiled. \n d. 6, CDEF", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1301, "Question": "/* Suppose that all needed libraries are included */\nint main() \n{ char S1[50]= \"ABCDEF\";\nchar S2[50]= \"GHI\";\nstrcat(S1,S2);\nprintf(\"%s\", S1);\ngetch();\nreturn 1;\n}\nWhat is the output of the program?\nChoose one answer. \n a. ABCDEFGHI \n b. 6 \n c. An error is thrown when it is compiled. \n d. ABCDEF \n e. 9", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1302, "Question": "Study three following code segments:\n(1)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nputs(S);\n(2)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nprintf(\"%s\",S);\n(3)\nchar S[50]= \"ABCD\";\nprintf(\"%s \\n\",S);\nChoose one answer. \n a. (1) and (2) have the same output. \n b. (2) and (3) have the same output. \n c. All of them have different outputs. \n d. (1) and (3) have the same output.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1303, "Question": "Suppose the string library was included. Study the following C-code:\nchar S1[10]=\"AB\";\nchar S2[10]=\"AB1\";\nprintf(\"%d, %d\", strcmp(S1,S2), strcmp(S2,S1));\nThe output of the above code is:\nChoose one answer. \n a. Non-predictable values. \n b. a negative and a positive integers. \n c. The function strcmp(...) is not in string.h \n d. Two 0s. \n e. a positive and a negative integers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1304, "Question": "The function fopen(...) is used for openning a text file. Which of the following mode parameters can not be used?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. rt \n b. art \n c. RW \n d. w+t \n e. a+t", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C "}, {"ID": 1305, "Question": "What in the following file operations should be used when the file closed only?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. renaming a file. \n b. seeking in a file. \n c. rewinding a file. \n d. get file size. \n e. remove a file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 1306, "Question": "Which of these statements about file format types are true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. With text format, the data on the file can be modified using a text editor. \n b. With text format, data from a file can be read directly to a numeral variable with no tranformation. \n c. With text format, data in a the file are stored as ASCII code of characters. \n d. With binary format, data in a file can be modified using text editor.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A C "}, {"ID": 1307, "Question": "In C, which of following functions can be used to write data to a file?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. gets \n b. fputc \n c. fprintf \n d. fgets \n e. fgetc \n f. fputs \n g. puts \n h. fgetchar", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B C F "}, {"ID": 1308, "Question": "Text format is used. Which of these statements about table, record, and fields are not true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. A record is a sequence of characters that ends with a new line delimiter. \n b. Typically, one table refers to one entity of information \n c. Table is a collection of records \n d. A record consists of fields \n e. A new line delimiter must be used to separate two adjacent fields of a record. \n f. A field may be of any data type", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B E "}, {"ID": 1309, "Question": "Select correct statements.\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. We can rename a file if the file is closed. \n b. We can rewind a file only if the file is closed. \n c. We can rename a file although the file is openning. \n d. The file can be remove if it is openning. \n e. Rewinding a file will move current position to the beginning of the file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A E "}, {"ID": 1310, "Question": "Suppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\nint n=7;\nIn C, if this variable is written to a textfile (using ASCII code), it will take ... byte(s) in the file.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 2 \n b. 4 \n c. 3 \n d. 1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1311, "Question": "Suppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\nint n=7;\nIn C, if this variable is written to a binary file, it will take ... byte(s) in the file.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 1 \n b. 4 \n c. 2 \n d. 3", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1312, "Question": "Select correct statement(s).\nSuppose that a value of the int type will be stored in 4 bytes.\n(1) Writing int values into text file will make the file having small size.\n(2) Writing int values into text file will make the file having large size.\n(3) Writing int values into text file is less efficient because type conversions are needed.\nChoose one answer.\n a. (1) and (3) \n b. None of the others. \n c. (3) \n d. (2) and (3)", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1313, "Question": "What guideline should be examined before working with a text file?\n(1) data format in the file must be known or designed.\n(2) number of values in the file must be known .\n(3) Last date modified of the file must be known.\nChoose one answer.\n a. 3 \n b. 1 \n c. 2 \n d. None of the others.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "B "}, {"ID": 1314, "Question": "Which of these statements about the black-box testing are not true?\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. External factors, such as logic-driven, and path-oriented, are determinant \n b. Each possible path through the code is executed at least once. The number of possibilities to be tested may be too great \n c. Synonyms for black-box include: structural, glass-box and clear-box \n d. External factors, such as testing to specifications, input-output driven, and data driven, are determinant \n e. Synonyms for black-box include: behavioral, functional, opaque-box, and closed-box", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B C "}, {"ID": 1315, "Question": "Methods are used in testing a software are .........\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. White box testing \n b. Black box testing. \n c. Action testing \n d. Statement testing", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 1316, "Question": "Which of these statements about comparing the difference of Waterfall and Open Source Model are true?\nChoose one answer.\n a. The Open Source is seldom reliability than Waterfall Models \n b. The Waterfall Models focus is user-driven rather than concept driven in Open Source Models \n c. None of the others", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1317, "Question": "Marks: 1\nStatement 1: If a program works then it is good designed.\nStatement 2: If the program models a real world situation, it can be hardly upgraded.\nChoose one answer.\n a. One of two statements is true. \n b. The statement 2 is true. \n c. Both of them are false. \n d. The statement 1 is true.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1318, "Question": "Study the following steps in software development process:\n(1) Analysis\n(2) Design\n(3) Implementing\n(4) Deploying\n(5) Maintenance\nThe correct order of them is ..........\nChoose one answer.\n a. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 \n b. None of the others. \n c. 1, 3, 2, 4, 5 \n d. 2, 3, 1, 4, 5", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}, {"ID": 1319, "Question": "The output of a program is incorrect. It may be caused by ......\nChoose at least one answer.\n a. the algorithm is wrong. \n b. a semantic error. \n c. a syntactical error.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A B "}, {"ID": 1320, "Question": "Analysis and maintenance are ............. phases in the sofware development process.\nChoose one answer.\n a. intermediate \n b. None of the others. \n c. last and first \n d. first and last", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D "}, {"ID": 1321, "Question": "........software development model(s) has (have) some phases that are concurrently carried out.\nChoose one answer.\n a. Waterfall and practical \n b. None of the others. \n c. Practical \n d. Waterfall", "Choices": [], "Answer": "C "}, {"ID": 1322, "Question": "Restricting our use of the language to the standard subset of a language will create the ......... of a program.\nChoose one answer.\n a. portability \n b. efficiency \n c. correctness\n d. reliability", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A "}]